<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For I made up my mind not to make another painful visit to you. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> For if I cause you pain, who is there to make me glad but the one whom I have pained? </verse>
    <verse value="3"> And I wrote as I did, so that when I came I might not suffer pain from those who should have made me rejoice, for I felt sure of all of you, that my joy would be the joy of you all. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> For I wrote to you out of much affliction and anguish of heart and with many tears, not to cause you pain but to let you know the abundant love that I have for you.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Now if anyone has caused pain, he has caused it not to me, but in some measure--not to put it too severely--to all of you. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> For such a one, this punishment by the majority is enough, </verse>
    <verse value="7"> so you should rather turn to forgive and comfort him, or he may be overwhelmed by excessive sorrow. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> So I beg you to reaffirm your love for him.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> For this is why I wrote, that I might test you and know whether you are obedient in everything. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> Anyone whom you forgive, I also forgive. Indeed, what I have forgiven, if I have forgiven anything, has been for your sake in the presence of Christ,</verse>
    <verse value="11"> so that we would not be outwitted by Satan; for we are not ignorant of his designs.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> When I came to Troas to preach the gospel of Christ, even though a door was opened for me in the Lord, </verse>
    <verse value="13"> my spirit was not at rest because I did not find my brother Titus there. So I took leave of them and went on to Macedonia.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> But thanks be to God, who in Christ always leads us in triumphal procession, and through us spreads the fragrance of the knowledge of him everywhere. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> For we are the aroma of Christ to God among those who are being saved and among those who are perishing, </verse>
    <verse value="16"> to one a fragrance from death to death, to the other a fragrance from life to life. Who is sufficient for these things? </verse>
    <verse value="17"> For we are not, like so many, peddlers of God's word, but as men of sincerity, as commissioned by God, in the sight of God we speak in Christ.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>