<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Therefore, my brothers, whom I love and long for, my joy and crown, stand firm thus in the Lord, my beloved.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> I entreat Euodia and I entreat Syntyche to agree in the Lord. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> Yes, I ask you also, true companion, help these women, who have labored side by side with me in the gospel together with Clement and the rest of my fellow workers, whose names are in the book of life.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Rejoice in the Lord always; again I will say, Rejoice. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> Let your reasonableness be known to everyone. The Lord is at hand; </verse>
    <verse value="6"> do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Finally, brothers, whatever is true, whatever is honorable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence, if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> What you have learned and received and heard and seen in me--practice these things, and the God of peace will be with you.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> I rejoiced in the Lord greatly that now at length you have revived your concern for me. You were indeed concerned for me, but you had no opportunity. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> Not that I am speaking of being in need, for I have learned in whatever situation I am to be content. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> I know how to be brought low, and I know how to abound. In any and every circumstance, I have learned the secret of facing plenty and hunger, abundance and need. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> I can do all things through him who strengthens me.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Yet it was kind of you to share my trouble. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> And you Philippians yourselves know that in the beginning of the gospel, when I left Macedonia, no church entered into partnership with me in giving and receiving, except you only. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> Even in Thessalonica you sent me help for my needs once and again.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Not that I seek the gift, but I seek the fruit that increases to your credit. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> I have received full payment, and more. I am well supplied, having received from Epaphroditus the gifts you sent, a fragrant offering, a sacrifice acceptable and pleasing to God. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> And my God will supply every need of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> To our God and Father be glory forever and ever. Amen.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Greet every saint in Christ Jesus. The brothers who are with me greet you. </verse>
    <verse value="22"> All the saints greet you, especially those of Caesar's household.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> The grace of the Lord Jesus Christ be with your spirit.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>