<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">These are the sons of David who were born to him in Hebron: the firstborn, Amnon, by Ahinoam the Jezreelite; the second, Daniel, by Abigail the Carmelite, </verse>
    <verse value="2"> the third, Absalom, whose mother was Maacah, the daughter of Talmai, king of Geshur; the fourth, Adonijah, whose mother was Haggith;</verse>
    <verse value="3"> the fifth, Shephatiah, by Abital; the sixth, Ithream, by his wife Eglah;</verse>
    <verse value="4"> six were born to him in Hebron, where he reigned for seven years and six months. And he reigned thirty-three years in Jerusalem. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> These were born to him in Jerusalem: Shimea, Shobab, Nathan and Solomon, four by Bath-shua, the daughter of Ammiel; </verse>
    <verse value="6"> then Ibhar, Elishama, Eliphelet, </verse>
    <verse value="7"> Nogah, Nepheg, Japhia,</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Elishama, Eliada, and Eliphelet, nine. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> All these were David's sons, besides the sons of the concubines, and Tamar was their sister.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The son of Solomon was Rehoboam, Abijah his son, Asa his son, Jehoshaphat his son, </verse>
    <verse value="11"> Joram his son, Ahaziah his son, Joash his son, </verse>
    <verse value="12"> Amaziah his son, Azariah his son, Jotham his son, </verse>
    <verse value="13"> Ahaz his son, Hezekiah his son, Manasseh his son, </verse>
    <verse value="14"> Amon his son, Josiah his son. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> The sons of Josiah: Johanan the firstborn, the second Jehoiakim, the third Zedekiah, the fourth Shallum. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> The descendants of Jehoiakim: Jeconiah his son, Zedekiah his son; </verse>
    <verse value="17"> and the sons of Jeconiah, the captive: Shealtiel his son, </verse>
    <verse value="18"> Malchiram, Pedaiah, Shenazzar, Jekamiah, Hoshama and Nedabiah;</verse>
    <verse value="19"> and the sons of Pedaiah: Zerubbabel and Shimei; and the sons of Zerubbabel: Meshullam and Hananiah, and Shelomith was their sister; </verse>
    <verse value="20"> and Hashubah, Ohel, Berechiah, Hasadiah, and Jushab-hesed, five.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> The sons of Hananiah: Pelatiah and Jeshaiah, his son Rephaiah, his son Arnan, his son Obadiah, his son Shecaniah. </verse>
    <verse value="22"> The son of Shecaniah: Shemaiah. And the sons of Shemaiah: Hattush, Igal, Bariah, Neariah, and Shaphat, six. </verse>
    <verse value="23"> The sons of Neariah: Elioenai, Hizkiah, and Azrikam, three.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> The sons of Elioenai: Hodaviah, Eliashib, Pelaiah, Akkub, Johanan, Delaiah, and Anani, seven.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>