<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Now these were the people of the province who came up out of the captivity of those exiles whom Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon had carried captive to Babylonia. They returned to Jerusalem and Judah, each to his own town. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> They came with Zerubbabel, Jeshua, Nehemiah, Seraiah, Reelaiah, Mordecai, Bilshan, Mispar, Bigvai, Rehum, and Baanah. The number of the men of the people of Israel: </verse>
    <verse value="3"> the sons of Parosh, 2,172. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> The sons of Shephatiah, 372.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> The sons of Arah, 775.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> The sons of Pahath-moab, namely the sons of Jeshua and Joab, 2,812.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> The sons of Elam, 1,254.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> The sons of Zattu, 945.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> The sons of Zaccai, 760.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The sons of Bani, 642.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The sons of Bebai, 623.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> The sons of Azgad, 1,222.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> The sons of Adonikam, 666.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The sons of Bigvai, 2,056.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The sons of Adin, 454.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> The sons of Ater, namely of Hezekiah, 98.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The sons of Bezai, 323.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> The sons of Jorah, 112.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> The sons of Hashum, 223.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> The sons of Gibbar, 95.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> The sons of Bethlehem, 123.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The men of Netophah, 56.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> The men of Anathoth, 128.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> The sons of Azmaveth, 42.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> The sons of Kiriath-arim, Chephirah, and Beeroth, 743.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> The sons of Ramah and Geba, 621.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> The men of Michmas, 122.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> The men of Bethel and Ai, 223.</verse>
    <verse value="29"> The sons of Nebo, 52.</verse>
    <verse value="30"> The sons of Magbish, 156.</verse>
    <verse value="31"> The sons of the other Elam, 1,254. </verse>
    <verse value="32"> The sons of Harim, 320.</verse>
    <verse value="33"> The sons of Lod, Hadid, and Ono, 725.</verse>
    <verse value="34"> The sons of Jericho, 345.</verse>
    <verse value="35"> The sons of Senaah, 3,630.</verse>
    <verse value="36"> The priests: the sons of Jedaiah, of the house of Jeshua, 973. </verse>
    <verse value="37"> The sons of Immer, 1,052.</verse>
    <verse value="38"> The sons of Pashhur, 1,247. </verse>
    <verse value="39"> The sons of Harim, 1,017.</verse>
    <verse value="40"> The Levites: the sons of Jeshua and Kadmiel, of the sons of Hodaviah, 74. </verse>
    <verse value="41"> The singers: the sons of Asaph, 128. </verse>
    <verse value="42"> The sons of the gatekeepers: the sons of Shallum, the sons of Ater, the sons of Talmon, the sons of Akkub, the sons of Hatita, and the sons of Shobai, in all 139.</verse>
    <verse value="43"> The temple servants: the sons of Ziha, the sons of Hasupha, the sons of Tabbaoth, </verse>
    <verse value="44"> the sons of Keros, the sons of Siaha, the sons of Padon,</verse>
    <verse value="45"> the sons of Lebanah, the sons of Hagabah, the sons of Akkub,</verse>
    <verse value="46"> the sons of Hagab, the sons of Shamlai, the sons of Hanan,</verse>
    <verse value="47"> the sons of Giddel, the sons of Gahar, the sons of Reaiah,</verse>
    <verse value="48"> the sons of Rezin, the sons of Nekoda, the sons of Gazzam,</verse>
    <verse value="49"> the sons of Uzza, the sons of Paseah, the sons of Besai,</verse>
    <verse value="50"> the sons of Asnah, the sons of Meunim, the sons of Nephisim,</verse>
    <verse value="51"> the sons of Bakbuk, the sons of Hakupha, the sons of Harhur,</verse>
    <verse value="52"> the sons of Bazluth, the sons of Mehida, the sons of Harsha,</verse>
    <verse value="53"> the sons of Barkos, the sons of Sisera, the sons of Temah,</verse>
    <verse value="54"> the sons of Neziah, and the sons of Hatipha.</verse>
    <verse value="55"> The sons of Solomon's servants: the sons of Sotai, the sons of Hassophereth, the sons of Peruda, </verse>
    <verse value="56"> the sons of Jaalah, the sons of Darkon, the sons of Giddel,</verse>
    <verse value="57"> the sons of Shephatiah, the sons of Hattil, the sons of Pochereth-hazzebaim, and the sons of Ami.</verse>
    <verse value="58"> All the temple servants and the sons of Solomon's servants were 392.</verse>
    <verse value="59"> The following were those who came up from Tel-melah, Tel-harsha, Cherub, Addan, and Immer, though they could not prove their fathers' houses or their descent, whether they belonged to Israel: </verse>
    <verse value="60"> the sons of Delaiah, the sons of Tobiah, and the sons of Nekoda, 652.</verse>
    <verse value="61"> Also, of the sons of the priests: the sons of Habaiah, the sons of Hakkoz, and the sons of Barzillai (who had taken a wife from the daughters of Barzillai the Gileadite, and was called by their name). </verse>
    <verse value="62"> These sought their registration among those enrolled in the genealogies, but they were not found there, and so they were excluded from the priesthood as unclean. </verse>
    <verse value="63"> The governor told them that they were not to partake of the most holy food, until there should be a priest to consult Urim and Thummim.</verse>
    <verse value="64"> The whole assembly together was 42,360, </verse>
    <verse value="65"> besides their male and female servants, of whom there were 7,337, and they had 200 male and female singers. </verse>
    <verse value="66"> Their horses were 736, their mules were 245,</verse>
    <verse value="67"> their camels were 435, and their donkeys were 6,720.</verse>
    <verse value="68"> Some of the heads of families, when they came to the house of the LORD that is in Jerusalem, made freewill offerings for the house of God, to erect it on its site. </verse>
    <verse value="69"> According to their ability they gave to the treasury of the work 61,000 darics of gold, 5,000 minas of silver, and 100 priests' garments.</verse>
    <verse value="70"> Now the priests, the Levites, some of the people, the singers, the gatekeepers, and the temple servants lived in their towns, and all the rest of Israel in their towns.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>