<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">"Behold, my eye has seen all this, my ear has heard and understood it.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> What you know, I also know; I am not inferior to you.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> But I would speak to the Almighty, and I desire to argue my case with God.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> As for you, you whitewash with lies; worthless physicians are you all.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Oh that you would keep silent, and it would be your wisdom!</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Hear now my argument and listen to the pleadings of my lips.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Will you speak falsely for God and speak deceitfully for him?</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Will you show partiality toward him? Will you plead the case for God?</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Will it be well with you when he searches you out? Or can you deceive him, as one deceives a man?</verse>
    <verse value="10"> He will surely rebuke you if in secret you show partiality.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Will not his majesty terrify you, and the dread of him fall upon you?</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Your maxims are proverbs of ashes; your defenses are defenses of clay.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> "Let me have silence, and I will speak, and let come on me what may.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Why should I take my flesh in my teeth and put my life in my hand?</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Though he slay me, I will hope in him; yet I will argue my ways to his face.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> This will be my salvation, that the godless shall not come before him.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Keep listening to my words, and let my declaration be in your ears.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Behold, I have prepared my case; I know that I shall be in the right.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Who is there who will contend with me? For then I would be silent and die.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Only grant me two things, then I will not hide myself from your face:</verse>
    <verse value="21"> withdraw your hand far from me, and let not dread of you terrify me.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Then call, and I will answer; or let me speak, and you reply to me.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> How many are my iniquities and my sins? Make me know my transgression and my sin.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> Why do you hide your face and count me as your enemy?</verse>
    <verse value="25"> Will you frighten a driven leaf and pursue dry chaff?</verse>
    <verse value="26"> For you write bitter things against me and make me inherit the iniquities of my youth.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> You put my feet in the stocks and watch all my paths; you set a limit for the soles of my feet.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Man wastes away like a rotten thing, like a garment that is moth-eaten.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>