<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Then Job answered and said:</verse>
    <verse value="2"> "I have heard many such things; miserable comforters are you all.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Shall windy words have an end? Or what provokes you that you answer?</verse>
    <verse value="4"> I also could speak as you do, if you were in my place; I could join words together against you and shake my head at you.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> I could strengthen you with my mouth, and the solace of my lips would assuage your pain.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> "If I speak, my pain is not assuaged, and if I forbear, how much of it leaves me?</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Surely now God has worn me out; he has made desolate all my company.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> And he has shriveled me up, which is a witness against me, and my leanness has risen up against me; it testifies to my face.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> He has torn me in his wrath and hated me; he has gnashed his teeth at me; my adversary sharpens his eyes against me.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Men have gaped at me with their mouth; they have struck me insolently on the cheek; they mass themselves together against me.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> God gives me up to the ungodly and casts me into the hands of the wicked.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> I was at ease, and he broke me apart; he seized me by the neck and dashed me to pieces; he set me up as his target;</verse>
    <verse value="13"> his archers surround me. He slashes open my kidneys and does not spare; he pours out my gall on the ground.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> He breaks me with breach upon breach; he runs upon me like a warrior.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> I have sewed sackcloth upon my skin and have laid my strength in the dust.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> My face is red with weeping, and on my eyelids is deep darkness,</verse>
    <verse value="17"> although there is no violence in my hands, and my prayer is pure.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> "O earth, cover not my blood, and let my cry find no resting place.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Even now, behold, my witness is in heaven, and he who testifies for me is on high.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> My friends scorn me; my eye pours out tears to God,</verse>
    <verse value="21"> that he would argue the case of a man with God, as a son of man does with his neighbor.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> For when a few years have come I shall go the way from which I shall not return.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>