<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Then Bildad the Shuhite answered and said:</verse>
    <verse value="2"> "How long will you hunt for words? Consider, and then we will speak.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Why are we counted as cattle? Why are we stupid in your sight?</verse>
    <verse value="4"> You who tear yourself in your anger, shall the earth be forsaken for you, or the rock be removed out of its place?</verse>
    <verse value="5"> "Indeed, the light of the wicked is put out, and the flame of his fire does not shine.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> The light is dark in his tent, and his lamp above him is put out.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> His strong steps are shortened, and his own schemes throw him down.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> For he is cast into a net by his own feet, and he walks on its mesh.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> A trap seizes him by the heel; a snare lays hold of him.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> A rope is hidden for him in the ground, a trap for him in the path.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Terrors frighten him on every side, and chase him at his heels.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> His strength is famished, and calamity is ready for his stumbling.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> It consumes the parts of his skin; the firstborn of death consumes his limbs.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> He is torn from the tent in which he trusted and is brought to the king of terrors.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> In his tent dwells that which is none of his; sulfur is scattered over his habitation.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> His roots dry up beneath, and his branches wither above.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> His memory perishes from the earth, and he has no name in the street.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> He is thrust from light into darkness, and driven out of the world.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> He has no posterity or progeny among his people, and no survivor where he used to live.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> They of the west are appalled at his day, and horror seizes them of the east.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Surely such are the dwellings of the unrighteous, such is the place of him who knows not God."</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>