<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Then Job answered and said:</verse>
    <verse value="2"> "How long will you torment me and break me in pieces with words?</verse>
    <verse value="3"> These ten times you have cast reproach upon me; are you not ashamed to wrong me?</verse>
    <verse value="4"> And even if it be true that I have erred, my error remains with myself.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> If indeed you magnify yourselves against me and make my disgrace an argument against me,</verse>
    <verse value="6"> know then that God has put me in the wrong and closed his net about me.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Behold, I cry out, 'Violence!' but I am not answered; I call for help, but there is no justice.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> He has walled up my way, so that I cannot pass, and he has set darkness upon my paths.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> He has stripped from me my glory and taken the crown from my head.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> He breaks me down on every side, and I am gone, and my hope has he pulled up like a tree.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> He has kindled his wrath against me and counts me as his adversary.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> His troops come on together; they have cast up their siege ramp against me and encamp around my tent.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> "He has put my brothers far from me, and those who knew me are wholly estranged from me.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> My relatives have failed me, my close friends have forgotten me.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The guests in my house and my maidservants count me as a stranger; I have become a foreigner in their eyes.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> I call to my servant, but he gives me no answer; I must plead with him with my mouth for mercy.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> My breath is strange to my wife, and I am a stench to the children of my own mother.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Even young children despise me; when I rise they talk against me.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> All my intimate friends abhor me, and those whom I loved have turned against me.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> My bones stick to my skin and to my flesh, and I have escaped by the skin of my teeth.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Have mercy on me, have mercy on me, O you my friends, for the hand of God has touched me!</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Why do you, like God, pursue me? Why are you not satisfied with my flesh?</verse>
    <verse value="23"> "Oh that my words were written! Oh that they were inscribed in a book!</verse>
    <verse value="24"> Oh that with an iron pen and lead they were engraved in the rock forever!</verse>
    <verse value="25"> For I know that my Redeemer lives, and at the last he will stand upon the earth.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> And after my skin has been thus destroyed, yet in my flesh I shall see God,</verse>
    <verse value="27"> whom I shall see for myself, and my eyes shall behold, and not another. My heart faints within me!</verse>
    <verse value="28"> If you say, 'How we will pursue him!' and, 'The root of the matter is found in him,'</verse>
    <verse value="29"> be afraid of the sword, for wrath brings the punishment of the sword, that you may know there is a judgment."</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>