<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">"Why are not times of judgment kept by the Almighty, and why do those who know him never see his days?</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Some move landmarks; they seize flocks and pasture them.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> They drive away the donkey of the fatherless; they take the widow's ox for a pledge.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> They thrust the poor off the road; the poor of the earth all hide themselves.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Behold, like wild donkeys in the desert the poor go out to their toil, seeking game; the wasteland yields food for their children.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> They gather their fodder in the field, and they glean the vineyard of the wicked man.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> They lie all night naked, without clothing, and have no covering in the cold.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> They are wet with the rain of the mountains and cling to the rock for lack of shelter.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> (There are those who snatch the fatherless child from the breast, and they take a pledge against the poor.)</verse>
    <verse value="10"> They go about naked, without clothing; hungry, they carry the sheaves;</verse>
    <verse value="11"> among the olive rows of the wicked they make oil; they tread the winepresses, but suffer thirst.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> From out of the city the dying groan, and the soul of the wounded cries for help; yet God charges no one with wrong.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> "There are those who rebel against the light, who are not acquainted with its ways, and do not stay in its paths.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The murderer rises before it is light, that he may kill the poor and needy, and in the night he is like a thief.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The eye of the adulterer also waits for the twilight, saying, 'No eye will see me'; and he veils his face.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> In the dark they dig through houses; by day they shut themselves up; they do not know the light.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> For deep darkness is morning to all of them; for they are friends with the terrors of deep darkness.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> "You say, 'Swift are they on the face of the waters; their portion is cursed in the land; no treader turns toward their vineyards.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Drought and heat snatch away the snow waters; so does Sheol those who have sinned.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> The womb forgets them; the worm finds them sweet; they are no longer remembered, so wickedness is broken like a tree.'</verse>
    <verse value="21"> "They wrong the barren, childless woman, and do no good to the widow.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Yet God prolongs the life of the mighty by his power; they rise up when they despair of life.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> He gives them security, and they are supported, and his eyes are upon their ways.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> They are exalted a little while, and then are gone; they are brought low and gathered up like all others; they are cut off like the heads of grain.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> If it is not so, who will prove me a liar and show that there is nothing in what I say?"</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>