<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[ Of David.] To you, O LORD, I lift up my soul.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> O my God, in you I trust; let me not be put to shame; let not my enemies exult over me.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Indeed, none who wait for you shall be put to shame; they shall be ashamed who are wantonly treacherous.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Make me to know your ways, O LORD; teach me your paths.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Lead me in your truth and teach me, for you are the God of my salvation; for you I wait all the day long.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Remember your mercy, O LORD, and your steadfast love, for they have been from of old.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Remember not the sins of my youth or my transgressions; according to your steadfast love remember me, for the sake of your goodness, O LORD!</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Good and upright is the LORD; therefore he instructs sinners in the way.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> He leads the humble in what is right, and teaches the humble his way.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> All the paths of the LORD are steadfast love and faithfulness, for those who keep his covenant and his testimonies.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> For your name's sake, O LORD, pardon my guilt, for it is great.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Who is the man who fears the LORD? Him will he instruct in the way that he should choose.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> His soul shall abide in well-being, and his offspring shall inherit the land.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The friendship of the LORD is for those who fear him, and he makes known to them his covenant.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> My eyes are ever toward the LORD, for he will pluck my feet out of the net.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Turn to me and be gracious to me, for I am lonely and afflicted.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The troubles of my heart are enlarged; bring me out of my distresses.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Consider my affliction and my trouble, and forgive all my sins.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Consider how many are my foes, and with what violent hatred they hate me.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Oh, guard my soul, and deliver me! Let me not be put to shame, for I take refuge in you.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> May integrity and uprightness preserve me, for I wait for you.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Redeem Israel, O God, out of all his troubles.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>