<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[ Of David, when he changed his behavior before Abimelech, so that he drove him out, and he went away.] I will bless the LORD at all times; his praise shall continually be in my mouth.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> My soul makes its boast in the LORD; let the humble hear and be glad.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Oh, magnify the LORD with me, and let us exalt his name together!</verse>
    <verse value="4"> I sought the LORD, and he answered me and delivered me from all my fears.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Those who look to him are radiant, and their faces shall never be ashamed.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> This poor man cried, and the LORD heard him and saved him out of all his troubles.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> The angel of the LORD encamps around those who fear him, and delivers them.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Oh, taste and see that the LORD is good! Blessed is the man who takes refuge in him!</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Oh, fear the LORD, you his saints, for those who fear him have no lack!</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The young lions suffer want and hunger; but those who seek the LORD lack no good thing.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Come, O children, listen to me; I will teach you the fear of the LORD.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> What man is there who desires life and loves many days, that he may see good?</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Keep your tongue from evil and your lips from speaking deceit.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Turn away from evil and do good; seek peace and pursue it.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The eyes of the LORD are toward the righteous and his ears toward their cry.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> The face of the LORD is against those who do evil, to cut off the memory of them from the earth.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> When the righteous cry for help, the LORD hears and delivers them out of all their troubles.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> The LORD is near to the brokenhearted and saves the crushed in spirit.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Many are the afflictions of the righteous, but the LORD delivers him out of them all.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> He keeps all his bones; not one of them is broken.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Affliction will slay the wicked, and those who hate the righteous will be condemned.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The LORD redeems the life of his servants; none of those who take refuge in him will be condemned.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>