<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[A Psalm of David, for the memorial offering.] O LORD, rebuke me not in your anger, nor discipline me in your wrath!</verse>
    <verse value="2"> For your arrows have sunk into me, and your hand has come down on me.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> There is no soundness in my flesh because of your indignation; there is no health in my bones because of my sin.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> For my iniquities have gone over my head; like a heavy burden, they are too heavy for me.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> My wounds stink and fester because of my foolishness,</verse>
    <verse value="6"> I am utterly bowed down and prostrate; all the day I go about mourning.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> For my sides are filled with burning, and there is no soundness in my flesh.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> I am feeble and crushed; I groan because of the tumult of my heart.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> O Lord, all my longing is before you; my sighing is not hidden from you.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> My heart throbs; my strength fails me, and the light of my eyes--it also has gone from me.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> My friends and companions stand aloof from my plague, and my nearest kin stand far off.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Those who seek my life lay their snares; those who seek my hurt speak of ruin and meditate treachery all day long.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> But I am like a deaf man; I do not hear, like a mute man who does not open his mouth.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> I have become like a man who does not hear, and in whose mouth are no rebukes.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> But for you, O LORD, do I wait; it is you, O Lord my God, who will answer.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> For I said, "Only let them not rejoice over me, who boast against me when my foot slips!"</verse>
    <verse value="17"> For I am ready to fall, and my pain is ever before me.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> I confess my iniquity; I am sorry for my sin.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> But my foes are vigorous, they are mighty, and many are those who hate me wrongfully.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Those who render me evil for good accuse me because I follow after good.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Do not forsake me, O LORD! O my God, be not far from me!</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Make haste to help me, O Lord, my salvation!</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>