<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[To the choirmaster: according to Lilies. A Maskil of the Sons of Korah; a love song.] My heart overflows with a pleasing theme; I address my verses to the king; my tongue is like the pen of a ready scribe.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> You are the most handsome of the sons of men; grace is poured upon your lips; therefore God has blessed you forever.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Gird your sword on your thigh, O mighty one, in your splendor and majesty!</verse>
    <verse value="4"> In your majesty ride out victoriously for the cause of truth and meekness and righteousness; let your right hand teach you awesome deeds!</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Your arrows are sharp in the heart of the king's enemies; the peoples fall under you.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Your throne, O God, is forever and ever. The scepter of your kingdom is a scepter of uprightness;</verse>
    <verse value="7"> you have loved righteousness and hated wickedness. Therefore God, your God, has anointed you with the oil of gladness beyond your companions;</verse>
    <verse value="8"> your robes are all fragrant with myrrh and aloes and cassia. From ivory palaces stringed instruments make you glad;</verse>
    <verse value="9"> daughters of kings are among your ladies of honor; at your right hand stands the queen in gold of Ophir.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Hear, O daughter, and consider, and incline your ear: forget your people and your father's house,</verse>
    <verse value="11"> and the king will desire your beauty. Since he is your lord, bow to him.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> The people of Tyre will seek your favor with gifts, the richest of the people.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> All glorious is the princess in her chamber, with robes interwoven with gold.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> In many-colored robes she is led to the king, with her virgin companions following behind her.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> With joy and gladness they are led along as they enter the palace of the king.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> In place of your fathers shall be your sons; you will make them princes in all the earth.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> I will cause your name to be remembered in all generations; therefore nations will praise you forever and ever.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>