<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[A Psalm of Asaph.] The Mighty One, God the LORD, speaks and summons the earth from the rising of the sun to its setting.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Out of Zion, the perfection of beauty, God shines forth.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Our God comes; he does not keep silence; before him is a devouring fire, around him a mighty tempest.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> He calls to the heavens above and to the earth, that he may judge his people:</verse>
    <verse value="5"> "Gather to me my faithful ones, who made a covenant with me by sacrifice!"</verse>
    <verse value="6"> The heavens declare his righteousness, for God himself is judge! Selah</verse>
    <verse value="7"> "Hear, O my people, and I will speak; O Israel, I will testify against you. I am God, your God.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Not for your sacrifices do I rebuke you; your burnt offerings are continually before me.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> I will not accept a bull from your house or goats from your folds.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> For every beast of the forest is mine, the cattle on a thousand hills.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> I know all the birds of the hills, and all that moves in the field is mine.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> "If I were hungry, I would not tell you, for the world and its fullness are mine.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Do I eat the flesh of bulls or drink the blood of goats?</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Offer to God a sacrifice of thanksgiving, and perform your vows to the Most High,</verse>
    <verse value="15"> and call upon me in the day of trouble; I will deliver you, and you shall glorify me."</verse>
    <verse value="16"> But to the wicked God says: "What right have you to recite my statutes or take my covenant on your lips?</verse>
    <verse value="17"> For you hate discipline, and you cast my words behind you.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> If you see a thief, you are pleased with him, and you keep company with adulterers.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> "You give your mouth free rein for evil, and your tongue frames deceit.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> You sit and speak against your brother; you slander your own mother's son.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> These things you have done, and I have been silent; you thought that I was one like yourself. But now I rebuke you and lay the charge before you.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> "Mark this, then, you who forget God, lest I tear you apart, and there be none to deliver!</verse>
    <verse value="23"> The one who offers thanksgiving as his sacrifice glorifies me; to one who orders his way rightly I will show the salvation of God!"</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>