<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[A Psalm of Asaph.] Truly God is good to Israel, to those who are pure in heart.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> But as for me, my feet had almost stumbled, my steps had nearly slipped.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> For I was envious of the arrogant when I saw the prosperity of the wicked.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> For they have no pangs until death; their bodies are fat and sleek.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> They are not in trouble as others are; they are not stricken like the rest of mankind.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Therefore pride is their necklace; violence covers them as a garment.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Their eyes swell out through fatness; their hearts overflow with follies.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> They scoff and speak with malice; loftily they threaten oppression.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> They set their mouths against the heavens, and their tongue struts through the earth.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Therefore his people turn back to them, and find no fault in them.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> And they say, "How can God know? Is there knowledge in the Most High?"</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Behold, these are the wicked; always at ease, they increase in riches.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> All in vain have I kept my heart clean and washed my hands in innocence.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> For all the day long I have been stricken and rebuked every morning.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> If I had said, "I will speak thus," I would have betrayed the generation of your children.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> But when I thought how to understand this, it seemed to me a wearisome task,</verse>
    <verse value="17"> until I went into the sanctuary of God; then I discerned their end.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Truly you set them in slippery places; you make them fall to ruin.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> How they are destroyed in a moment, swept away utterly by terrors!</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Like a dream when one awakes, O Lord, when you rouse yourself, you despise them as phantoms.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> When my soul was embittered, when I was pricked in heart,</verse>
    <verse value="22"> I was brutish and ignorant; I was like a beast toward you.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Nevertheless, I am continually with you; you hold my right hand.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> You guide me with your counsel, and afterward you will receive me to glory.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> Whom have I in heaven but you? And there is nothing on earth that I desire besides you.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> My flesh and my heart may fail, but God is the strength of my heart and my portion forever.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> For behold, those who are far from you shall perish; you put an end to everyone who is unfaithful to you.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> But for me it is good to be near God; I have made the Lord GOD my refuge, that I may tell of all your works.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>