<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[A Song. A Psalm of Asaph.] O God, do not keep silence; do not hold your peace or be still, O God!</verse>
    <verse value="2"> For behold, your enemies make an uproar; those who hate you have raised their heads.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> They lay crafty plans against your people; they consult together against your treasured ones.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> They say, "Come, let us wipe them out as a nation; let the name of Israel be remembered no more!"</verse>
    <verse value="5"> For they conspire with one accord; against you they make a covenant--</verse>
    <verse value="6"> the tents of Edom and the Ishmaelites, Moab and the Hagrites,</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Gebal and Ammon and Amalek, Philistia with the inhabitants of Tyre;</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Asshur also has joined them; they are the strong arm of the children of Lot. Selah</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Do to them as you did to Midian, as to Sisera and Jabin at the river Kishon,</verse>
    <verse value="10"> who were destroyed at En-dor, who became dung for the ground.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Make their nobles like Oreb and Zeeb, all their princes like Zebah and Zalmunna,</verse>
    <verse value="12"> who said, "Let us take possession for ourselves of the pastures of God."</verse>
    <verse value="13"> O my God, make them like whirling dust, like chaff before the wind.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> As fire consumes the forest, as the flame sets the mountains ablaze,</verse>
    <verse value="15"> so may you pursue them with your tempest and terrify them with your hurricane!</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Fill their faces with shame, that they may seek your name, O LORD.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Let them be put to shame and dismayed forever; let them perish in disgrace,</verse>
    <verse value="18"> that they may know that you alone, whose name is the LORD, are the Most High over all the earth.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>