<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[A Prayer of David.] Incline your ear, O LORD, and answer me, for I am poor and needy.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Preserve my life, for I am godly; save your servant, who trusts in you--you are my God.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Be gracious to me, O Lord, for to you do I cry all the day.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Gladden the soul of your servant, for to you, O Lord, do I lift up my soul.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> For you, O Lord, are good and forgiving, abounding in steadfast love to all who call upon you.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Give ear, O LORD, to my prayer; listen to my plea for grace.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> In the day of my trouble I call upon you, for you answer me.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> There is none like you among the gods, O Lord, nor are there any works like yours.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> All the nations you have made shall come and worship before you, O Lord, and shall glorify your name.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> For you are great and do wondrous things; you alone are God.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Teach me your way, O LORD, that I may walk in your truth; unite my heart to fear your name.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> I give thanks to you, O Lord my God, with my whole heart, and I will glorify your name forever.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> For great is your steadfast love toward me; you have delivered my soul from the depths of Sheol.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> O God, insolent men have risen up against me; a band of ruthless men seeks my life, and they do not set you before them.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> But you, O Lord, are a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Turn to me and be gracious to me; give your strength to your servant, and save the son of your maidservant.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Show me a sign of your favor, that those who hate me may see and be put to shame because you, LORD, have helped me and comforted me.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>