<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[A Prayer of Moses, the man of God.] Lord, you have been our dwelling place in all generations.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Before the mountains were brought forth, or ever you had formed the earth and the world, from everlasting to everlasting you are God.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> You return man to dust and say, "Return, O children of man!"</verse>
    <verse value="4"> For a thousand years in your sight are but as yesterday when it is past, or as a watch in the night.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> You sweep them away as with a flood; they are like a dream, like grass that is renewed in the morning:</verse>
    <verse value="6"> in the morning it flourishes and is renewed; in the evening it fades and withers.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> For we are brought to an end by your anger; by your wrath we are dismayed.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> You have set our iniquities before you, our secret sins in the light of your presence.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> For all our days pass away under your wrath; we bring our years to an end like a sigh.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The years of our life are seventy, or even by reason of strength eighty; yet their span is but toil and trouble; they are soon gone, and we fly away.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Who considers the power of your anger, and your wrath according to the fear of you?</verse>
    <verse value="12"> So teach us to number our days that we may get a heart of wisdom.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Return, O LORD! How long? Have pity on your servants!</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Satisfy us in the morning with your steadfast love, that we may rejoice and be glad all our days.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Make us glad for as many days as you have afflicted us, and for as many years as we have seen evil.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Let your work be shown to your servants, and your glorious power to their children.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Let the favor of the Lord our God be upon us, and establish the work of our hands upon us; yes, establish the work of our hands!</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>