<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[To the choirmaster. A Psalm of David.] Be not silent, O God of my praise!</verse>
    <verse value="2"> For wicked and deceitful mouths are opened against me, speaking against me with lying tongues.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> They encircle me with words of hate, and attack me without cause.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> In return for my love they accuse me, but I give myself to prayer.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> So they reward me evil for good, and hatred for my love.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Appoint a wicked man against him; let an accuser stand at his right hand.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> When he is tried, let him come forth guilty; let his prayer be counted as sin!</verse>
    <verse value="8"> May his days be few; may another take his office!</verse>
    <verse value="9"> May his children be fatherless and his wife a widow!</verse>
    <verse value="10"> May his children wander about and beg, seeking food far from the ruins they inhabit!</verse>
    <verse value="11"> May the creditor seize all that he has; may strangers plunder the fruits of his toil!</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Let there be none to extend kindness to him, nor any to pity his fatherless children!</verse>
    <verse value="13"> May his posterity be cut off; may his name be blotted out in the second generation!</verse>
    <verse value="14"> May the iniquity of his fathers be remembered before the LORD, and let not the sin of his mother be blotted out!</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Let them be before the LORD continually, that he may cut off the memory of them from the earth!</verse>
    <verse value="16"> For he did not remember to show kindness, but pursued the poor and needy and the brokenhearted, to put them to death.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> He loved to curse; let curses come upon him! He did not delight in blessing; may it be far from him!</verse>
    <verse value="18"> He clothed himself with cursing as his coat; may it soak into his body like water, like oil into his bones!</verse>
    <verse value="19"> May it be like a garment that he wraps around him, like a belt that he puts on every day!</verse>
    <verse value="20"> May this be the reward of my accusers from the LORD, of those who speak evil against my life!</verse>
    <verse value="21"> But you, O GOD my Lord, deal on my behalf for your name's sake; because your steadfast love is good, deliver me!</verse>
    <verse value="22"> For I am poor and needy, and my heart is stricken within me.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> I am gone like a shadow at evening; I am shaken off like a locust.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> My knees are weak through fasting; my body has become gaunt, with no fat.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> I am an object of scorn to my accusers; when they see me, they wag their heads.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> Help me, O LORD my God! Save me according to your steadfast love!</verse>
    <verse value="27"> Let them know that this is your hand; you, O LORD, have done it!</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Let them curse, but you will bless! They arise and are put to shame, but your servant will be glad!</verse>
    <verse value="29"> May my accusers be clothed with dishonor; may they be wrapped in their own shame as in a cloak!</verse>
    <verse value="30"> With my mouth I will give great thanks to the LORD; I will praise him in the midst of the throng.</verse>
    <verse value="31"> For he stands at the right hand of the needy one, to save him from those who condemn his soul to death.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>