<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[To the choirmaster. A Psalm of David.] O LORD, you have searched me and known me!</verse>
    <verse value="2"> You know when I sit down and when I rise up; you discern my thoughts from afar.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> You search out my path and my lying down and are acquainted with all my ways.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Even before a word is on my tongue, behold, O LORD, you know it altogether.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> You hem me in, behind and before, and lay your hand upon me.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Such knowledge is too wonderful for me; it is high; I cannot attain it.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Where shall I go from your Spirit? Or where shall I flee from your presence?</verse>
    <verse value="8"> If I ascend to heaven, you are there! If I make my bed in Sheol, you are there!</verse>
    <verse value="9"> If I take the wings of the morning and dwell in the uttermost parts of the sea,</verse>
    <verse value="10"> even there your hand shall lead me, and your right hand shall hold me.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> If I say, "Surely the darkness shall cover me, and the light about me be night,"</verse>
    <verse value="12"> even the darkness is not dark to you; the night is bright as the day, for darkness is as light with you.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> For you formed my inward parts; you knitted me together in my mother's womb.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> I praise you, for I am fearfully and wonderfully made. Wonderful are your works; my soul knows it very well.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> My frame was not hidden from you, when I was being made in secret, intricately woven in the depths of the earth.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Your eyes saw my unformed substance; in your book were written, every one of them, the days that were formed for me, when as yet there was none of them.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> How precious to me are your thoughts, O God! How vast is the sum of them!</verse>
    <verse value="18"> If I would count them, they are more than the sand. I awake, and I am still with you.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Oh that you would slay the wicked, O God! O men of blood, depart from me!</verse>
    <verse value="20"> They speak against you with malicious intent; your enemies take your name in vain!</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Do I not hate those who hate you, O LORD? And do I not loathe those who rise up against you?</verse>
    <verse value="22"> I hate them with complete hatred; I count them my enemies.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Search me, O God, and know my heart! Try me and know my thoughts!</verse>
    <verse value="24"> And see if there be any grievous way in me, and lead me in the way everlasting!</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>