<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">[ A Song of Praise. Of David.] I will extol you, my God and King, and bless your name forever and ever.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Every day I will bless you and praise your name forever and ever.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Great is the LORD, and greatly to be praised, and his greatness is unsearchable.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> One generation shall commend your works to another, and shall declare your mighty acts.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> On the glorious splendor of your majesty, and on your wondrous works, I will meditate.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> They shall speak of the might of your awesome deeds, and I will declare your greatness.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> They shall pour forth the fame of your abundant goodness and shall sing aloud of your righteousness.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> The LORD is gracious and merciful, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> The LORD is good to all, and his mercy is over all that he has made.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> All your works shall give thanks to you, O LORD, and all your saints shall bless you!</verse>
    <verse value="11"> They shall speak of the glory of your kingdom and tell of your power,</verse>
    <verse value="12"> to make known to the children of man your mighty deeds, and the glorious splendor of your kingdom.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Your kingdom is an everlasting kingdom, and your dominion endures throughout all generations. [The LORD is faithful in all his words and kind in all his works.]</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The LORD upholds all who are falling and raises up all who are bowed down.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The eyes of all look to you, and you give them their food in due season.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> You open your hand; you satisfy the desire of every living thing.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The LORD is righteous in all his ways and kind in all his works.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> The LORD is near to all who call on him, to all who call on him in truth.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> He fulfills the desire of those who fear him; he also hears their cry and saves them.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> The LORD preserves all who love him, but all the wicked he will destroy.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> My mouth will speak the praise of the LORD, and let all flesh bless his holy name forever and ever.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>