<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">My son, be attentive to my wisdom; incline your ear to my understanding,</verse>
    <verse value="2"> that you may keep discretion, and your lips may guard knowledge.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> For the lips of a forbidden woman drip honey, and her speech is smoother than oil,</verse>
    <verse value="4"> but in the end she is bitter as wormwood, sharp as a two-edged sword.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Her feet go down to death; her steps follow the path to Sheol;</verse>
    <verse value="6"> she does not ponder the path of life; her ways wander, and she does not know it.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> And now, O sons, listen to me, and do not depart from the words of my mouth.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Keep your way far from her, and do not go near the door of her house,</verse>
    <verse value="9"> lest you give your honor to others and your years to the merciless,</verse>
    <verse value="10"> lest strangers take their fill of your strength, and your labors go to the house of a foreigner,</verse>
    <verse value="11"> and at the end of your life you groan, when your flesh and body are consumed,</verse>
    <verse value="12"> and you say, "How I hated discipline, and my heart despised reproof!</verse>
    <verse value="13"> I did not listen to the voice of my teachers or incline my ear to my instructors.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> I am at the brink of utter ruin in the assembled congregation."</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Drink water from your own cistern, flowing water from your own well.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Should your springs be scattered abroad, streams of water in the streets?</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Let them be for yourself alone, and not for strangers with you.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Let your fountain be blessed, and rejoice in the wife of your youth,</verse>
    <verse value="19"> a lovely deer, a graceful doe. Let her breasts fill you at all times with delight; be intoxicated always in her love.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Why should you be intoxicated, my son, with a forbidden woman and embrace the bosom of an adulteress?</verse>
    <verse value="21"> For a man's ways are before the eyes of the LORD, and he ponders all his paths.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The iniquities of the wicked ensnare him, and he is held fast in the cords of his sin.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> He dies for lack of discipline, and because of his great folly he is led astray.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>