<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Does not wisdom call? Does not understanding raise her voice?</verse>
    <verse value="2"> On the heights beside the way, at the crossroads she takes her stand;</verse>
    <verse value="3"> beside the gates in front of the town, at the entrance of the portals she cries aloud:</verse>
    <verse value="4"> "To you, O men, I call, and my cry is to the children of man.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> O simple ones, learn prudence; O fools, learn sense.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Hear, for I will speak noble things, and from my lips will come what is right,</verse>
    <verse value="7"> for my mouth will utter truth; wickedness is an abomination to my lips.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> All the words of my mouth are righteous; there is nothing twisted or crooked in them.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> They are all straight to him who understands, and right to those who find knowledge.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Take my instruction instead of silver, and knowledge rather than choice gold,</verse>
    <verse value="11"> for wisdom is better than jewels, and all that you may desire cannot compare with her.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> "I, wisdom, dwell with prudence, and I find knowledge and discretion.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> The fear of the LORD is hatred of evil. Pride and arrogance and the way of evil and perverted speech I hate.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> I have counsel and sound wisdom; I have insight; I have strength.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> By me kings reign, and rulers decree what is just;</verse>
    <verse value="16"> by me princes rule, and nobles, all who govern justly.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> I love those who love me, and those who seek me diligently find me.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Riches and honor are with me, enduring wealth and righteousness.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> My fruit is better than gold, even fine gold, and my yield than choice silver.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> I walk in the way of righteousness, in the paths of justice,</verse>
    <verse value="21"> granting an inheritance to those who love me, and filling their treasuries.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> "The LORD possessed me at the beginning of his work, the first of his acts of old.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Ages ago I was set up, at the first, before the beginning of the earth.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> When there were no depths I was brought forth, when there were no springs abounding with water.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> Before the mountains had been shaped, before the hills, I was brought forth,</verse>
    <verse value="26"> before he had made the earth with its fields, or the first of the dust of the world.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> When he established the heavens, I was there; when he drew a circle on the face of the deep,</verse>
    <verse value="28"> when he made firm the skies above, when he established the fountains of the deep,</verse>
    <verse value="29"> when he assigned to the sea its limit, so that the waters might not transgress his command, when he marked out the foundations of the earth,</verse>
    <verse value="30"> then I was beside him, like a master workman, and I was daily his delight, rejoicing before him always,</verse>
    <verse value="31"> rejoicing in his inhabited world and delighting in the children of man.</verse>
    <verse value="32"> "And now, O sons, listen to me: blessed are those who keep my ways.</verse>
    <verse value="33"> Hear instruction and be wise, and do not neglect it.</verse>
    <verse value="34"> Blessed is the one who listens to me, watching daily at my gates, waiting beside my doors.</verse>
    <verse value="35"> For whoever finds me finds life and obtains favor from the LORD,</verse>
    <verse value="36"> but he who fails to find me injures himself; all who hate me love death."</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>