<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Whoever loves discipline loves knowledge, but he who hates reproof is stupid.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> A good man obtains favor from the LORD, but a man of evil devices he condemns.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> No one is established by wickedness, but the root of the righteous will never be moved.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> An excellent wife is the crown of her husband, but she who brings shame is like rottenness in his bones.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> The thoughts of the righteous are just; the counsels of the wicked are deceitful.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> The words of the wicked lie in wait for blood, but the mouth of the upright delivers them.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> The wicked are overthrown and are no more, but the house of the righteous will stand.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> A man is commended according to his good sense, but one of twisted mind is despised.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Better to be lowly and have a servant than to play the great man and lack bread.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Whoever is righteous has regard for the life of his beast, but the mercy of the wicked is cruel.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Whoever works his land will have plenty of bread, but he who follows worthless pursuits lacks sense.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Whoever is wicked covets the spoil of evildoers, but the root of the righteous bears fruit.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> An evil man is ensnared by the transgression of his lips, but the righteous escapes from trouble.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> From the fruit of his mouth a man is satisfied with good, and the work of a man's hand comes back to him.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The way of a fool is right in his own eyes, but a wise man listens to advice.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> The vexation of a fool is known at once, but the prudent ignores an insult.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Whoever speaks the truth gives honest evidence, but a false witness utters deceit.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> There is one whose rash words are like sword thrusts, but the tongue of the wise brings healing.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Truthful lips endure forever, but a lying tongue is but for a moment.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Deceit is in the heart of those who devise evil, but those who plan peace have joy.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> No ill befalls the righteous, but the wicked are filled with trouble.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Lying lips are an abomination to the LORD, but those who act faithfully are his delight.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> A prudent man conceals knowledge, but the heart of fools proclaims folly.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> The hand of the diligent will rule, while the slothful will be put to forced labor.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> Anxiety in a man's heart weighs him down, but a good word makes him glad.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> One who is righteous is a guide to his neighbor, but the way of the wicked leads them astray.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> Whoever is slothful will not roast his game, but the diligent man will get precious wealth.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> In the path of righteousness is life, and in its pathway there is no death.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>