<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Better is a dry morsel with quiet than a house full of feasting with strife.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> A servant who deals wisely will rule over a son who acts shamefully and will share the inheritance as one of the brothers.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> The crucible is for silver, and the furnace is for gold, and the LORD tests hearts.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> An evildoer listens to wicked lips, and a liar gives ear to a mischievous tongue.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Whoever mocks the poor insults his Maker; he who is glad at calamity will not go unpunished.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Grandchildren are the crown of the aged, and the glory of children is their fathers.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Fine speech is not becoming to a fool; still less is false speech to a prince.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> A bribe is like a magic stone in the eyes of the one who gives it; wherever he turns he prospers.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Whoever covers an offense seeks love, but he who repeats a matter separates close friends.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> A rebuke goes deeper into a man of understanding than a hundred blows into a fool.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> An evil man seeks only rebellion, and a cruel messenger will be sent against him.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Let a man meet a she-bear robbed of her cubs rather than a fool in his folly.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> If anyone returns evil for good, evil will not depart from his house.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The beginning of strife is like letting out water, so quit before the quarrel breaks out.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> He who justifies the wicked and he who condemns the righteous are both alike an abomination to the LORD.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Why should a fool have money in his hand to buy wisdom when he has no sense?</verse>
    <verse value="17"> A friend loves at all times, and a brother is born for adversity.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> One who lacks sense gives a pledge and puts up security in the presence of his neighbor.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Whoever loves transgression loves strife; he who makes his door high seeks destruction.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> A man of crooked heart does not discover good, and one with a dishonest tongue falls into calamity.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> He who sires a fool gets himself sorrow, and the father of a fool has no joy.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> A joyful heart is good medicine, but a crushed spirit dries up the bones.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> The wicked accepts a bribe in secret to pervert the ways of justice.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> The discerning sets his face toward wisdom, but the eyes of a fool are on the ends of the earth.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> A foolish son is a grief to his father and bitterness to her who bore him.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> To impose a fine on a righteous man is not good, nor to strike the noble for their uprightness.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> Whoever restrains his words has knowledge, and he who has a cool spirit is a man of understanding.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Even a fool who keeps silent is considered wise; when he closes his lips, he is deemed intelligent.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>