<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">The king's heart is a stream of water in the hand of the LORD; he turns it wherever he will.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Every way of a man is right in his own eyes, but the LORD weighs the heart.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> To do righteousness and justice is more acceptable to the LORD than sacrifice.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Haughty eyes and a proud heart, the lamp of the wicked, are sin.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> The plans of the diligent lead surely to abundance, but everyone who is hasty comes only to poverty.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> The getting of treasures by a lying tongue is a fleeting vapor and a snare of death.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> The violence of the wicked will sweep them away, because they refuse to do what is just.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> The way of the guilty is crooked, but the conduct of the pure is upright.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> It is better to live in a corner of the housetop than in a house shared with a quarrelsome wife.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The soul of the wicked desires evil; his neighbor finds no mercy in his eyes.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> When a scoffer is punished, the simple becomes wise; when a wise man is instructed, he gains knowledge.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> The Righteous One observes the house of the wicked; he throws the wicked down to ruin.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Whoever closes his ear to the cry of the poor will himself call out and not be answered.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> A gift in secret averts anger, and a concealed bribe, strong wrath.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> When justice is done, it is a joy to the righteous but terror to evildoers.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> One who wanders from the way of good sense will rest in the assembly of the dead.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Whoever loves pleasure will be a poor man; he who loves wine and oil will not be rich.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> The wicked is a ransom for the righteous, and the traitor for the upright.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> It is better to live in a desert land than with a quarrelsome and fretful woman.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Precious treasure and oil are in a wise man's dwelling, but a foolish man devours it.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Whoever pursues righteousness and kindness will find life, righteousness, and honor.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> A wise man scales the city of the mighty and brings down the stronghold in which they trust.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Whoever keeps his mouth and his tongue keeps himself out of trouble.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> "Scoffer" is the name of the arrogant, haughty man who acts with arrogant pride.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> The desire of the sluggard kills him, for his hands refuse to labor.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> All day long he craves and craves, but the righteous gives and does not hold back.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> The sacrifice of the wicked is an abomination; how much more when he brings it with evil intent.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> A false witness will perish, but the word of a man who hears will endure.</verse>
    <verse value="29"> A wicked man puts on a bold face, but the upright gives thought to his ways.</verse>
    <verse value="30"> No wisdom, no understanding, no counsel can avail against the LORD.</verse>
    <verse value="31"> The horse is made ready for the day of battle, but the victory belongs to the LORD.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>