<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">These also are proverbs of Solomon which the men of Hezekiah king of Judah copied.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> It is the glory of God to conceal things, but the glory of kings is to search things out.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> As the heavens for height, and the earth for depth, so the heart of kings is unsearchable.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Take away the dross from the silver, and the smith has material for a vessel;</verse>
    <verse value="5"> take away the wicked from the presence of the king, and his throne will be established in righteousness.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Do not put yourself forward in the king's presence or stand in the place of the great,</verse>
    <verse value="7"> for it is better to be told, "Come up here," than to be put lower in the presence of a noble. What your eyes have seen</verse>
    <verse value="8"> do not hastily bring into court, for what will you do in the end, when your neighbor puts you to shame?</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Argue your case with your neighbor himself, and do not reveal another's secret,</verse>
    <verse value="10"> lest he who hears you bring shame upon you, and your ill repute have no end.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> A word fitly spoken is like apples of gold in a setting of silver.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Like a gold ring or an ornament of gold is a wise reprover to a listening ear.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Like the cold of snow in the time of harvest is a faithful messenger to those who send him; he refreshes the soul of his masters.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Like clouds and wind without rain is a man who boasts of a gift he does not give.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> With patience a ruler may be persuaded, and a soft tongue will break a bone.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> If you have found honey, eat only enough for you, lest you have your fill of it and vomit it.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Let your foot be seldom in your neighbor's house, lest he have his fill of you and hate you.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> A man who bears false witness against his neighbor is like a war club, or a sword, or a sharp arrow.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Trusting in a treacherous man in time of trouble is like a bad tooth or a foot that slips.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Whoever sings songs to a heavy heart is like one who takes off a garment on a cold day, and like vinegar on soda.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> If your enemy is hungry, give him bread to eat, and if he is thirsty, give him water to drink,</verse>
    <verse value="22"> for you will heap burning coals on his head, and the LORD will reward you.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> The north wind brings forth rain, and a backbiting tongue, angry looks.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> It is better to live in a corner of the housetop than in a house shared with a quarrelsome wife.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> Like cold water to a thirsty soul, so is good news from a far country.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> Like a muddied spring or a polluted fountain is a righteous man who gives way before the wicked.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> It is not good to eat much honey, nor is it glorious to seek one's own glory.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> A man without self-control is like a city broken into and left without walls.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>