<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">The words of King Lemuel. An oracle that his mother taught him:</verse>
    <verse value="2"> What are you doing, my son? What are you doing, son of my womb? What are you doing, son of my vows?</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Do not give your strength to women, your ways to those who destroy kings.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> It is not for kings, O Lemuel, it is not for kings to drink wine, or for rulers to take strong drink,</verse>
    <verse value="5"> lest they drink and forget what has been decreed and pervert the rights of all the afflicted.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Give strong drink to the one who is perishing, and wine to those in bitter distress;</verse>
    <verse value="7"> let them drink and forget their poverty and remember their misery no more.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Open your mouth for the mute, for the rights of all who are destitute.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Open your mouth, judge righteously, defend the rights of the poor and needy.</verse>
    <verse value="10">  An excellent wife who can find? She is far more precious than jewels.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The heart of her husband trusts in her, and he will have no lack of gain.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> She does him good, and not harm, all the days of her life.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> She seeks wool and flax, and works with willing hands.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> She is like the ships of the merchant; she brings her food from afar.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> She rises while it is yet night and provides food for her household and portions for her maidens.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> She considers a field and buys it; with the fruit of her hands she plants a vineyard.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> She dresses herself with strength and makes her arms strong.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> She perceives that her merchandise is profitable. Her lamp does not go out at night.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> She puts her hands to the distaff, and her hands hold the spindle.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> She opens her hand to the poor and reaches out her hands to the needy.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> She is not afraid of snow for her household, for all her household are clothed in scarlet.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> She makes bed coverings for herself; her clothing is fine linen and purple.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Her husband is known in the gates when he sits among the elders of the land.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> She makes linen garments and sells them; she delivers sashes to the merchant.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> Strength and dignity are her clothing, and she laughs at the time to come.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> She opens her mouth with wisdom, and the teaching of kindness is on her tongue.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> She looks well to the ways of her household and does not eat the bread of idleness.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Her children rise up and call her blessed; her husband also, and he praises her:</verse>
    <verse value="29"> "Many women have done excellently, but you surpass them all."</verse>
    <verse value="30"> Charm is deceitful, and beauty is vain, but a woman who fears the LORD is to be praised.</verse>
    <verse value="31"> Give her of the fruit of her hands, and let her works praise her in the gates.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>