<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Send the lamb to the ruler of the land, from Sela, by way of the desert, to the mount of the daughter of Zion.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Like fleeing birds, like a scattered nest, so are the daughters of Moab at the fords of the Arnon.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> "Give counsel; grant justice; make your shade like night at the height of noon; shelter the outcasts; do not reveal the fugitive;</verse>
    <verse value="4"> let the outcasts of Moab sojourn among you; be a shelter to them from the destroyer. When the oppressor is no more, and destruction has ceased, and he who tramples underfoot has vanished from the land,</verse>
    <verse value="5"> then a throne will be established in steadfast love, and on it will sit in faithfulness in the tent of David one who judges and seeks justice and is swift to do righteousness."</verse>
    <verse value="6"> We have heard of the pride of Moab-- how proud he is!-- of his arrogance, his pride, and his insolence; in his idle boasting he is not right.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Therefore let Moab wail for Moab, let everyone wail. Mourn, utterly stricken, for the raisin cakes of Kir-hareseth.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> For the fields of Heshbon languish, and the vine of Sibmah; the lords of the nations have struck down its branches, which reached to Jazer and strayed to the desert; its shoots spread abroad and passed over the sea.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Therefore I weep with the weeping of Jazer for the vine of Sibmah; I drench you with my tears, O Heshbon and Elealeh; for over your summer fruit and your harvest the shout has ceased.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> And joy and gladness are taken away from the fruitful field, and in the vineyards no songs are sung, no cheers are raised; no treader treads out wine in the presses; I have put an end to the shouting.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Therefore my inner parts moan like a lyre for Moab, and my inmost self for Kir-hareseth.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> And when Moab presents himself, when he wearies himself on the high place, when he comes to his sanctuary to pray, he will not prevail.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> This is the word that the LORD spoke concerning Moab in the past. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> But now the LORD has spoken, saying, "In three years, like the years of a hired worker, the glory of Moab will be brought into contempt, in spite of all his great multitude, and those who remain will be very few and feeble."</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>