<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="ESV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">I am the man who has seen affliction under the rod of his wrath;</verse>
    <verse value="2"> he has driven and brought me into darkness without any light;</verse>
    <verse value="3"> surely against me he turns his hand again and again the whole day long.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> He has made my flesh and my skin waste away; he has broken my bones;</verse>
    <verse value="5"> he has besieged and enveloped me with bitterness and tribulation;</verse>
    <verse value="6"> he has made me dwell in darkness like the dead of long ago.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> He has walled me about so that I cannot escape; he has made my chains heavy;</verse>
    <verse value="8"> though I call and cry for help, he shuts out my prayer;</verse>
    <verse value="9"> he has blocked my ways with blocks of stones; he has made my paths crooked.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> He is a bear lying in wait for me, a lion in hiding;</verse>
    <verse value="11"> he turned aside my steps and tore me to pieces; he has made me desolate;</verse>
    <verse value="12"> he bent his bow and set me as a target for his arrow.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> He drove into my kidneys the arrows of his quiver;</verse>
    <verse value="14"> I have become the laughingstock of all peoples, the object of their taunts all day long.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> He has filled me with bitterness; he has sated me with wormwood.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> He has made my teeth grind on gravel, and made me cower in ashes;</verse>
    <verse value="17"> my soul is bereft of peace; I have forgotten what happiness is;</verse>
    <verse value="18"> so I say, "My endurance has perished; so has my hope from the LORD."</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Remember my affliction and my wanderings, the wormwood and the gall!</verse>
    <verse value="20"> My soul continually remembers it and is bowed down within me.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> But this I call to mind, and therefore I have hope:</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end;</verse>
    <verse value="23"> they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> "The LORD is my portion," says my soul, "therefore I will hope in him."</verse>
    <verse value="25"> The LORD is good to those who wait for him, to the soul who seeks him.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> It is good that one should wait quietly for the salvation of the LORD.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> It is good for a man that he bear the yoke in his youth.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Let him sit alone in silence when it is laid on him;</verse>
    <verse value="29"> let him put his mouth in the dust-- there may yet be hope;</verse>
    <verse value="30"> let him give his cheek to the one who strikes, and let him be filled with insults.</verse>
    <verse value="31"> For the Lord will not cast off forever,</verse>
    <verse value="32"> but, though he cause grief, he will have compassion according to the abundance of his steadfast love;</verse>
    <verse value="33"> for he does not willingly afflict or grieve the children of men.</verse>
    <verse value="34"> To crush underfoot all the prisoners of the earth,</verse>
    <verse value="35"> to deny a man justice in the presence of the Most High,</verse>
    <verse value="36"> to subvert a man in his lawsuit, the Lord does not approve.</verse>
    <verse value="37"> Who has spoken and it came to pass, unless the Lord has commanded it?</verse>
    <verse value="38"> Is it not from the mouth of the Most High that good and bad come?</verse>
    <verse value="39"> Why should a living man complain, a man, about the punishment of his sins?</verse>
    <verse value="40"> Let us test and examine our ways, and return to the LORD!</verse>
    <verse value="41"> Let us lift up our hearts and hands to God in heaven:</verse>
    <verse value="42"> "We have transgressed and rebelled, and you have not forgiven.</verse>
    <verse value="43"> "You have wrapped yourself with anger and pursued us, killing without pity;</verse>
    <verse value="44"> you have wrapped yourself with a cloud so that no prayer can pass through.</verse>
    <verse value="45"> You have made us scum and garbage among the peoples.</verse>
    <verse value="46"> "All our enemies open their mouths against us;</verse>
    <verse value="47"> panic and pitfall have come upon us, devastation and destruction;</verse>
    <verse value="48"> my eyes flow with rivers of tears because of the destruction of the daughter of my people.</verse>
    <verse value="49"> "My eyes will flow without ceasing, without respite,</verse>
    <verse value="50"> until the LORD from heaven looks down and sees;</verse>
    <verse value="51"> my eyes cause me grief at the fate of all the daughters of my city.</verse>
    <verse value="52"> "I have been hunted like a bird by those who were my enemies without cause;</verse>
    <verse value="53"> they flung me alive into the pit and cast stones on me;</verse>
    <verse value="54"> water closed over my head; I said, 'I am lost.'</verse>
    <verse value="55"> "I called on your name, O LORD, from the depths of the pit;</verse>
    <verse value="56"> you heard my plea, 'Do not close your ear to my cry for help!'</verse>
    <verse value="57"> You came near when I called on you; you said, 'Do not fear!'</verse>
    <verse value="58"> "You have taken up my cause, O Lord; you have redeemed my life.</verse>
    <verse value="59"> You have seen the wrong done to me, O LORD; judge my cause.</verse>
    <verse value="60"> You have seen all their vengeance, all their plots against me.</verse>
    <verse value="61"> "You have heard their taunts, O LORD, all their plots against me.</verse>
    <verse value="62"> The lips and thoughts of my assailants are against me all the day long.</verse>
    <verse value="63"> Behold their sitting and their rising; I am the object of their taunts.</verse>
    <verse value="64"> "You will repay them, O LORD, according to the work of their hands.</verse>
    <verse value="65"> You will give them dullness of heart; your curse will be on them.</verse>
    <verse value="66"> You will pursue them in anger and destroy them from under your heavens, O LORD."</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>