<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Remember, O LORD, what has befallen us; look, and see our disgrace!</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Our inheritance has been turned over to strangers, our homes to foreigners.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> We have become orphans, fatherless; our mothers are like widows.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> We must pay for the water we drink; the wood we get must be bought.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Our pursuers are at our necks; we are weary; we are given no rest.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> We have given the hand to Egypt, and to Assyria, to get bread enough.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Our fathers sinned, and are no more; and we bear their iniquities.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Slaves rule over us; there is none to deliver us from their hand.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> We get our bread at the peril of our lives, because of the sword in the wilderness.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Our skin is hot as an oven with the burning heat of famine.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Women are raped in Zion, young women in the towns of Judah.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Princes are hung up by their hands; no respect is shown to the elders.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Young men are compelled to grind at the mill, and boys stagger under loads of wood.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The old men have left the city gate, the young men their music.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The joy of our hearts has ceased; our dancing has been turned to mourning.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> The crown has fallen from our head; woe to us, for we have sinned!</verse>
    <verse value="17"> For this our heart has become sick, for these things our eyes have grown dim,</verse>
    <verse value="18"> for Mount Zion which lies desolate; jackals prowl over it.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> But you, O LORD, reign forever; your throne endures to all generations.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Why do you forget us forever, why do you forsake us for so many days?</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Restore us to yourself, O LORD, that we may be restored! Renew our days as of old--</verse>
    <verse value="22"> unless you have utterly rejected us, and you remain exceedingly angry with us.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>