<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Set the trumpet to your lips! One like a vulture is over the house of the LORD, because they have transgressed my covenant and rebelled against my law.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> To me they cry, "My God, we--Israel--know you."</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Israel has spurned the good; the enemy shall pursue him.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> They made kings, but not through me. They set up princes, but I knew it not. With their silver and gold they made idols for their own destruction.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> I have spurned your calf, O Samaria. My anger burns against them. How long will they be incapable of innocence?</verse>
    <verse value="6"> For it is from Israel; a craftsman made it; it is not God. The calf of Samaria shall be broken to pieces.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> For they sow the wind, and they shall reap the whirlwind. The standing grain has no heads; it shall yield no flour; if it were to yield, strangers would devour it.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Israel is swallowed up; already they are among the nations as a useless vessel.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> For they have gone up to Assyria, a wild donkey wandering alone; Ephraim has hired lovers.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Though they hire allies among the nations, I will soon gather them up. And the king and princes shall soon writhe because of the tribute.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Because Ephraim has multiplied altars for sinning, they have become to him altars for sinning.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Were I to write for him my laws by the ten thousands, they would be regarded as a strange thing.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> As for my sacrificial offerings, they sacrifice meat and eat it, but the LORD does not accept them. Now he will remember their iniquity and punish their sins; they shall return to Egypt.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> For Israel has forgotten his Maker and built palaces, and Judah has multiplied fortified cities; so I will send a fire upon his cities, and it shall devour her strongholds.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>