<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">When Jesus had finished instructing his twelve disciples, he went on from there to teach and preach in their cities.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Now when John heard in prison about the deeds of the Christ, he sent word by his disciples </verse>
    <verse value="3"> and said to him, "Are you the one who is to come, or shall we look for another?" </verse>
    <verse value="4"> And Jesus answered them, "Go and tell John what you hear and see:</verse>
    <verse value="5"> the blind receive their sight and the lame walk, lepers are cleansed and the deaf hear, and the dead are raised up, and the poor have good news preached to them. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> And blessed is the one who is not offended by me."</verse>
    <verse value="7"> As they went away, Jesus began to speak to the crowds concerning John: "What did you go out into the wilderness to see? A reed shaken by the wind? </verse>
    <verse value="8"> What then did you go out to see? A man dressed in soft clothing? Behold, those who wear soft clothing are in kings' houses. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> What then did you go out to see? A prophet? Yes, I tell you, and more than a prophet. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> This is he of whom it is written, "'Behold, I send my messenger before your face, who will prepare your way before you.'</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Truly, I say to you, among those born of women there has arisen no one greater than John the Baptist. Yet the one who is least in the kingdom of heaven is greater than he.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> From the days of John the Baptist until now the kingdom of heaven has suffered violence, and the violent take it by force. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> For all the Prophets and the Law prophesied until John, </verse>
    <verse value="14"> and if you are willing to accept it, he is Elijah who is to come. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> He who has ears to hear, let him hear.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> "But to what shall I compare this generation? It is like children sitting in the marketplaces and calling to their playmates,</verse>
    <verse value="17"> "'We played the flute for you, and you did not dance; we sang a dirge, and you did not mourn.'</verse>
    <verse value="18"> For John came neither eating nor drinking, and they say, 'He has a demon.' </verse>
    <verse value="19"> The Son of Man came eating and drinking, and they say, 'Look at him! A glutton and a drunkard, a friend of tax collectors and sinners!' Yet wisdom is justified by her deeds."</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Then he began to denounce the cities where most of his mighty works had been done, because they did not repent. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> "Woe to you, Chorazin! Woe to you, Bethsaida! For if the mighty works done in you had been done in Tyre and Sidon, they would have repented long ago in sackcloth and ashes.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> But I tell you, it will be more bearable on the day of judgment for Tyre and Sidon than for you. </verse>
    <verse value="23"> And you, Capernaum, will you be exalted to heaven? You will be brought down to Hades. For if the mighty works done in you had been done in Sodom, it would have remained until this day. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> But I tell you that it will be more tolerable on the day of judgment for the land of Sodom than for you."</verse>
    <verse value="25"> At that time Jesus declared, "I thank you, Father, Lord of heaven and earth, that you have hidden these things from the wise and understanding and revealed them to little children; </verse>
    <verse value="26"> yes, Father, for such was your gracious will. </verse>
    <verse value="27"> All things have been handed over to me by my Father, and no one knows the Son except the Father, and no one knows the Father except the Son and anyone to whom the Son chooses to reveal him. </verse>
    <verse value="28"> Come to me, all who labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. </verse>
    <verse value="29"> Take my yoke upon you, and learn from me, for I am gentle and lowly in heart, and you will find rest for your souls. </verse>
    <verse value="30"> For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light."</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>