<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">When morning came, all the chief priests and the elders of the people took counsel against Jesus to put him to death. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> And they bound him and led him away and delivered him over to Pilate the governor.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Then when Judas, his betrayer, saw that Jesus was condemned, he changed his mind and brought back the thirty pieces of silver to the chief priests and the elders, </verse>
    <verse value="4"> saying, "I have sinned by betraying innocent blood." They said, "What is that to us? See to it yourself." </verse>
    <verse value="5"> And throwing down the pieces of silver into the temple, he departed, and he went and hanged himself. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> But the chief priests, taking the pieces of silver, said, "It is not lawful to put them into the treasury, since it is blood money." </verse>
    <verse value="7"> So they took counsel and bought with them the potter's field as a burial place for strangers.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Therefore that field has been called the Field of Blood to this day. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> Then was fulfilled what had been spoken by the prophet Jeremiah, saying, "And they took the thirty pieces of silver, the price of him on whom a price had been set by some of the sons of Israel, </verse>
    <verse value="10"> and they gave them for the potter's field, as the Lord directed me."</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Now Jesus stood before the governor, and the governor asked him, "Are you the King of the Jews?" Jesus said, "You have said so." </verse>
    <verse value="12"> But when he was accused by the chief priests and elders, he gave no answer. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> Then Pilate said to him, "Do you not hear how many things they testify against you?" </verse>
    <verse value="14"> But he gave him no answer, not even to a single charge, so that the governor was greatly amazed.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Now at the feast the governor was accustomed to release for the crowd any one prisoner whom they wanted. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> And they had then a notorious prisoner called Barabbas.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> So when they had gathered, Pilate said to them, "Whom do you want me to release for you: Barabbas, or Jesus who is called Christ?" </verse>
    <verse value="18"> For he knew that it was out of envy that they had delivered him up. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> Besides, while he was sitting on the judgment seat, his wife sent word to him, "Have nothing to do with that righteous man, for I have suffered much because of him today in a dream." </verse>
    <verse value="20"> Now the chief priests and the elders persuaded the crowd to ask for Barabbas and destroy Jesus. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> The governor again said to them, "Which of the two do you want me to release for you?" And they said, "Barabbas."</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Pilate said to them, "Then what shall I do with Jesus who is called Christ?" They all said, "Let him be crucified!" </verse>
    <verse value="23"> And he said, "Why, what evil has he done?" But they shouted all the more, "Let him be crucified!"</verse>
    <verse value="24"> So when Pilate saw that he was gaining nothing, but rather that a riot was beginning, he took water and washed his hands before the crowd, saying, "I am innocent of this man's blood; see to it yourselves." </verse>
    <verse value="25"> And all the people answered, "His blood be on us and on our children!" </verse>
    <verse value="26"> Then he released for them Barabbas, and having scourged Jesus, delivered him to be crucified.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> Then the soldiers of the governor took Jesus into the governor's headquarters, and they gathered the whole battalion before him. </verse>
    <verse value="28"> And they stripped him and put a scarlet robe on him, </verse>
    <verse value="29"> and twisting together a crown of thorns, they put it on his head and put a reed in his right hand. And kneeling before him, they mocked him, saying, "Hail, King of the Jews!" </verse>
    <verse value="30"> And they spit on him and took the reed and struck him on the head. </verse>
    <verse value="31"> And when they had mocked him, they stripped him of the robe and put his own clothes on him and led him away to crucify him.</verse>
    <verse value="32"> As they went out, they found a man of Cyrene, Simon by name. They compelled this man to carry his cross. </verse>
    <verse value="33"> And when they came to a place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull), </verse>
    <verse value="34"> they offered him wine to drink, mixed with gall, but when he tasted it, he would not drink it. </verse>
    <verse value="35"> And when they had crucified him, they divided his garments among them by casting lots. </verse>
    <verse value="36"> Then they sat down and kept watch over him there. </verse>
    <verse value="37"> And over his head they put the charge against him, which read, "This is Jesus, the King of the Jews."</verse>
    <verse value="38"> Then two robbers were crucified with him, one on the right and one on the left. </verse>
    <verse value="39"> And those who passed by derided him, wagging their heads </verse>
    <verse value="40"> and saying, "You who would destroy the temple and rebuild it in three days, save yourself! If you are the Son of God, come down from the cross." </verse>
    <verse value="41"> So also the chief priests, with the scribes and elders, mocked him, saying,</verse>
    <verse value="42"> "He saved others; he cannot save himself. He is the King of Israel; let him come down now from the cross, and we will believe in him. </verse>
    <verse value="43"> He trusts in God; let God deliver him now, if he desires him. For he said, 'I am the Son of God.'" </verse>
    <verse value="44"> And the robbers who were crucified with him also reviled him in the same way.</verse>
    <verse value="45"> Now from the sixth hour there was darkness over all the land until the ninth hour. </verse>
    <verse value="46"> And about the ninth hour Jesus cried out with a loud voice, saying, "Eli, Eli, lema sabachthani?" that is, "My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?" </verse>
    <verse value="47"> And some of the bystanders, hearing it, said, "This man is calling Elijah."</verse>
    <verse value="48"> And one of them at once ran and took a sponge, filled it with sour wine, and put it on a reed and gave it to him to drink. </verse>
    <verse value="49"> But the others said, "Wait, let us see whether Elijah will come to save him."</verse>
    <verse value="50"> And Jesus cried out again with a loud voice and yielded up his spirit.</verse>
    <verse value="51"> And behold, the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. And the earth shook, and the rocks were split.</verse>
    <verse value="52"> The tombs also were opened. And many bodies of the saints who had fallen asleep were raised,</verse>
    <verse value="53"> and coming out of the tombs after his resurrection they went into the holy city and appeared to many. </verse>
    <verse value="54"> When the centurion and those who were with him, keeping watch over Jesus, saw the earthquake and what took place, they were filled with awe and said, "Truly this was the Son of God!"</verse>
    <verse value="55"> There were also many women there, looking on from a distance, who had followed Jesus from Galilee, ministering to him, </verse>
    <verse value="56"> among whom were Mary Magdalene and Mary the mother of James and Joseph and the mother of the sons of Zebedee.</verse>
    <verse value="57"> When it was evening, there came a rich man from Arimathea, named Joseph, who also was a disciple of Jesus.</verse>
    <verse value="58"> He went to Pilate and asked for the body of Jesus. Then Pilate ordered it to be given to him.</verse>
    <verse value="59"> And Joseph took the body and wrapped it in a clean linen shroud</verse>
    <verse value="60"> and laid it in his own new tomb, which he had cut in the rock. And he rolled a great stone to the entrance of the tomb and went away. </verse>
    <verse value="61"> Mary Magdalene and the other Mary were there, sitting opposite the tomb.</verse>
    <verse value="62"> The next day, that is, after the day of Preparation, the chief priests and the Pharisees gathered before Pilate </verse>
    <verse value="63"> and said, "Sir, we remember how that impostor said, while he was still alive, 'After three days I will rise.' </verse>
    <verse value="64"> Therefore order the tomb to be made secure until the third day, lest his disciples go and steal him away and tell the people, 'He has risen from the dead,' and the last fraud will be worse than the first." </verse>
    <verse value="65"> Pilate said to them, "You have a guard of soldiers. Go, make it as secure as you can." </verse>
    <verse value="66"> So they went and made the tomb secure by sealing the stone and setting a guard.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>