<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="TCVs" language="CHS">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">And as soon as it was morning, the chief priests held a consultation with the elders and scribes and the whole Council. And they bound Jesus and led him away and delivered him over to Pilate. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> And Pilate asked him, "Are you the King of the Jews?" And he answered him, "You have said so." </verse>
    <verse value="3"> And the chief priests accused him of many things.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> And Pilate again asked him, "Have you no answer to make? See how many charges they bring against you." </verse>
    <verse value="5"> But Jesus made no further answer, so that Pilate was amazed.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Now at the feast he used to release for them one prisoner for whom they asked. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> And among the rebels in prison, who had committed murder in the insurrection, there was a man called Barabbas. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> And the crowd came up and began to ask Pilate to do as he usually did for them.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> And he answered them, saying, "Do you want me to release for you the King of the Jews?"</verse>
    <verse value="10"> For he perceived that it was out of envy that the chief priests had delivered him up.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> But the chief priests stirred up the crowd to have him release for them Barabbas instead.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> And Pilate again said to them, "Then what shall I do with the man you call the King of the Jews?" </verse>
    <verse value="13"> And they cried out again, "Crucify him."</verse>
    <verse value="14"> And Pilate said to them, "Why, what evil has he done?" But they shouted all the more, "Crucify him." </verse>
    <verse value="15"> So Pilate, wishing to satisfy the crowd, released for them Barabbas, and having scourged Jesus, he delivered him to be crucified.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> And the soldiers led him away inside the palace (that is, the governor's headquarters), and they called together the whole battalion. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> And they clothed him in a purple cloak, and twisting together a crown of thorns, they put it on him. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> And they began to salute him, "Hail, King of the Jews!" </verse>
    <verse value="19"> And they were striking his head with a reed and spitting on him and kneeling down in homage to him.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> And when they had mocked him, they stripped him of the purple cloak and put his own clothes on him. And they led him out to crucify him.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> And they compelled a passerby, Simon of Cyrene, who was coming in from the country, the father of Alexander and Rufus, to carry his cross. </verse>
    <verse value="22"> And they brought him to the place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull). </verse>
    <verse value="23"> And they offered him wine mixed with myrrh, but he did not take it. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> And they crucified him and divided his garments among them, casting lots for them, to decide what each should take.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> And it was the third hour when they crucified him. </verse>
    <verse value="26"> And the inscription of the charge against him read, "The King of the Jews." </verse>
    <verse value="27"> And with him they crucified two robbers, one on his right and one on his left. </verse>
    <verse value="28">
    </verse>
    <verse value="29"> And those who passed by derided him, wagging their heads and saying, "Aha! You who would destroy the temple and rebuild it in three days,</verse>
    <verse value="30"> save yourself, and come down from the cross!"</verse>
    <verse value="31"> So also the chief priests with the scribes mocked him to one another, saying, "He saved others; he cannot save himself. </verse>
    <verse value="32"> Let the Christ, the King of Israel, come down now from the cross that we may see and believe." Those who were crucified with him also reviled him.</verse>
    <verse value="33"> And when the sixth hour had come, there was darkness over the whole land until the ninth hour. </verse>
    <verse value="34"> And at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, "Eloi, Eloi, lema sabachthani?" which means, "My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?" </verse>
    <verse value="35"> And some of the bystanders hearing it said, "Behold, he is calling Elijah."</verse>
    <verse value="36"> And someone ran and filled a sponge with sour wine, put it on a reed and gave it to him to drink, saying, "Wait, let us see whether Elijah will come to take him down." </verse>
    <verse value="37"> And Jesus uttered a loud cry and breathed his last. </verse>
    <verse value="38"> And the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. </verse>
    <verse value="39"> And when the centurion, who stood facing him, saw that in this way he breathed his last, he said, "Truly this man was the Son of God!"</verse>
    <verse value="40"> There were also women looking on from a distance, among whom were Mary Magdalene, and Mary the mother of James the younger and of Joses, and Salome. </verse>
    <verse value="41"> When he was in Galilee, they followed him and ministered to him, and there were also many other women who came up with him to Jerusalem.</verse>
    <verse value="42"> And when evening had come, since it was the day of Preparation, that is, the day before the Sabbath, </verse>
    <verse value="43"> Joseph of Arimathea, a respected member of the Council, who was also himself looking for the kingdom of God, took courage and went to Pilate and asked for the body of Jesus. </verse>
    <verse value="44"> Pilate was surprised to hear that he should have already died. And summoning the centurion, he asked him whether he was already dead. </verse>
    <verse value="45"> And when he learned from the centurion that he was dead, he granted the corpse to Joseph. </verse>
    <verse value="46"> And Joseph bought a linen shroud, and taking him down, wrapped him in the linen shroud and laid him in a tomb that had been cut out of the rock. And he rolled a stone against the entrance of the tomb. </verse>
    <verse value="47"> Mary Magdalene and Mary the mother of Joses saw where he was laid.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>