<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">After these things, Jesus was walking in Galilee, for he wouldn't walk in Judea, because the Jews sought to kill him.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Now the feast of the Jews, the Feast of Booths, was at hand.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> His brothers therefore said to him, "Depart from here, and go into Judea, that your disciples also may see your works which you do.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> For no one does anything in secret, and himself seeks to be known openly. If you do these things, reveal yourself to the world."</verse>
    <verse value="5"> For even his brothers didn't believe in him. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Jesus therefore said to them, "My time has not yet come, but your time is always ready.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> The world can't hate you, but it hates me, because I testify about it, that its works are evil.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> You go up to the feast. I am not yet going up to this feast, because my time is not yet fulfilled." |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Having said these things to them, he stayed in Galilee.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> But when his brothers had gone up to the feast, then he also went up, not publicly, but as it were in secret.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The Jews therefore sought him at the feast, and said, "Where is he?"</verse>
    <verse value="12"> There was much murmuring among the multitudes concerning him. Some said, "He is a good man." Others said, "Not so, but he leads the multitude astray."</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Yet no one spoke openly of him for fear of the Jews.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> But when it was now the midst of the feast, Jesus went up into the temple and taught.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The Jews therefore marveled, saying, "How does this man know letters, having never been educated?" |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Jesus therefore answered them, "My teaching is not mine, but his who sent me.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> If anyone desires to do his will, he will know about the teaching, whether it is from God, or if I am speaking from myself.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> He who speaks from himself seeks his own glory, but he who seeks the glory of him who sent him is true, and no unrighteousness is in him.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Didn't Moses give you the law, and yet none of you keeps the law? Why do you seek to kill me?" |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> The multitude answered, "You have a demon! Who seeks to kill you?" |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Jesus answered them, "I did one work, and you all marvel because of it.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Moses has given you circumcision (not that it is of Moses, but of the fathers), and on the Sabbath you circumcise a boy.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> If a boy receives circumcision on the Sabbath, that the law of Moses may not be broken, are you angry with me, because I made a man completely healthy on the Sabbath?</verse>
    <verse value="24"> Don't judge according to appearance, but judge righteous judgment." |</verse>
    <verse value="25"> Therefore some of them of Jerusalem said, "Isn't this he whom they seek to kill?</verse>
    <verse value="26"> Behold, he speaks openly, and they say nothing to him. Can it be that the rulers indeed know that this is truly the Christ?</verse>
    <verse value="27"> However we know where this man comes from, but when the Christ comes, no one will know where he comes from." |</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Jesus therefore cried out in the temple, teaching and saying, "You both know me, and know where I am from. I have not come of myself, but he who sent me is true, whom you don't know.</verse>
    <verse value="29"> I know him, because I am from him, and he sent me." |</verse>
    <verse value="30"> They sought therefore to take him; but no one laid a hand on him, because his hour had not yet come.</verse>
    <verse value="31"> But of the multitude, many believed in him. They said, "When the Christ comes, he won't do more signs than those which this man has done, will he?"</verse>
    <verse value="32"> The Pharisees heard the multitude murmuring these things concerning him, and the chief priests and the Pharisees sent officers to arrest him. |</verse>
    <verse value="33"> Then Jesus said, "I will be with you a little while longer, then I go to him who sent me.</verse>
    <verse value="34"> You will seek me, and won't find me; and where I am, you can't come." |</verse>
    <verse value="35"> The Jews therefore said among themselves, "Where will this man go that we won't find him? Will he go to the Dispersion among the Greeks, and teach the Greeks?</verse>
    <verse value="36"> What is this word that he said, 'You will seek me, and won't find me; and where I am, you can't come'?" |</verse>
    <verse value="37"> Now on the last and greatest day of the feast, Jesus stood and cried out, "If anyone is thirsty, let him come to me and drink!</verse>
    <verse value="38"> He who believes in me, as the Scripture has said, from within him will flow rivers of living water."</verse>
    <verse value="39"> But he said this about the Spirit, which those believing in him were to receive. For the Holy Spirit was not yet given, because Jesus wasn't yet glorified. |</verse>
    <verse value="40"> Many of the multitude therefore, when they heard these words, said, "This is truly the prophet."</verse>
    <verse value="41"> Others said, "This is the Christ." But some said, "What, does the Christ come out of Galilee?</verse>
    <verse value="42"> Hasn't the Scripture said that the Christ comes of the seed of David, {2 Samuel 7:12} and from Bethlehem, {Micah 5:2} the village where David was?"</verse>
    <verse value="43"> So there arose a division in the multitude because of him.</verse>
    <verse value="44"> Some of them would have arrested him, but no one laid hands on him.</verse>
    <verse value="45"> The officers therefore came to the chief priests and Pharisees, and they said to them, "Why didn't you bring him?" |</verse>
    <verse value="46"> The officers answered, "No man ever spoke like this man!" |</verse>
    <verse value="47"> The Pharisees therefore answered them, "You aren't also led astray, are you?</verse>
    <verse value="48"> Have any of the rulers believed in him, or of the Pharisees?</verse>
    <verse value="49"> But this multitude that doesn't know the law is accursed." |</verse>
    <verse value="50"> Nicodemus (he who came to him by night, being one of them) said to them,</verse>
    <verse value="51"> "Does our law judge a man, unless it first hears from him personally and knows what he does?" |</verse>
    <verse value="52"> They answered him, "Are you also from Galilee? Search, and see that no prophet has arisen out of Galilee. {See Isaiah 9:1 and Matthew 4:13-16.}" |</verse>
    <verse value="53"> Everyone went to his own house,</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>