<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Now these were the sons of David, who were born to him in Hebron: the firstborn, Amnon, of Ahinoam the Jezreelitess; the second, Daniel, of Abigail the Carmelitess;</verse>
    <verse value="2"> the third, Absalom the son of Maacah the daughter of Talmai king of Geshur; the fourth, Adonijah the son of Haggith;</verse>
    <verse value="3"> the fifth, Shephatiah of Abital; the sixth, Ithream by Eglah his wife:</verse>
    <verse value="4"> six were born to him in Hebron; and there he reigned seven years and six months. In Jerusalem he reigned thirty-three years;</verse>
    <verse value="5"> and these were born to him in Jerusalem: Shimea, and Shobab, and Nathan, and Solomon, four, of Bathshua the daughter of Ammiel;</verse>
    <verse value="6"> and Ibhar, and Elishama, and Eliphelet,</verse>
    <verse value="7"> and Nogah, and Nepheg, and Japhia,</verse>
    <verse value="8"> and Elishama, and Eliada, and Eliphelet, nine.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> All these were the sons of David, besides the sons of the concubines; and Tamar was their sister.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Solomon's son was Rehoboam, Abijah his son, Asa his son, Jehoshaphat his son,</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Joram his son, Ahaziah his son, Joash his son,</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Amaziah his son, Azariah his son, Jotham his son,</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Ahaz his son, Hezekiah his son, Manasseh his son,</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Amon his son, Josiah his son.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The sons of Josiah: the firstborn Johanan, the second Jehoiakim, the third Zedekiah, the fourth Shallum.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> The sons of Jehoiakim: Jeconiah his son, Zedekiah his son.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The sons of Jeconiah, the captive: Shealtiel his son,</verse>
    <verse value="18"> and Malchiram, and Pedaiah, and Shenazzar, Jekamiah, Hoshama, and Nedabiah.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> The sons of Pedaiah: Zerubbabel, and Shimei. The sons of Zerubbabel: Meshullam, and Hananiah; and Shelomith was their sister;</verse>
    <verse value="20"> and Hashubah, and Ohel, and Berechiah, and Hasadiah, Jushab Hesed, five.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> The sons of Hananiah: Pelatiah, and Jeshaiah; the sons of Rephaiah, the sons of Arnan, the sons of Obadiah, the sons of Shecaniah.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The sons of Shecaniah: Shemaiah. The sons of Shemaiah: Hattush, and Igal, and Bariah, and Neariah, and Shaphat, six.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> The sons of Neariah: Elioenai, and Hizkiah, and Azrikam, three.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> The sons of Elioenai: Hodaviah, and Eliashib, and Pelaiah, and Akkub, and Johanan, and Delaiah, and Anani, seven. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>