<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Now these are the children of the province, who went up out of the captivity of those who had been carried away, whom Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon had carried away to Babylon, and who returned to Jerusalem and Judah, everyone to his city;</verse>
    <verse value="2"> who came with Zerubbabel, Jeshua, Nehemiah, Seraiah, Reelaiah, Mordecai, Bilshan, Mispar, Bigvai, Rehum, Baanah. The number of the men of the people of Israel:</verse>
    <verse value="3"> The children of Parosh, two thousand one hundred seventy-two.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> The children of Shephatiah, three hundred seventy-two.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> The children of Arah, seven hundred seventy-five.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> The children of Pahathmoab, of the children of Jeshua and Joab, two thousand eight hundred twelve.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> The children of Elam, one thousand two hundred fifty-four.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> The children of Zattu, nine hundred forty-five.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> The children of Zaccai, seven hundred sixty.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The children of Bani, six hundred forty-two.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The children of Bebai, six hundred twenty-three.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> The children of Azgad, one thousand two hundred twenty-two.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> The children of Adonikam, six hundred sixty-six.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The children of Bigvai, two thousand fifty-six.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The children of Adin, four hundred fifty-four.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> The children of Ater, of Hezekiah, ninety-eight.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The children of Bezai, three hundred twenty-three.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> The children of Jorah, one hundred twelve.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> The children of Hashum, two hundred twenty-three.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> The children of Gibbar, ninety-five.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> The children of Bethlehem, one hundred twenty-three.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The men of Netophah, fifty-six.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> The men of Anathoth, one hundred twenty-eight.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> The children of Azmaveth, forty-two.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> The children of Kiriath Arim, Chephirah, and Beeroth, seven hundred forty-three.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> The children of Ramah and Geba, six hundred twenty-one.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> The men of Michmas, one hundred twenty-two.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> The men of Bethel and Ai, two hundred twenty-three.</verse>
    <verse value="29"> The children of Nebo, fifty-two.</verse>
    <verse value="30"> The children of Magbish, one hundred fifty-six.</verse>
    <verse value="31"> The children of the other Elam, one thousand two hundred fifty-four.</verse>
    <verse value="32"> The children of Harim, three hundred twenty.</verse>
    <verse value="33"> The children of Lod, Hadid, and Ono, seven hundred twenty-five.</verse>
    <verse value="34"> The children of Jericho, three hundred forty-five.</verse>
    <verse value="35"> The children of Senaah, three thousand six hundred thirty.</verse>
    <verse value="36"> The priests: the children of Jedaiah, of the house of Jeshua, nine hundred seventy-three.</verse>
    <verse value="37"> The children of Immer, one thousand fifty-two.</verse>
    <verse value="38"> The children of Pashhur, one thousand two hundred forty-seven.</verse>
    <verse value="39"> The children of Harim, one thousand seventeen.</verse>
    <verse value="40"> The Levites: the children of Jeshua and Kadmiel, of the children of Hodaviah, seventy-four.</verse>
    <verse value="41"> The singers: the children of Asaph, one hundred twenty-eight.</verse>
    <verse value="42"> The children of the porters: the children of Shallum, the children of Ater, the children of Talmon, the children of Akkub, the children of Hatita, the children of Shobai, in all one hundred thirty-nine.</verse>
    <verse value="43"> The Nethinim: the children of Ziha, the children of Hasupha, the children of Tabbaoth,</verse>
    <verse value="44"> the children of Keros, the children of Siaha, the children of Padon,</verse>
    <verse value="45"> the children of Lebanah, the children of Hagabah, the children of Akkub,</verse>
    <verse value="46"> the children of Hagab, the children of Shamlai, the children of Hanan,</verse>
    <verse value="47"> the children of Giddel, the children of Gahar, the children of Reaiah,</verse>
    <verse value="48"> the children of Rezin, the children of Nekoda, the children of Gazzam,</verse>
    <verse value="49"> the children of Uzza, the children of Paseah, the children of Besai,</verse>
    <verse value="50"> the children of Asnah, the children of Meunim, the children of Nephisim,</verse>
    <verse value="51"> the children of Bakbuk, the children of Hakupha, the children of Harhur,</verse>
    <verse value="52"> the children of Bazluth, the children of Mehida, the children of Harsha,</verse>
    <verse value="53"> the children of Barkos, the children of Sisera, the children of Temah,</verse>
    <verse value="54"> the children of Neziah, the children of Hatipha.</verse>
    <verse value="55"> The children of Solomon's servants: the children of Sotai, the children of Hassophereth, the children of Peruda,</verse>
    <verse value="56"> the children of Jaalah, the children of Darkon, the children of Giddel,</verse>
    <verse value="57"> the children of Shephatiah, the children of Hattil, the children of Pochereth Hazzebaim, the children of Ami.</verse>
    <verse value="58"> All the Nethinim, and the children of Solomon's servants, were three hundred ninety-two.</verse>
    <verse value="59"> These were those who went up from Tel Melah, Tel Harsha, Cherub, Addan, and Immer; but they could not show their fathers' houses, and their seed, whether they were of Israel:</verse>
    <verse value="60"> the children of Delaiah, the children of Tobiah, the children of Nekoda, six hundred fifty-two.</verse>
    <verse value="61"> Of the children of the priests: the children of Habaiah, the children of Hakkoz, the children of Barzillai, who took a wife of the daughters of Barzillai the Gileadite, and was called after their name.</verse>
    <verse value="62"> These sought their place among those who were registered by genealogy, but they were not found: therefore were they deemed polluted and put from the priesthood.</verse>
    <verse value="63"> The governor said to them, that they should not eat of the most holy things, until there stood up a priest with Urim and with Thummim.</verse>
    <verse value="64"> The whole assembly together was forty-two thousand three hundred sixty,</verse>
    <verse value="65"> besides their male servants and their female servants, of whom there were seven thousand three hundred thirty-seven: and they had two hundred singing men and singing women.</verse>
    <verse value="66"> Their horses were seven hundred thirty-six; their mules, two hundred forty-five;</verse>
    <verse value="67"> their camels, four hundred thirty-five; their donkeys, six thousand seven hundred and twenty.</verse>
    <verse value="68"> Some of the heads of fathers' households, when they came to the house of Yahweh which is in Jerusalem, offered willingly for God's house to set it up in its place:</verse>
    <verse value="69"> they gave after their ability into the treasury of the work sixty-one thousand darics of gold, and five thousand minas of silver, and one hundred priests' garments.</verse>
    <verse value="70"> So the priests, and the Levites, and some of the people, and the singers, and the porters, and the Nethinim, lived in their cities, and all Israel in their cities. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>