<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Then Job answered, |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> "Truly I know that it is so, / but how can man be just with God? |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> If he is pleased to contend with him, / he can't answer him one time in a thousand. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> God who is wise in heart, and mighty in strength: / who has hardened himself against him, and prospered? |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> He removes the mountains, and they don't know it, / when he overturns them in his anger. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> He shakes the earth out of its place. / Its pillars tremble. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> He commands the sun, and it doesn't rise, / and seals up the stars. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> He alone stretches out the heavens, / and treads on the waves of the sea. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> He makes the Bear, Orion, and the Pleiades, / and the rooms of the south. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> He does great things past finding out; / yes, marvelous things without number. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Behold, he goes by me, and I don't see him. / He passes on also, but I don't perceive him. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Behold, he snatches away. / Who can hinder him? / Who will ask him, 'What are you doing?' |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> "God will not withdraw his anger. / The helpers of Rahab stoop under him. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> How much less shall I answer him, / And choose my words to argue with him? |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Though I were righteous, yet I wouldn't answer him. / I would make supplication to my judge. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> If I had called, and he had answered me, / yet I wouldn't believe that he listened to my voice. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> For he breaks me with a storm, / and multiplies my wounds without cause. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> He will not allow me to catch my breath, / but fills me with bitterness. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> If it is a matter of strength, behold, he is mighty! / If of justice, 'Who,' says he, 'will summon me?' |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Though I am righteous, my own mouth shall condemn me. / Though I am blameless, it shall prove me perverse. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> I am blameless. / I don't respect myself. / I despise my life. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> "It is all the same. / Therefore I say he destroys the blameless and the wicked. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> If the scourge kills suddenly, / he will mock at the trial of the innocent. |</verse>
    <verse value="24"> The earth is given into the hand of the wicked. / He covers the faces of its judges. / If not he, then who is it? |</verse>
    <verse value="25"> "Now my days are swifter than a runner. / They flee away, they see no good, |</verse>
    <verse value="26"> They have passed away as the swift ships, / as the eagle that swoops on the prey. |</verse>
    <verse value="27"> If I say, 'I will forget my complaint, / I will put off my sad face, and cheer up;' |</verse>
    <verse value="28"> I am afraid of all my sorrows, / I know that you will not hold me innocent. |</verse>
    <verse value="29"> I shall be condemned. / Why then do I labor in vain? |</verse>
    <verse value="30"> If I wash myself with snow, / and cleanse my hands with lye, |</verse>
    <verse value="31"> yet you will plunge me in the ditch. / My own clothes shall abhor me. |</verse>
    <verse value="32"> For he is not a man, as I am, that I should answer him, / that we should come together in judgment. |</verse>
    <verse value="33"> There is no umpire between us, / that might lay his hand on us both. |</verse>
    <verse value="34"> Let him take his rod away from me. / Let his terror not make me afraid; |</verse>
    <verse value="35"> then I would speak, and not fear him, / for I am not so in myself. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>