<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">"Man, who is born of a woman, / is of few days, and full of trouble. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> He comes forth like a flower, and is cut down. / He also flees like a shadow, and doesn't continue. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Do you open your eyes on such a one, / and bring me into judgment with you? |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Who can bring a clean thing out of an unclean? / Not one. /</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Seeing his days are determined, / the number of his months is with you, / and you have appointed his bounds that he can't pass; |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Look away from him, that he may rest, / until he shall accomplish, as a hireling, his day. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> "For there is hope for a tree, / If it is cut down, that it will sprout again, / that the tender branch of it will not cease. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Though its root grows old in the earth, / and its stock dies in the ground, |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> yet through the scent of water it will bud, / and put forth boughs like a plant. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> But man dies, and is laid low. / Yes, man gives up the spirit, and where is he? |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> As the waters fail from the sea, / and the river wastes and dries up, |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> so man lies down and doesn't rise. / Until the heavens are no more, they shall not awake, / nor be roused out of their sleep. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> "Oh that you would hide me in Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}, / that you would keep me secret, until your wrath is past, / that you would appoint me a set time, and remember me! |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> If a man dies, shall he live again? / All the days of my warfare would I wait, / until my release should come. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> You would call, and I would answer you. / You would have a desire to the work of your hands. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> But now you number my steps. / Don't you watch over my sin? |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> My disobedience is sealed up in a bag. / You fasten up my iniquity. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> "But the mountain falling comes to nothing. / The rock is removed out of its place; |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> The waters wear the stones. / The torrents of it wash away the dust of the earth. / So you destroy the hope of man. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> You forever prevail against him, and he departs. / You change his face, and send him away. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> His sons come to honor, and he doesn't know it. / They are brought low, but he doesn't perceive it of them. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> But his flesh on him has pain, / and his soul within him mourns." |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>