<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Then Bildad the Shuhite answered, |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> "How long will you hunt for words? / Consider, and afterwards we will speak. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Why are we counted as animals, / which have become unclean in your sight? |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> You who tear yourself in your anger, / shall the earth be forsaken for you? / Or shall the rock be removed out of its place? |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> "Yes, the light of the wicked shall be put out, / The spark of his fire shall not shine. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> The light shall be dark in his tent. / His lamp above him shall be put out. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> The steps of his strength shall be shortened. / His own counsel shall cast him down. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> For he is cast into a net by his own feet, / and he wanders into its mesh. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> A snare will take him by the heel. / A trap will catch him. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> A noose is hidden for him in the ground, / a trap for him in the way. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Terrors shall make him afraid on every side, / and shall chase him at his heels. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> His strength shall be famished. / Calamity shall be ready at his side. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> The members of his body shall be devoured. / The firstborn of death shall devour his members. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> He shall be rooted out of his tent where he trusts. / He shall be brought to the king of terrors. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> There shall dwell in his tent that which is none of his. / Sulfur shall be scattered on his habitation. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> His roots shall be dried up beneath. / Above shall his branch be cut off. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> His memory shall perish from the earth. / He shall have no name in the street. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> He shall be driven from light into darkness, / and chased out of the world. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> He shall have neither son nor grandson among his people, / nor any remaining where he lived. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Those who come after shall be astonished at his day, / as those who went before were frightened. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Surely such are the dwellings of the unrighteous. / This is the place of him who doesn't know God." |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>