<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">This is the book of the generations of Adam. In the day that God created man, he made him in God's likeness.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> He created them male and female, and blessed them, and called their name "Adam," {"Adam" and "Man" are spelled with the exact same consonants in Hebrew, so this can be correctly translated either way.} in the day when they were created.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Adam lived one hundred thirty years, and became the father of a son in his own likeness, after his image, and named him Seth.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> The days of Adam after he became the father of Seth were eight hundred years, and he became the father of sons and daughters.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> All the days that Adam lived were nine hundred thirty years, then he died. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Seth lived one hundred five years, and became the father of Enosh.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Seth lived after he became the father of Enosh eight hundred seven years, and became the father of sons and daughters.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> All the days of Seth were nine hundred twelve years, then he died. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Enosh lived ninety years, and became the father of Kenan.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Enosh lived after he became the father of Kenan, eight hundred fifteen years, and became the father of sons and daughters.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> All the days of Enosh were nine hundred five years, then he died. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Kenan lived seventy years, and became the father of Mahalalel.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Kenan lived after he became the father of Mahalalel eight hundred forty years, and became the father of sons and daughters</verse>
    <verse value="14"> and all the days of Kenan were nine hundred ten years, then he died. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Mahalalel lived sixty-five years, and became the father of Jared.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Mahalalel lived after he became the father of Jared eight hundred thirty years, and became the father of sons and daughters.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> All the days of Mahalalel were eight hundred ninety-five years, then he died. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Jared lived one hundred sixty-two years, and became the father of Enoch.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Jared lived after he became the father of Enoch eight hundred years, and became the father of sons and daughters.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> All the days of Jared were nine hundred sixty-two years, then he died. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Enoch lived sixty-five years, and became the father of Methuselah.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Enoch walked with God after he became the father of Methuselah three hundred years, and became the father of sons and daughters.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> All the days of Enoch were three hundred sixty-five years.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> Enoch walked with God, and he was not, for God took him. |</verse>
    <verse value="25"> Methuselah lived one hundred eighty-seven years, and became the father of Lamech.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> Methuselah lived after he became the father of Lamech seven hundred eighty-two years, and became the father of sons and daughters.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> All the days of Methuselah were nine hundred sixty-nine years, then he died. |</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Lamech lived one hundred eighty-two years, and became the father of a son,</verse>
    <verse value="29"> and he named him Noah, saying, "This same will comfort us in our work and in the toil of our hands, because of the ground which Yahweh has cursed."</verse>
    <verse value="30"> Lamech lived after he became the father of Noah five hundred ninety-five years, and became the father of sons and daughters.</verse>
    <verse value="31"> All the days of Lamech were seven hundred seventy-seven years, then he died. |</verse>
    <verse value="32"> Noah was five hundred years old, and Noah became the father of Shem, Ham, and Japheth. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>