<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Rejoice in Yahweh, you righteous! / Praise is fitting for the upright. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Give thanks to Yahweh with the lyre. / Sing praises to him with the harp of ten strings. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Sing to him a new song. / Play skillfully with a shout of joy! |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> For the word of Yahweh is right. / All his work is done in faithfulness. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> He loves righteousness and justice. / The earth is full of the loving kindness of Yahweh. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> By Yahweh's word, the heavens were made; / all their army by the breath of his mouth. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> He gathers the waters of the sea together as a heap. / He lays up the deeps in storehouses. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Let all the earth fear Yahweh. / Let all the inhabitants of the world stand in awe of him. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> For he spoke, and it was done. / He commanded, and it stood firm. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Yahweh brings the counsel of the nations to nothing. / He makes the thoughts of the peoples to be of no effect. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The counsel of Yahweh stands fast forever, / the thoughts of his heart to all generations. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Blessed is the nation whose God is Yahweh, / the people whom he has chosen for his own inheritance. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Yahweh looks from heaven. / He sees all the sons of men. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> From the place of his habitation he looks out on all the inhabitants of the earth, /</verse>
    <verse value="15"> he who fashions all of their hearts; / and he considers all of their works. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> There is no king saved by the multitude of an army. / A mighty man is not delivered by great strength. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> A horse is a vain thing for safety, / neither does he deliver any by his great power. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Behold, Yahweh's eye is on those who fear him, / on those who hope in his loving kindness; /</verse>
    <verse value="19"> to deliver their soul from death, / to keep them alive in famine. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Our soul has waited for Yahweh. / He is our help and our shield. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> For our heart rejoices in him, / because we have trusted in his holy name. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Let your loving kindness be on us, Yahweh, / since we have hoped in you. |  {} |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>