<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">By David. | Don't fret because of evildoers, / neither be envious against those who work unrighteousness. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> For they shall soon be cut down like the grass, / and wither like the green herb. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Trust in Yahweh, and do good. / Dwell in the land, and enjoy safe pasture. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Also delight yourself in Yahweh, / and he will give you the desires of your heart. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Commit your way to Yahweh. / Trust also in him, and he will do this: |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> he will make your righteousness go forth as the light, / and your justice as the noon day sun. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Rest in Yahweh, and wait patiently for him. / Don't fret because of him who prospers in his way, / because of the man who makes wicked plots happen. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Cease from anger, and forsake wrath. / Don't fret, it leads only to evildoing. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> For evildoers shall be cut off, / but those who wait for Yahweh shall inherit the land. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> For yet a little while, and the wicked will be no more. / Yes, though you look for his place, he isn't there. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> But the humble shall inherit the land, / and shall delight themselves in the abundance of peace. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> The wicked plots against the just, / and gnashes at him with his teeth. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> The Lord will laugh at him, / for he sees that his day is coming. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The wicked have drawn out the sword, and have bent their bow, / to cast down the poor and needy, / to kill those who are upright in the way. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Their sword shall enter into their own heart. / Their bows shall be broken. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Better is a little that the righteous has, / than the abundance of many wicked. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> For the arms of the wicked shall be broken, / but Yahweh upholds the righteous. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Yahweh knows the days of the perfect. / Their inheritance shall be forever. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> They shall not be disappointed in the time of evil. / In the days of famine they shall be satisfied. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> But the wicked shall perish. / The enemies of Yahweh shall be like the beauty of the fields. / They will vanish-- / vanish like smoke. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> The wicked borrow, and don't pay back, / but the righteous give generously. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> For such as are blessed by him shall inherit the land. / Those who are cursed by him shall be cut off. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> A man's goings are established by Yahweh. / He delights in his way. |</verse>
    <verse value="24"> Though he stumble, he shall not fall, / for Yahweh holds him up with his hand. |</verse>
    <verse value="25"> I have been young, and now am old, / yet I have not seen the righteous forsaken, / nor his children begging for bread. |</verse>
    <verse value="26"> All day long he deals graciously, and lends. / His seed is blessed. |</verse>
    <verse value="27"> Depart from evil, and do good. / Live securely forever. |</verse>
    <verse value="28"> For Yahweh loves justice, / and doesn't forsake his saints. / They are preserved forever, / but the children of the wicked shall be cut off. |</verse>
    <verse value="29"> The righteous shall inherit the land, / and live in it forever. |</verse>
    <verse value="30"> The mouth of the righteous talks of wisdom. / His tongue speaks justice. |</verse>
    <verse value="31"> The law of his God is in his heart. / None of his steps shall slide. |</verse>
    <verse value="32"> The wicked watches the righteous, / and seeks to kill him. |</verse>
    <verse value="33"> Yahweh will not leave him in his hand, / nor condemn him when he is judged. |</verse>
    <verse value="34"> Wait for Yahweh, and keep his way, / and he will exalt you to inherit the land. / When the wicked are cut off, you shall see it. |</verse>
    <verse value="35"> I have seen the wicked in great power, / spreading himself like a green tree in its native soil. |</verse>
    <verse value="36"> But he passed away, and behold, he was not. / Yes, I sought him, but he could not be found. |</verse>
    <verse value="37"> Mark the perfect man, and see the upright, / for there is a future for the man of peace. |</verse>
    <verse value="38"> As for transgressors, they shall be destroyed together. / The future of the wicked shall be cut off. |</verse>
    <verse value="39"> But the salvation of the righteous is from Yahweh. / He is their stronghold in the time of trouble. |</verse>
    <verse value="40"> Yahweh helps them, and rescues them. / He rescues them from the wicked, and saves them, / Because they have taken refuge in him. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>