<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For the Chief Musician. A Psalm by the sons of Korah. | Hear this, all you peoples. / Listen, all you inhabitants of the world, /</verse>
    <verse value="2"> both low and high, / rich and poor together. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> My mouth will speak words of wisdom. / My heart shall utter understanding. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> I will incline my ear to a proverb. / I will open my riddle on the harp. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Why should I fear in the days of evil, / when iniquity at my heels surrounds me? |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Those who trust in their wealth, / and boast in the multitude of their riches-- /</verse>
    <verse value="7"> none of them can by any means redeem his brother, / nor give God a ransom for him. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> For the redemption of their life is costly, / no payment is ever enough, /</verse>
    <verse value="9"> That he should live on forever, / that he should not see corruption. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> For he sees that wise men die; / likewise the fool and the senseless perish, / and leave their wealth to others. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Their inward thought is that their houses will endure forever, / and their dwelling places to all generations. / They name their lands after themselves. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> But man, despite his riches, doesn't endure. / He is like the animals that perish. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> This is the destiny of those who are foolish, / and of those who approve their sayings. | Selah. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> They are appointed as a flock for Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}. / Death shall be their shepherd. | The upright shall have dominion over them in the morning. / Their beauty shall decay in Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}, / far from their mansion. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> But God will redeem my soul from the power of Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}, / for he will receive me. | Selah. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Don't be afraid when a man is made rich, / when the glory of his house is increased. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> For when he dies he shall carry nothing away. / His glory shall not descend after him. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Though while he lived he blessed his soul-- / and men praise you when you do well for yourself-- /</verse>
    <verse value="19"> he shall go to the generation of his fathers. / They shall never see the light. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> A man who has riches without understanding, / is like the animals that perish. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>