<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For the Chief Musician. On stringed instruments. A contemplation by David. | Listen to my prayer, God. / Don't hide yourself from my supplication. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Attend to me, and answer me. / I am restless in my complaint, and moan, /</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Because of the voice of the enemy, / Because of the oppression of the wicked. | For they bring suffering on me. / In anger they hold a grudge against me. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> My heart is severely pained within me. / The terrors of death have fallen on me. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Fearfulness and trembling have come on me. / Horror has overwhelmed me. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> I said, "Oh that I had wings like a dove! / Then I would fly away, and be at rest. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Behold, then I would wander far off. / I would lodge in the wilderness." | Selah. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> "I would hurry to a shelter from the stormy wind and storm." |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Confuse them, Lord, and confound their language, / for I have seen violence and strife in the city. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Day and night they prowl around on its walls. / Malice and abuse are also within her. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Destructive forces are within her. / Threats and lies don't depart from her streets. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> For it was not an enemy who insulted me, / then I could have endured it. | Neither was it he who hated me who raised himself up against me, / then I would have hidden myself from him. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> But it was you, a man like me, / my companion, and my familiar friend. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> We took sweet fellowship together. / We walked in God's house with company. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Let death come suddenly on them. / Let them go down alive into Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}. / For wickedness is in their dwelling, in their midst. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> As for me, I will call on God. / Yahweh will save me. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Evening, morning, and at noon, I will cry out in distress. / He will hear my voice. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> He has redeemed my soul in peace from the battle that was against me, / although there are many who oppose me. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> God, who is enthroned forever, / will hear, and answer them. | Selah. | They never change, / who don't fear God. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> He raises his hands against his friends. / He has violated his covenant. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> His mouth was smooth as butter, / but his heart was war. | His words were softer than oil, / yet they were drawn swords. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Cast your burden on Yahweh, and he will sustain you. / He will never allow the righteous to be moved. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> But you, God, will bring them down into the pit of destruction. / Bloodthirsty and deceitful men shall not live out half their days, / but I will trust in you. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>