<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">By Solomon. | God, give the king your justice; / your righteousness to the royal son. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> He will judge your people with righteousness, / and your poor with justice. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> The mountains shall bring prosperity to the people. / The hills bring the fruit of righteousness. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> He will judge the poor of the people. / He will save the children of the needy, / and will break the oppressor in pieces. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> They shall fear you while the sun endures; / and as long as the moon, throughout all generations. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> He will come down like rain on the mown grass, / as showers that water the earth. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> In his days, the righteous shall flourish, / and abundance of peace, until the moon is no more. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> He shall have dominion also from sea to sea, / from the River to the ends of the earth. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Those who dwell in the wilderness shall bow before him. / His enemies shall lick the dust. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The kings of Tarshish and of the islands will bring tribute. / The kings of Sheba and Seba shall offer gifts. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Yes, all kings shall fall down before him. / All nations shall serve him. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> For he will deliver the needy when he cries; / the poor, who has no helper. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> He will have pity on the poor and needy. / He will save the souls of the needy. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> He will redeem their soul from oppression and violence. / Their blood will be precious in his sight. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> They shall live, and to him shall be given of the gold of Sheba. / Men shall pray for him continually. / They shall bless him all day long. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Abundance of grain shall be throughout the land. / Its fruit sways like Lebanon. / Let it flourish, thriving like the grass of the field. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> His name endures forever. / His name continues as long as the sun. | Men shall be blessed by him. / All nations will call him blessed. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Praise be to Yahweh God, the God of Israel, / who alone does marvelous deeds. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Blessed be his glorious name forever! / Let the whole earth be filled with his glory! | Amen and amen. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> This ends the prayers by David, the son of Jesse. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>