<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">A contemplation by Asaph. | God, why have you rejected us forever? / Why does your anger smolder against the sheep of your pasture? |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Remember your congregation, which you purchased of old, / which you have redeemed to be the tribe of your inheritance; / Mount Zion, in which you have lived. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Lift up your feet to the perpetual ruins, / all the evil that the enemy has done in the sanctuary. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Your adversaries have roared in the midst of your assembly. / They have set up their standards as signs. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> They behaved like men wielding axes, / cutting through a thicket of trees. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Now they break all its carved work down with hatchet and hammers. /</verse>
    <verse value="7"> They have burned your sanctuary to the ground. / They have profaned the dwelling place of your Name. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> They said in their heart, "We will crush them completely." / They have burned up all the places in the land where God was worshiped. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> We see no miraculous signs. / There is no longer any prophet, / neither is there among us anyone who knows how long. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> How long, God, shall the adversary reproach? / Shall the enemy blaspheme your name forever? |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Why do you draw back your hand, even your right hand? / Take it out of your pocket and consume them! |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Yet God is my King of old, / working salvation in the midst of the earth. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> You divided the sea by your strength. / You broke the heads of the sea monsters in the waters. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> You broke the heads of Leviathan in pieces. / You gave him as food to people and desert creatures. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> You opened up spring and stream. / You dried up mighty rivers. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> The day is yours, the night is also yours. / You have prepared the light and the sun. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> You have set all the boundaries of the earth. / You have made summer and winter. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Remember this, that the enemy has mocked you, Yahweh. / Foolish people have blasphemed your name. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Don't deliver the soul of your dove to wild beasts. / Don't forget the life of your poor forever. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Honor your covenant, / for haunts of violence fill the dark places of the earth. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Don't let the oppressed return ashamed. / Let the poor and needy praise your name. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Arise, God! Plead your own cause. / Remember how the foolish man mocks you all day. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Don't forget the voice of your adversaries. / The tumult of those who rise up against you ascends continually. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>