<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">A Prayer by David. | Hear, Yahweh, and answer me, / for I am poor and needy. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Preserve my soul, for I am godly. / You, my God, save your servant who trusts in you. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Be merciful to me, Lord, / for I call to you all day long. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Bring joy to the soul of your servant, / for to you, Lord, do I lift up my soul. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> For you, Lord, are good, and ready to forgive; / abundant in loving kindness to all those who call on you. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Hear, Yahweh, my prayer. / Listen to the voice of my petitions. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> In the day of my trouble I will call on you, / for you will answer me. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> There is no one like you among the gods, Lord, / nor any deeds like your deeds. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> All nations you have made will come and worship before you, Lord. / They shall glorify your name. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> For you are great, and do wondrous things. / You are God alone. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Teach me your way, Yahweh. / I will walk in your truth. / Make my heart undivided to fear your name. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> I will praise you, Lord my God, with my whole heart. / I will glorify your name forevermore. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> For your loving kindness is great toward me. / You have delivered my soul from the lowest Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> God, the proud have risen up against me. / A company of violent men have sought after my soul, / and they don't hold regard for you before them. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> But you, Lord, are a merciful and gracious God, / slow to anger, and abundant in loving kindness and truth. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Turn to me, and have mercy on me! / Give your strength to your servant. / Save the son of your handmaid. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Show me a sign of your goodness, / that those who hate me may see it, and be shamed, / because you, Yahweh, have helped me, and comforted me. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>