<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">A Song. A Psalm by the sons of Korah. For the Chief Musician. To the tune of "The Suffering of Affliction." A contemplation by Heman, the Ezrahite. | Yahweh, the God of my salvation, / I have cried day and night before you. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Let my prayer enter into your presence. / Turn your ear to my cry. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> For my soul is full of troubles. / My life draws near to Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> I am counted among those who go down into the pit. / I am like a man who has no help, /</verse>
    <verse value="5"> set apart among the dead, / like the slain who lie in the grave, / whom you remember no more. / They are cut off from your hand. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> You have laid me in the lowest pit, / in the darkest depths. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Your wrath lies heavily on me. / You have afflicted me with all your waves. | Selah. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> You have taken my friends from me. / You have made me an abomination to them. / I am confined, and I can't escape. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> My eyes are dim from grief. / I have called on you daily, Yahweh. / I have spread out my hands to you. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Do you show wonders to the dead? / Do the dead rise up and praise you? | Selah. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Is your loving kindness declared in the grave? / Or your faithfulness in Destruction? |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Are your wonders made known in the dark? / Or your righteousness in the land of forgetfulness? |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> But to you, Yahweh, I have cried. / In the morning, my prayer comes before you. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Yahweh, why do you reject my soul? / Why do you hide your face from me? |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> I am afflicted and ready to die from my youth up. / While I suffer your terrors, I am distracted. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Your fierce wrath has gone over me. / Your terrors have cut me off. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> They came around me like water all day long. / They completely engulfed me. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> You have put lover and friend far from me, / and my friends into darkness. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>