<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">A contemplation by Ethan, the Ezrahite. | I will sing of the loving kindness of Yahweh forever. / With my mouth, I will make known your faithfulness to all generations. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> I indeed declare, "Love stands firm forever. / You established the heavens. / Your faithfulness is in them." |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> "I have made a covenant with my chosen one, / I have sworn to David, my servant, |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> 'I will establish your seed forever, / and build up your throne to all generations.'" | Selah. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> The heavens will praise your wonders, Yahweh; / your faithfulness also in the assembly of the holy ones. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> For who in the skies can be compared to Yahweh? / Who among the sons of the heavenly beings is like Yahweh, |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> a very awesome God in the council of the holy ones, / to be feared above all those who are around him? |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Yahweh, God of Armies, who is a mighty one, like you? / Yah, your faithfulness is around you. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> You rule the pride of the sea. / When its waves rise up, you calm them. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> You have broken Rahab in pieces, like one of the slain. / You have scattered your enemies with your mighty arm. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The heavens are yours. / The earth also is yours; / the world and its fullness. / You have founded them. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> The north and the south, you have created them. / Tabor and Hermon rejoice in your name. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> You have a mighty arm. / Your hand is strong, and your right hand is exalted. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Righteousness and justice are the foundation of your throne. / Loving kindness and truth go before your face. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Blessed are the people who learn to acclaim you. / They walk in the light of your presence, Yahweh. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> In your name they rejoice all day. / In your righteousness, they are exalted. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> For you are the glory of their strength. / In your favor, our horn will be exalted. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> For our shield belongs to Yahweh; / our king to the Holy One of Israel. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Then you spoke in vision to your saints, / and said, "I have bestowed strength on the warrior. / I have exalted a young man from the people. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> I have found David, my servant. / I have anointed him with my holy oil, |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> with whom my hand shall be established. / My arm will also strengthen him. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> No enemy will tax him. / No wicked man will oppress him. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> I will beat down his adversaries before him, / and strike those who hate him. |</verse>
    <verse value="24"> But my faithfulness and my loving kindness will be with him. / In my name, his horn will be exalted. |</verse>
    <verse value="25"> I will set his hand also on the sea, / and his right hand on the rivers. |</verse>
    <verse value="26"> He will call to me, 'You are my Father, / my God, and the rock of my salvation!' |</verse>
    <verse value="27"> I will also appoint him my firstborn, / the highest of the kings of the earth. |</verse>
    <verse value="28"> I will keep my loving kindness for him forevermore. / My covenant will stand firm with him. |</verse>
    <verse value="29"> I will also make his seed endure forever, / and his throne as the days of heaven. |</verse>
    <verse value="30"> If his children forsake my law, / and don't walk in my ordinances; |</verse>
    <verse value="31"> if they break my statutes, / and don't keep my commandments; |</verse>
    <verse value="32"> then I will punish their sin with the rod, / and their iniquity with stripes. |</verse>
    <verse value="33"> But I will not completely take my loving kindness from him, / nor allow my faithfulness to fail. |</verse>
    <verse value="34"> I will not break my covenant, / nor alter what my lips have uttered. |</verse>
    <verse value="35"> Once have I sworn by my holiness, / I will not lie to David. |</verse>
    <verse value="36"> His seed will endure forever, / his throne like the sun before me. |</verse>
    <verse value="37"> It will be established forever like the moon, / the faithful witness in the sky." | Selah. |</verse>
    <verse value="38"> But you have rejected and spurned. / You have been angry with your anointed. |</verse>
    <verse value="39"> You have renounced the covenant of your servant. / You have defiled his crown in the dust. |</verse>
    <verse value="40"> You have broken down all his hedges. / You have brought his strongholds to ruin. |</verse>
    <verse value="41"> All who pass by the way rob him. | He has become a reproach to his neighbors. |</verse>
    <verse value="42"> You have exalted the right hand of his adversaries. / You have made all of his enemies rejoice. |</verse>
    <verse value="43"> Yes, you turn back the edge of his sword, / and haven't supported him in battle. |</verse>
    <verse value="44"> You have ended his splendor, / and thrown his throne down to the ground. |</verse>
    <verse value="45"> You have shortened the days of his youth. / You have covered him with shame. | Selah. |</verse>
    <verse value="46"> How long, Yahweh? / Will you hide yourself forever? / Will your wrath burn like fire? |</verse>
    <verse value="47"> Remember how short my time is! / For what vanity have you created all the children of men! |</verse>
    <verse value="48"> What man is he who shall live and not see death, / who shall deliver his soul from the power of Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}? | Selah. |</verse>
    <verse value="49"> Lord, where are your former loving kindnesses, / which you swore to David in your faithfulness? |</verse>
    <verse value="50"> Remember, Lord, the reproach of your servants, / how I bear in my heart the taunts of all the mighty peoples, |</verse>
    <verse value="51"> With which your enemies have mocked, Yahweh, / with which they have mocked the footsteps of your anointed one. |</verse>
    <verse value="52"> Blessed be Yahweh forevermore. | Amen, and Amen. |  {} |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>