<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Bless Yahweh, my soul. / Yahweh, my God, you are very great. / You are clothed with honor and majesty. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> He covers himself with light as with a garment. / He stretches out the heavens like a curtain. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> He lays the beams of his rooms in the waters. / He makes the clouds his chariot. / He walks on the wings of the wind. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> He makes his messengers {or, angels} winds; / his servants flames of fire. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> He laid the foundations of the earth, / that it should not be moved forever. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> You covered it with the deep as with a cloak. / The waters stood above the mountains. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> At your rebuke they fled. / At the voice of your thunder they hurried away. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> The mountains rose, / the valleys sank down, / to the place which you had assigned to them. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> You have set a boundary that they may not pass over; / that they don't turn again to cover the earth. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> He sends forth springs into the valleys. / They run among the mountains. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> They give drink to every animal of the field. / The wild donkeys quench their thirst. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> The birds of the sky nest by them. / They sing among the branches. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> He waters the mountains from his rooms. / The earth is filled with the fruit of your works. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> He causes the grass to grow for the livestock, / and plants for man to cultivate, / that he may bring forth food out of the earth: |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> wine that makes glad the heart of man, / oil to make his face to shine, / and bread that strengthens man's heart. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Yahweh's trees are well watered, / the cedars of Lebanon, which he has planted; |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> where the birds make their nests. / The stork makes its home in the fir trees. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> The high mountains are for the wild goats. / The rocks are a refuge for the rock badgers. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> He appointed the moon for seasons. / The sun knows when to set. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> You make darkness, and it is night, / in which all the animals of the forest prowl. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> The young lions roar after their prey, / and seek their food from God. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The sun rises, and they steal away, / and lay down in their dens. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Man goes forth to his work, / to his labor until the evening. |</verse>
    <verse value="24"> Yahweh, how many are your works! / In wisdom have you made them all. / The earth is full of your riches. |</verse>
    <verse value="25"> There is the sea, great and wide, / in which are innumerable living things, / both small and large animals. |</verse>
    <verse value="26"> There the ships go, / and leviathan, whom you formed to play there. |</verse>
    <verse value="27"> These all wait for you, / that you may give them their food in due season. |</verse>
    <verse value="28"> You give to them; they gather. / You open your hand; they are satisfied with good. |</verse>
    <verse value="29"> You hide your face: they are troubled; / you take away their breath: they die, and return to the dust. |</verse>
    <verse value="30"> You send forth your Spirit: they are created. / You renew the face of the ground. |</verse>
    <verse value="31"> Let the glory of Yahweh endure forever. / Let Yahweh rejoice in his works. |</verse>
    <verse value="32"> He looks at the earth, and it trembles. / He touches the mountains, and they smoke. |</verse>
    <verse value="33"> I will sing to Yahweh as long as I live. / I will sing praise to my God while I have any being. |</verse>
    <verse value="34"> Let your meditation be sweet to him. / I will rejoice in Yahweh. |</verse>
    <verse value="35"> Let sinners be consumed out of the earth. / Let the wicked be no more. / Bless Yahweh, my soul. / Praise Yah! |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>