<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">A Song of Ascents. | Yahweh, remember David and all his affliction, |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> how he swore to Yahweh, / and vowed to the Mighty One of Jacob: |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> "Surely I will not come into the structure of my house, / nor go up into my bed; |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> I will not give sleep to my eyes, / or slumber to my eyelids; |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> until I find out a place for Yahweh, / a dwelling for the Mighty One of Jacob." |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Behold, we heard of it in Ephrathah. / We found it in the field of Jaar: |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> "We will go into his dwelling place. / We will worship at his footstool. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Arise, Yahweh, into your resting place; / you, and the ark of your strength. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Let your priest be clothed with righteousness. / Let your saints shout for joy!" |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> For your servant David's sake, / don't turn away the face of your anointed one. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Yahweh has sworn to David in truth. / He will not turn from it: / "I will set the fruit of your body on your throne. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> If your children will keep my covenant, / my testimony that I will teach them, / their children also will sit on your throne forevermore." |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> For Yahweh has chosen Zion. / He has desired it for his habitation. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> "This is my resting place forever. / Here I will live, for I have desired it. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> I will abundantly bless her provision. / I will satisfy her poor with bread. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Her priests I will also clothe with salvation. / Her saints will shout aloud for joy. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> There I will make the horn of David to bud. / I have ordained a lamp for my anointed. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> I will clothe his enemies with shame, / but on himself, his crown will be resplendent." |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>