<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For the Chief Musician. A Psalm by David. | Yahweh, you have searched me, / and you know me. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> You know my sitting down and my rising up. / You perceive my thoughts from afar. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> You search out my path and my lying down, / and are acquainted with all my ways. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> For there is not a word on my tongue, / but, behold, Yahweh, you know it altogether. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> You hem me in behind and before. / You laid your hand on me. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> This knowledge is beyond me. / It's lofty. / I can't attain it. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Where could I go from your Spirit? / Or where could I flee from your presence? |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> If I ascend up into heaven, you are there. / If I make my bed in Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}, behold, you are there! |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> If I take the wings of the dawn, / and settle in the uttermost parts of the sea; |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Even there your hand will lead me, / and your right hand will hold me. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> If I say, "Surely the darkness will overwhelm me; / the light around me will be night"; |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> even the darkness doesn't hide from you, / but the night shines as the day. / The darkness is like light to you. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> For you formed my inmost being. / You knit me together in my mother's womb. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> I will give thanks to you, / for I am fearfully and wonderfully made. | Your works are wonderful. / My soul knows that very well. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> My frame wasn't hidden from you, / when I was made in secret, / woven together in the depths of the earth. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Your eyes saw my body. / In your book they were all written, / the days that were ordained for me, / when as yet there were none of them. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> How precious to me are your thoughts, God! / How vast is their sum! |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> If I would count them, they are more in number than the sand. / When I wake up, I am still with you. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> If only you, God, would kill the wicked. / Get away from me, you bloodthirsty men! |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> For they speak against you wickedly. / Your enemies take your name in vain. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Yahweh, don't I hate those who hate you? / Am I not grieved with those who rise up against you? |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> I hate them with perfect hatred. / They have become my enemies. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Search me, God, and know my heart. / Try me, and know my thoughts. |</verse>
    <verse value="24"> See if there is any wicked way in me, / and lead me in the everlasting way. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>