<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">My son, if you will receive my words, / and store up my commandments within you; |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> So as to turn your ear to wisdom, / and apply your heart to understanding; |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Yes, if you call out for discernment, / and lift up your voice for understanding; |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> If you seek her as silver, / and search for her as for hidden treasures: |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> then you will understand the fear of Yahweh, / and find the knowledge of God {The Hebrew word rendered "God" is "Elohim."}. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> For Yahweh gives wisdom. / Out of his mouth comes knowledge and understanding. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> He lays up sound wisdom for the upright. / He is a shield to those who walk in integrity; |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> that he may guard the paths of justice, / and preserve the way of his saints. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Then you will understand righteousness and justice, / equity and every good path. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> For wisdom will enter into your heart. / Knowledge will be pleasant to your soul. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Discretion will watch over you. / Understanding will keep you, |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> to deliver you from the way of evil, / from the men who speak perverse things; |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> who forsake the paths of uprightness, / to walk in the ways of darkness; |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> who rejoice to do evil, / and delight in the perverseness of evil; |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> who are crooked in their ways, / and wayward in their paths: |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> To deliver you from the strange woman, / even from the foreigner who flatters with her words; |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> who forsakes the friend of her youth, / and forgets the covenant of her God: |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> for her house leads down to death, / her paths to the dead. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> None who go to her return again, / neither do they attain to the paths of life: |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> that you may walk in the way of good men, / and keep the paths of the righteous. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> For the upright will dwell in the land. / The perfect will remain in it. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> But the wicked will be cut off from the land. / The treacherous will be rooted out of it. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>