<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">My son, pay attention to my wisdom. / Turn your ear to my understanding: |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> that you may maintain discretion, / that your lips may preserve knowledge. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> For the lips of an adulteress drip honey. / Her mouth is smoother than oil, |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> But in the end she is as bitter as wormwood, / and as sharp as a two-edged sword. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Her feet go down to death. / Her steps lead straight to Sheol {Sheol is the place of the dead.}. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> She gives no thought to the way of life. / Her ways are crooked, and she doesn't know it. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Now therefore, my sons, listen to me. / Don't depart from the words of my mouth. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Remove your way far from her. / Don't come near the door of her house, |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> lest you give your honor to others, / and your years to the cruel one; |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> lest strangers feast on your wealth, / and your labors enrich another man's house. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> You will groan at your latter end, / when your flesh and your body are consumed, |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> and say, "How I have hated instruction, / and my heart despised reproof; |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> neither have I obeyed the voice of my teachers, / nor turned my ear to those who instructed me! |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> I have come to the brink of utter ruin, / in the midst of the gathered assembly." |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Drink water out of your own cistern, / running water out of your own well. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Should your springs overflow in the streets, / streams of water in the public squares? |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Let them be for yourself alone, / not for strangers with you. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Let your spring be blessed. / Rejoice in the wife of your youth. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> A loving doe and a graceful deer-- / let her breasts satisfy you at all times. / Be captivated always with her love. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> For why should you, my son, be captivated with an adulteress? / Why embrace the bosom of another? |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> For the ways of man are before the eyes of Yahweh. / He examines all his paths. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The evil deeds of the wicked ensnare him. / The cords of his sin hold him firmly. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> He will die for lack of instruction. / In the greatness of his folly, he will go astray. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>