<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">An unfriendly man pursues selfishness, / and defies all sound judgment. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> A fool has no delight in understanding, / but only in revealing his own opinion. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> When wickedness comes, contempt also comes, / and with shame comes disgrace. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> The words of a man's mouth are like deep waters. / The fountain of wisdom is like a flowing brook. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> To be partial to the faces of the wicked is not good, / nor to deprive the innocent of justice. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> A fool's lips come into strife, / and his mouth invites beatings. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> A fool's mouth is his destruction, / and his lips are a snare to his soul. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> The words of a gossip are like dainty morsels: / they go down into a person's innermost parts. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> One who is slack in his work / is brother to him who is a master of destruction. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The name of Yahweh is a strong tower: / the righteous run to him, and are safe. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The rich man's wealth is his strong city, / like an unscalable wall in his own imagination. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Before destruction the heart of man is proud, / but before honor is humility. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> He who gives answer before he hears, / that is folly and shame to him. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> A man's spirit will sustain him in sickness, / but a crushed spirit, who can bear? |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The heart of the discerning gets knowledge. / The ear of the wise seeks knowledge. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> A man's gift makes room for him, / and brings him before great men. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> He who pleads his cause first seems right; / until another comes and questions him. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> The lot settles disputes, / and keeps strong ones apart. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> A brother offended is more difficult than a fortified city; / and disputes are like the bars of a castle. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> A man's stomach is filled with the fruit of his mouth. / With the harvest of his lips he is satisfied. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Death and life are in the power of the tongue; / those who love it will eat its fruit. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Whoever finds a wife finds a good thing, / and obtains favor of Yahweh. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> The poor plead for mercy, / but the rich answer harshly. |</verse>
    <verse value="24"> A man of many companions may be ruined, / but there is a friend who sticks closer than a brother. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>