<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Wine is a mocker, and beer is a brawler. / Whoever is led astray by them is not wise. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> The terror of a king is like the roaring of a lion. / He who provokes him to anger forfeits his own life. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> It is an honor for a man to keep aloof from strife; / but every fool will be quarreling. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> The sluggard will not plow by reason of the winter; / therefore he shall beg in harvest, and have nothing. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Counsel in the heart of man is like deep water; / but a man of understanding will draw it out. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Many men claim to be men of unfailing love, / but who can find a faithful man? |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> A righteous man walks in integrity. / Blessed are his children after him. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> A king who sits on the throne of judgment / scatters away all evil with his eyes. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Who can say, "I have made my heart pure. / I am clean and without sin?" |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Differing weights and differing measures, / both of them alike are an abomination to Yahweh. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Even a child makes himself known by his doings, / whether his work is pure, and whether it is right. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> The hearing ear, and the seeing eye, / Yahweh has made even both of them. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Don't love sleep, lest you come to poverty. / Open your eyes, and you shall be satisfied with bread. |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> "It's no good, it's no good," says the buyer; / but when he is gone his way, then he boasts. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> There is gold and abundance of rubies; / but the lips of knowledge are a rare jewel. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Take the garment of one who puts up collateral for a stranger; / and hold him in pledge for a wayward woman. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Fraudulent food is sweet to a man, / but afterwards his mouth is filled with gravel. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Plans are established by advice; / by wise guidance you wage war! |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> He who goes about as a tale-bearer reveals secrets; / therefore don't keep company with him who opens wide his lips. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Whoever curses his father or his mother, / his lamp shall be put out in blackness of darkness. |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> An inheritance quickly gained at the beginning, / won't be blessed in the end. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Don't say, "I will pay back evil." / Wait for Yahweh, and he will save you. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Yahweh detests differing weights, / and dishonest scales are not pleasing. |</verse>
    <verse value="24"> A man's steps are from Yahweh; / how then can man understand his way? |</verse>
    <verse value="25"> It is a snare to a man to make a rash dedication, / then later to consider his vows. |</verse>
    <verse value="26"> A wise king winnows out the wicked, / and drives the threshing wheel over them. |</verse>
    <verse value="27"> The spirit of man is Yahweh's lamp, / searching all his innermost parts. |</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Love and faithfulness keep the king safe. / His throne is sustained by love. |</verse>
    <verse value="29"> The glory of young men is their strength. / The splendor of old men is their gray hair. |</verse>
    <verse value="30"> Wounding blows cleanse away evil, / and beatings purge the innermost parts. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>