<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">A good name is more desirable than great riches, / and loving favor is better than silver and gold. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> The rich and the poor have this in common: / Yahweh is the maker of them all. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> A prudent man sees danger, and hides himself; / but the simple pass on, and suffer for it. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> The result of humility and the fear of Yahweh / is wealth, honor, and life. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Thorns and snares are in the path of the wicked: / whoever guards his soul stays from them. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Train up a child in the way he should go, / and when he is old he will not depart from it. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> The rich rule over the poor. / The borrower is servant to the lender. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> He who sows wickedness reaps trouble, / and the rod of his fury will be destroyed. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> He who has a generous eye will be blessed; / for he shares his food with the poor. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Drive out the mocker, and strife will go out; / yes, quarrels and insults will stop. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> He who loves purity of heart and speaks gracefully / is the king's friend. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> The eyes of Yahweh watch over knowledge; / but he frustrates the words of the unfaithful. |</verse>
    <verse value="13"> The sluggard says, "There is a lion outside! / I will be killed in the streets!" |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The mouth of an adulteress is a deep pit: / he who is under Yahweh's wrath will fall into it. |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Folly is bound up in the heart of a child: / the rod of discipline drives it far from him. |</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Whoever oppresses the poor for his own increase and whoever gives to the rich, / both come to poverty. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Turn your ear, and listen to the words of the wise. / Apply your heart to my teaching. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> For it is a pleasant thing if you keep them within you, / if all of them are ready on your lips. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> That your trust may be in Yahweh, / I teach you today, even you. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Haven't I written to you thirty excellent things / of counsel and knowledge, |</verse>
    <verse value="21"> To teach you truth, reliable words, / to give sound answers to the ones who sent you? |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Don't exploit the poor, because he is poor; / and don't crush the needy in court; |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> for Yahweh will plead their case, / and plunder the life of those who plunder them. |</verse>
    <verse value="24"> Don't befriend a hot-tempered man, / and don't associate with one who harbors anger: |</verse>
    <verse value="25"> lest you learn his ways, / and ensnare your soul. |</verse>
    <verse value="26"> Don't you be one of those who strike hands, / of those who are collateral for debts. |</verse>
    <verse value="27"> If you don't have means to pay, / why should he take away your bed from under you? |</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Don't move the ancient boundary stone, / which your fathers have set up. |</verse>
    <verse value="29"> Do you see a man skilled in his work? / He will serve kings. / He won't serve obscure men. |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>