<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">This is what Isaiah the son of Amoz saw concerning Judah and Jerusalem. |</verse>
    <verse value="2"> It shall happen in the latter days, that the mountain of Yahweh's house shall be established on the top of the mountains, / and shall be raised above the hills; / and all nations shall flow to it. |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Many peoples shall go and say, / "Come, let's go up to the mountain of Yahweh, / to the house of the God of Jacob; / and he will teach us of his ways, / and we will walk in his paths." | For out of Zion the law shall go forth, / and the word of Yahweh from Jerusalem. |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> He will judge between the nations, / and will decide concerning many peoples; / and they shall beat their swords into plowshares, / and their spears into pruning hooks. | Nation shall not lift up sword against nation, / neither shall they learn war any more. |</verse>
    <verse value="5"> House of Jacob, come, and let us walk in the light of Yahweh. |</verse>
    <verse value="6"> For you have forsaken your people, the house of Jacob, / because they are filled from the east, / with those who practice divination like the Philistines, / and they clasp hands with the children of foreigners. |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Their land is full of silver and gold, / neither is there any end of their treasures. | Their land also is full of horses, / neither is there any end of their chariots. |</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Their land also is full of idols. / They worship the work of their own hands, / that which their own fingers have made. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Man is brought low, / and mankind is humbled; / therefore don't forgive them. |</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Enter into the rock, / and hide in the dust, | from before the terror of Yahweh, / and from the glory of his majesty. |</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The lofty looks of man will be brought low, / the haughtiness of men will be bowed down, / and Yahweh alone will be exalted in that day. |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> For there will be a day of Yahweh of Armies for all that is proud and haughty, / and for all that is lifted up; / and it shall be brought low: /</verse>
    <verse value="13"> For all the cedars of Lebanon, that are high and lifted up, / for all the oaks of Bashan, /</verse>
    <verse value="14"> For all the high mountains, / for all the hills that are lifted up, /</verse>
    <verse value="15"> For every lofty tower, / for every fortified wall, /</verse>
    <verse value="16"> For all the ships of Tarshish, / and for all pleasant imagery. |</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The loftiness of man shall be bowed down, / and the haughtiness of men shall be brought low; / and Yahweh alone shall be exalted in that day. |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> The idols shall utterly pass away. |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Men shall go into the caves of the rocks, / and into the holes of the earth, / from before the terror of Yahweh, / and from the glory of his majesty, / when he arises to shake the earth mightily. |</verse>
    <verse value="20"> In that day, men shall cast away their idols of silver, / and their idols of gold, / which have been made for themselves to worship, / to the moles and to the bats; /</verse>
    <verse value="21"> To go into the caverns of the rocks, / and into the clefts of the ragged rocks, / from before the terror of Yahweh, / and from the glory of his majesty, / when he arises to shake the earth mightily. |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Stop trusting in man, whose breath is in his nostrils; / for of what account is he? |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>