<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="WEV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">He entered into a boat, and crossed over, and came into his own city.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Behold, they brought to him a man who was paralyzed, lying on a bed. Jesus, seeing their faith, said to the paralytic, "Son, cheer up! Your sins are forgiven you." |</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Behold, some of the scribes said to themselves, "This man blasphemes." |</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Jesus, knowing their thoughts, said, "Why do you think evil in your hearts?</verse>
    <verse value="5"> For which is easier, to say, 'Your sins are forgiven;' or to say, 'Get up, and walk?'</verse>
    <verse value="6"> But that you may know that the Son of Man has authority on earth to forgive sins..." (then he said to the paralytic), "Get up, and take up your mat, and go up to your house." |</verse>
    <verse value="7"> He arose and departed to his house.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> But when the multitudes saw it, they marveled and glorified God, who had given such authority to men. |</verse>
    <verse value="9"> As Jesus passed by from there, he saw a man called Matthew sitting at the tax collection office. He said to him, "Follow me." He got up and followed him.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> It happened as he sat in the house, behold, many tax collectors and sinners came and sat down with Jesus and his disciples.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> When the Pharisees saw it, they said to his disciples, "Why does your teacher eat with tax collectors and sinners?" |</verse>
    <verse value="12"> When Jesus heard it, he said to them, "Those who are healthy have no need for a physician, but those who are sick do.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> But you go and learn what this means: 'I desire mercy, and not sacrifice,' {Hosea 6:6} for I came not to call the righteous, but sinners to repentance. {NU omits "to repentance".}" |</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Then John's disciples came to him, saying, "Why do we and the Pharisees fast often, but your disciples don't fast?" |</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Jesus said to them, "Can the friends of the bridegroom mourn, as long as the bridegroom is with them? But the days will come when the bridegroom will be taken away from them, and then they will fast.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> No one puts a piece of unshrunk cloth on an old garment; for the patch would tear away from the garment, and a worse hole is made.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Neither do people put new wine into old wineskins, or else the skins would burst, and the wine be spilled, and the skins ruined. No, they put new wine into fresh wineskins, and both are preserved." |</verse>
    <verse value="18"> While he told these things to them, behold, a ruler came and worshiped him, saying, "My daughter has just died, but come and lay your hand on her, and she will live." |</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Jesus got up and followed him, as did his disciples.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Behold, a woman who had an issue of blood for twelve years came behind him, and touched the fringe {or, tassel} of his garment;</verse>
    <verse value="21"> for she said within herself, "If I just touch his garment, I will be made well." |</verse>
    <verse value="22"> But Jesus, turning around and seeing her, said, "Daughter, cheer up! Your faith has made you well." And the woman was made well from that hour. |</verse>
    <verse value="23"> When Jesus came into the ruler's house, and saw the flute players, and the crowd in noisy disorder,</verse>
    <verse value="24"> he said to them, "Make room, because the girl isn't dead, but sleeping." | They were ridiculing him.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> But when the crowd was put out, he entered in, took her by the hand, and the girl arose.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> The report of this went out into all that land.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> As Jesus passed by from there, two blind men followed him, calling out and saying, "Have mercy on us, son of David!" |</verse>
    <verse value="28"> When he had come into the house, the blind men came to him. Jesus said to them, "Do you believe that I am able to do this?" | They told him, "Yes, Lord." |</verse>
    <verse value="29"> Then he touched their eyes, saying, "According to your faith be it done to you."</verse>
    <verse value="30"> Their eyes were opened. Jesus strictly commanded them, saying, "See that no one knows about this."</verse>
    <verse value="31"> But they went out and spread abroad his fame in all that land. |</verse>
    <verse value="32"> As they went out, behold, a mute man who was demon possessed was brought to him.</verse>
    <verse value="33"> When the demon was cast out, the mute man spoke. The multitudes marveled, saying, "Nothing like this has ever been seen in Israel!" |</verse>
    <verse value="34"> But the Pharisees said, "By the prince of the demons, he casts out demons." |</verse>
    <verse value="35"> Jesus went about all the cities and the villages, teaching in their synagogues, and preaching the Good News of the Kingdom, and healing every disease and every sickness among the people.</verse>
    <verse value="36"> But when he saw the multitudes, he was moved with compassion for them, because they were harassed {TR reads "weary" instead of "harassed"} and scattered, like sheep without a shepherd.</verse>
    <verse value="37"> Then he said to his disciples, "The harvest indeed is plentiful, but the laborers are few.</verse>
    <verse value="38"> Pray therefore that the Lord of the harvest will send out laborers into his harvest." |</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>