<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Meanwhile, Saul was still breathing out murderous threats against the Lord's disciples. He went to the high priest </verse>
    <verse value="2"> and asked him for letters to the synagogues in Damascus, so that if he found any there who belonged to the Way, whether men or women, he might take them as prisoners to Jerusalem. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> As he neared Damascus on his journey, suddenly a light from heaven flashed around him. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> He fell to the ground and heard a voice say to him, "Saul, Saul, why do you persecute me?" </verse>
    <verse value="5"> "Who are you, Lord?" Saul asked. "I am Jesus, whom you are persecuting," he replied.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> "Now get up and go into the city, and you will be told what you must do." </verse>
    <verse value="7"> The men traveling with Saul stood there speechless; they heard the sound but did not see anyone. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> Saul got up from the ground, but when he opened his eyes he could see nothing. So they led him by the hand into Damascus. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> For three days he was blind, and did not eat or drink anything.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> In Damascus there was a disciple named Ananias. The Lord called to him in a vision, "Ananias!" "Yes, Lord," he answered.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The Lord told him, "Go to the house of Judas on Straight Street and ask for a man from Tarsus named Saul, for he is praying. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> In a vision he has seen a man named Ananias come and place his hands on him to restore his sight." </verse>
    <verse value="13"> "Lord," Ananias answered, "I have heard many reports about this man and all the harm he has done to your saints in Jerusalem. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> And he has come here with authority from the chief priests to arrest all who call on your name." </verse>
    <verse value="15"> But the Lord said to Ananias, "Go! This man is my chosen instrument to carry my name before the Gentiles and their kings and before the people of Israel. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> I will show him how much he must suffer for my name." </verse>
    <verse value="17"> Then Ananias went to the house and entered it. Placing his hands on Saul, he said, "Brother Saul, the Lord--Jesus, who appeared to you on the road as you were coming here--has sent me so that you may see again and be filled with the Holy Spirit." </verse>
    <verse value="18"> Immediately, something like scales fell from Saul's eyes, and he could see again. He got up and was baptized, </verse>
    <verse value="19"> and after taking some food, he regained his strength. Saul spent several days with the disciples in Damascus. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> At once he began to preach in the synagogues that Jesus is the Son of God. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> All those who heard him were astonished and asked, "Isn't he the man who raised havoc in Jerusalem among those who call on this name? And hasn't he come here to take them as prisoners to the chief priests?" </verse>
    <verse value="22"> Yet Saul grew more and more powerful and baffled the Jews living in Damascus by proving that Jesus is the Christ. </verse>
    <verse value="23"> After many days had gone by, the Jews conspired to kill him, </verse>
    <verse value="24"> but Saul learned of their plan. Day and night they kept close watch on the city gates in order to kill him. </verse>
    <verse value="25"> But his followers took him by night and lowered him in a basket through an opening in the wall. </verse>
    <verse value="26"> When he came to Jerusalem, he tried to join the disciples, but they were all afraid of him, not believing that he really was a disciple. </verse>
    <verse value="27"> But Barnabas took him and brought him to the apostles. He told them how Saul on his journey had seen the Lord and that the Lord had spoken to him, and how in Damascus he had preached fearlessly in the name of Jesus. </verse>
    <verse value="28"> So Saul stayed with them and moved about freely in Jerusalem, speaking boldly in the name of the Lord.</verse>
    <verse value="29"> He talked and debated with the Grecian Jews, but they tried to kill him. </verse>
    <verse value="30"> When the brothers learned of this, they took him down to Caesarea and sent him off to Tarsus. </verse>
    <verse value="31"> Then the church throughout Judea, Galilee and Samaria enjoyed a time of peace. It was strengthened; and encouraged by the Holy Spirit, it grew in numbers, living in the fear of the Lord. </verse>
    <verse value="32"> As Peter traveled about the country, he went to visit the saints in Lydda. </verse>
    <verse value="33"> There he found a man named Aeneas, a paralytic who had been bedridden for eight years.</verse>
    <verse value="34"> "Aeneas," Peter said to him, "Jesus Christ heals you. Get up and take care of your mat." Immediately Aeneas got up. </verse>
    <verse value="35"> All those who lived in Lydda and Sharon saw him and turned to the Lord. </verse>
    <verse value="36"> In Joppa there was a disciple named Tabitha (which, when translated, is Dorcas), who was always doing good and helping the poor.</verse>
    <verse value="37"> About that time she became sick and died, and her body was washed and placed in an upstairs room. </verse>
    <verse value="38"> Lydda was near Joppa; so when the disciples heard that Peter was in Lydda, they sent two men to him and urged him, "Please come at once!" </verse>
    <verse value="39"> Peter went with them, and when he arrived he was taken upstairs to the room. All the widows stood around him, crying and showing him the robes and other clothing that Dorcas had made while she was still with them. </verse>
    <verse value="40"> Peter sent them all out of the room; then he got down on his knees and prayed. Turning toward the dead woman, he said, "Tabitha, get up." She opened her eyes, and seeing Peter she sat up. </verse>
    <verse value="41"> He took her by the hand and helped her to her feet. Then he called the believers and the widows and presented her to them alive.</verse>
    <verse value="42"> This became known all over Joppa, and many people believed in the Lord. </verse>
    <verse value="43"> Peter stayed in Joppa for some time with a tanner named Simon. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>