<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">It is actually reported that there is sexual immorality among you, and of a kind that does not occur even among pagans: A man has his father's wife. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> And you are proud! Shouldn't you rather have been filled with grief and have put out of your fellowship the man who did this? </verse>
    <verse value="3"> Even though I am not physically present, I am with you in spirit. And I have already passed judgment on the one who did this, just as if I were present. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> When you are assembled in the name of our Lord Jesus and I am with you in spirit, and the power of our Lord Jesus is present, </verse>
    <verse value="5"> hand this man over to Satan, so that the sinful nature may be destroyed and his spirit saved on the day of the Lord. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> Your boasting is not good. Don't you know that a little yeast works through the whole batch of dough? </verse>
    <verse value="7"> Get rid of the old yeast that you may be a new batch without yeast--as you really are. For Christ, our Passover lamb, has been sacrificed. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> Therefore let us keep the Festival, not with the old yeast, the yeast of malice and wickedness, but with bread without yeast, the bread of sincerity and truth. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> I have written you in my letter not to associate with sexually immoral people-- </verse>
    <verse value="10"> not at all meaning the people of this world who are immoral, or the greedy and swindlers, or idolaters. In that case you would have to leave this world. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> But now I am writing you that you must not associate with anyone who calls himself a brother but is sexually immoral or greedy, an idolater or a slanderer, a drunkard or a swindler. With such a man do not even eat. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> What business is it of mine to judge those outside the church? Are you not to judge those inside? </verse>
    <verse value="13"> God will judge those outside. "Expel the wicked man from among you." </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>