<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Since, then, you have been raised with Christ, set your hearts on things above, where Christ is seated at the right hand of God. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> Set your minds on things above, not on earthly things. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> For you died, and your life is now hidden with Christ in God. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> When Christ, who is your life, appears, then you also will appear with him in glory. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> Put to death, therefore, whatever belongs to your earthly nature: sexual immorality, impurity, lust, evil desires and greed, which is idolatry.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Because of these, the wrath of God is coming. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> You used to walk in these ways, in the life you once lived. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> But now you must rid yourselves of all such things as these: anger, rage, malice, slander, and filthy language from your lips. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> Do not lie to each other, since you have taken off your old self with its practices </verse>
    <verse value="10"> and have put on the new self, which is being renewed in knowledge in the image of its Creator. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> Here there is no Greek or Jew, circumcised or uncircumcised, barbarian, Scythian, slave or free, but Christ is all, and is in all. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> Therefore, as God's chosen people, holy and dearly loved, clothe yourselves with compassion, kindness, humility, gentleness and patience. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> Bear with each other and forgive whatever grievances you may have against one another. Forgive as the Lord forgave you. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> And over all these virtues put on love, which binds them all together in perfect unity. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> Let the peace of Christ rule in your hearts, since as members of one body you were called to peace. And be thankful.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly as you teach and admonish one another with all wisdom, and as you sing psalms, hymns and spiritual songs with gratitude in your hearts to God. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> And whatever you do, whether in word or deed, do it all in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> Wives, submit to your husbands, as is fitting in the Lord. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> Husbands, love your wives and do not be harsh with them.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Children, obey your parents in everything, for this pleases the Lord.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Fathers, do not embitter your children, or they will become discouraged.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Slaves, obey your earthly masters in everything; and do it, not only when their eye is on you and to win their favor, but with sincerity of heart and reverence for the Lord.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Whatever you do, work at it with all your heart, as working for the Lord, not for men,</verse>
    <verse value="24"> since you know that you will receive an inheritance from the Lord as a reward. It is the Lord Christ you are serving. </verse>
    <verse value="25"> Anyone who does wrong will be repaid for his wrong, and there is no favoritism. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>