<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Finally, brothers, we instructed you how to live in order to please God, as in fact you are living. Now we ask you and urge you in the Lord Jesus to do this more and more. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> For you know what instructions we gave you by the authority of the Lord Jesus.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> It is God's will that you should be sanctified: that you should avoid sexual immorality; </verse>
    <verse value="4"> that each of you should learn to control his own body in a way that is holy and honorable, </verse>
    <verse value="5"> not in passionate lust like the heathen, who do not know God; </verse>
    <verse value="6"> and that in this matter no one should wrong his brother or take advantage of him. The Lord will punish men for all such sins, as we have already told you and warned you. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> For God did not call us to be impure, but to live a holy life. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> Therefore, he who rejects this instruction does not reject man but God, who gives you his Holy Spirit. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> Now about brotherly love we do not need to write to you, for you yourselves have been taught by God to love each other. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> And in fact, you do love all the brothers throughout Macedonia. Yet we urge you, brothers, to do so more and more. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> Make it your ambition to lead a quiet life, to mind your own business and to work with your hands, just as we told you, </verse>
    <verse value="12"> so that your daily life may win the respect of outsiders and so that you will not be dependent on anybody. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> Brothers, we do not want you to be ignorant about those who fall asleep, or to grieve like the rest of men, who have no hope. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> We believe that Jesus died and rose again and so we believe that God will bring with Jesus those who have fallen asleep in him. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> According to the Lord's own word, we tell you that we who are still alive, who are left till the coming of the Lord, will certainly not precede those who have fallen asleep. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> For the Lord himself will come down from heaven, with a loud command, with the voice of the archangel and with the trumpet call of God, and the dead in Christ will rise first. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> After that, we who are still alive and are left will be caught up together with them in the clouds to meet the Lord in the air. And so we will be with the Lord forever. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> Therefore encourage each other with these words. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>