<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Now, brothers, about times and dates we do not need to write to you, </verse>
    <verse value="2"> for you know very well that the day of the Lord will come like a thief in the night. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> While people are saying, "Peace and safety," destruction will come on them suddenly, as labor pains on a pregnant woman, and they will not escape. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> But you, brothers, are not in darkness so that this day should surprise you like a thief. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> You are all sons of the light and sons of the day. We do not belong to the night or to the darkness. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> So then, let us not be like others, who are asleep, but let us be alert and self-controlled. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> For those who sleep, sleep at night, and those who get drunk, get drunk at night. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> But since we belong to the day, let us be self-controlled, putting on faith and love as a breastplate, and the hope of salvation as a helmet. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> For God did not appoint us to suffer wrath but to receive salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> He died for us so that, whether we are awake or asleep, we may live together with him. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> Therefore encourage one another and build each other up, just as in fact you are doing. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> Now we ask you, brothers, to respect those who work hard among you, who are over you in the Lord and who admonish you. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> Hold them in the highest regard in love because of their work. Live in peace with each other. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> And we urge you, brothers, warn those who are idle, encourage the timid, help the weak, be patient with everyone. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> Make sure that nobody pays back wrong for wrong, but always try to be kind to each other and to everyone else.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Be joyful always; </verse>
    <verse value="17"> pray continually; </verse>
    <verse value="18"> give thanks in all circumstances, for this is God's will for you in Christ Jesus. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> Do not put out the Spirit's fire; </verse>
    <verse value="20"> do not treat prophecies with contempt. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> Test everything. Hold on to the good.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Avoid every kind of evil.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> May God himself, the God of peace, sanctify you through and through. May your whole spirit, soul and body be kept blameless at the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> The one who calls you is faithful and he will do it.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> Brothers, pray for us. </verse>
    <verse value="26"> Greet all the brothers with a holy kiss. </verse>
    <verse value="27"> I charge you before the Lord to have this letter read to all the brothers. </verse>
    <verse value="28"> The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with you. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>