<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">The LORD said to Moses,</verse>
    <verse value="2"> "Send some men to explore the land of Canaan, which I am giving to the Israelites. From each ancestral tribe send one of its leaders." </verse>
    <verse value="3"> So at the LORD's command Moses sent them out from the Desert of Paran. All of them were leaders of the Israelites. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> These are their names: from the tribe of Reuben, Shammua son of Zaccur;</verse>
    <verse value="5"> from the tribe of Simeon, Shaphat son of Hori;</verse>
    <verse value="6"> from the tribe of Judah, Caleb son of Jephunneh; </verse>
    <verse value="7"> from the tribe of Issachar, Igal son of Joseph;</verse>
    <verse value="8"> from the tribe of Ephraim, Hoshea son of Nun;</verse>
    <verse value="9"> from the tribe of Benjamin, Palti son of Raphu;</verse>
    <verse value="10"> from the tribe of Zebulun, Gaddiel son of Sodi;</verse>
    <verse value="11"> from the tribe of Manasseh (a tribe of Joseph), Gaddi son of Susi;</verse>
    <verse value="12"> from the tribe of Dan, Ammiel son of Gemalli;</verse>
    <verse value="13"> from the tribe of Asher, Sethur son of Michael;</verse>
    <verse value="14"> from the tribe of Naphtali, Nahbi son of Vophsi;</verse>
    <verse value="15"> from the tribe of Gad, Geuel son of Maki.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> These are the names of the men Moses sent to explore the land. (Moses gave Hoshea son of Nun the name Joshua.) </verse>
    <verse value="17"> When Moses sent them to explore Canaan, he said, "Go up through the Negev and on into the hill country. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> See what the land is like and whether the people who live there are strong or weak, few or many.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> What kind of land do they live in? Is it good or bad? What kind of towns do they live in? Are they unwalled or fortified?</verse>
    <verse value="20"> How is the soil? Is it fertile or poor? Are there trees on it or not? Do your best to bring back some of the fruit of the land." (It was the season for the first ripe grapes.) </verse>
    <verse value="21"> So they went up and explored the land from the Desert of Zin as far as Rehob, toward Lebo Hamath. </verse>
    <verse value="22"> They went up through the Negev and came to Hebron, where Ahiman, Sheshai and Talmai, the descendants of Anak, lived. (Hebron had been built seven years before Zoan in Egypt.)</verse>
    <verse value="23"> When they reached the Valley of Eshcol, they cut off a branch bearing a single cluster of grapes. Two of them carried it on a pole between them, along with some pomegranates and figs. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> That place was called the Valley of Eshcol because of the cluster of grapes the Israelites cut off there.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> At the end of forty days they returned from exploring the land. </verse>
    <verse value="26"> They came back to Moses and Aaron and the whole Israelite community at Kadesh in the Desert of Paran. There they reported to them and to the whole assembly and showed them the fruit of the land. </verse>
    <verse value="27"> They gave Moses this account: "We went into the land to which you sent us, and it does flow with milk and honey! Here is its fruit. </verse>
    <verse value="28"> But the people who live there are powerful, and the cities are fortified and very large. We even saw descendants of Anak there. </verse>
    <verse value="29"> The Amalekites live in the Negev; the Hittites, Jebusites and Amorites live in the hill country; and the Canaanites live near the sea and along the Jordan." </verse>
    <verse value="30"> Then Caleb silenced the people before Moses and said, "We should go up and take possession of the land, for we can certainly do it." </verse>
    <verse value="31"> But the men who had gone up with him said, "We can't attack those people; they are stronger than we are." </verse>
    <verse value="32"> And they spread among the Israelites a bad report about the land they had explored. They said, "The land we explored devours those living in it. All the people we saw there are of great size.</verse>
    <verse value="33"> We saw the Nephilim there (the descendants of Anak come from the Nephilim). We seemed like grasshoppers in our own eyes, and we looked the same to them." </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>