<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">The LORD said to Moses,</verse>
    <verse value="2"> "Command the Israelites and say to them: 'When you enter Canaan, the land that will be allotted to you as an inheritance will have these boundaries:</verse>
    <verse value="3"> " 'Your southern side will include some of the Desert of Zin along the border of Edom. On the east, your southern boundary will start from the end of the Salt Sea, </verse>
    <verse value="4"> cross south of Scorpion Pass, continue on to Zin and go south of Kadesh Barnea. Then it will go to Hazar Addar and over to Azmon, </verse>
    <verse value="5"> where it will turn, join the Wadi of Egypt and end at the Sea. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> " 'Your western boundary will be the coast of the Great Sea. This will be your boundary on the west. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> " 'For your northern boundary, run a line from the Great Sea to Mount Hor </verse>
    <verse value="8"> and from Mount Hor to Lebo Hamath. Then the boundary will go to Zedad, </verse>
    <verse value="9"> continue to Ziphron and end at Hazar Enan. This will be your boundary on the north.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> " 'For your eastern boundary, run a line from Hazar Enan to Shepham. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> The boundary will go down from Shepham to Riblah on the east side of Ain and continue along the slopes east of the Sea of Kinnereth. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> Then the boundary will go down along the Jordan and end at the Salt Sea. " 'This will be your land, with its boundaries on every side.'"</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Moses commanded the Israelites: "Assign this land by lot as an inheritance. The LORD has ordered that it be given to the nine and a half tribes, </verse>
    <verse value="14"> because the families of the tribe of Reuben, the tribe of Gad and the half-tribe of Manasseh have received their inheritance. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> These two and a half tribes have received their inheritance on the east side of the Jordan of Jericho, toward the sunrise." </verse>
    <verse value="16"> The LORD said to Moses,</verse>
    <verse value="17"> "These are the names of the men who are to assign the land for you as an inheritance: Eleazar the priest and Joshua son of Nun. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> And appoint one leader from each tribe to help assign the land. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> These are their names: Caleb son of Jephunneh, from the tribe of Judah;</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Shemuel son of Ammihud, from the tribe of Simeon; </verse>
    <verse value="21"> Elidad son of Kislon, from the tribe of Benjamin; </verse>
    <verse value="22"> Bukki son of Jogli, the leader from the tribe of Dan;</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Hanniel son of Ephod, the leader from the tribe of Manasseh son of Joseph; </verse>
    <verse value="24"> Kemuel son of Shiphtan, the leader from the tribe of Ephraim son of Joseph; </verse>
    <verse value="25"> Elizaphan son of Parnach, the leader from the tribe of Zebulun; </verse>
    <verse value="26"> Paltiel son of Azzan, the leader from the tribe of Issachar;</verse>
    <verse value="27"> Ahihud son of Shelomi, the leader from the tribe of Asher;</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Pedahel son of Ammihud, the leader from the tribe of Naphtali."</verse>
    <verse value="29"> These are the men the LORD commanded to assign the inheritance to the Israelites in the land of Canaan. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>