<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">These were the sons of David born to him in Hebron: The firstborn was Amnon the son of Ahinoam of Jezreel; the second, Daniel the son of Abigail of Carmel; </verse>
    <verse value="2"> the third, Absalom the son of Maacah daughter of Talmai king of Geshur; the fourth, Adonijah the son of Haggith; </verse>
    <verse value="3"> the fifth, Shephatiah the son of Abital; and the sixth, Ithream, by his wife Eglah.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> These six were born to David in Hebron, where he reigned seven years and six months. David reigned in Jerusalem thirty-three years, </verse>
    <verse value="5"> and these were the children born to him there: Shammua, Shobab, Nathan and Solomon. These four were by Bathsheba daughter of Ammiel. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> There were also Ibhar, Elishua, Eliphelet, </verse>
    <verse value="7"> Nogah, Nepheg, Japhia,</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Elishama, Eliada and Eliphelet--nine in all.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> All these were the sons of David, besides his sons by his concubines. And Tamar was their sister.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Solomon's son was Rehoboam, Abijah his son, Asa his son, Jehoshaphat his son, </verse>
    <verse value="11"> Jehoram his son, Ahaziah his son, Joash his son, </verse>
    <verse value="12"> Amaziah his son, Azariah his son, Jotham his son, </verse>
    <verse value="13"> Ahaz his son, Hezekiah his son, Manasseh his son, </verse>
    <verse value="14"> Amon his son, Josiah his son. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> The sons of Josiah: Johanan the firstborn, Jehoiakim the second son, Zedekiah the third, Shallum the fourth. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> The successors of Jehoiakim: Jehoiachin his son, and Zedekiah.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The descendants of Jehoiachin the captive: Shealtiel his son,</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Malkiram, Pedaiah, Shenazzar, Jekamiah, Hoshama and Nedabiah.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> The sons of Pedaiah: Zerubbabel and Shimei. The sons of Zerubbabel: Meshullam and Hananiah. Shelomith was their sister. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> There were also five others: Hashubah, Ohel, Berekiah, Hasadiah and Jushab-Hesed.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> The descendants of Hananiah: Pelatiah and Jeshaiah, and the sons of Rephaiah, of Arnan, of Obadiah and of Shecaniah.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The descendants of Shecaniah: Shemaiah and his sons: Hattush, Igal, Bariah, Neariah and Shaphat--six in all. </verse>
    <verse value="23"> The sons of Neariah: Elioenai, Hizkiah and Azrikam--three in all.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> The sons of Elioenai: Hodaviah, Eliashib, Pelaiah, Akkub, Johanan, Delaiah and Anani--seven in all.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>