<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Jehoshaphat his son succeeded him as king and strengthened himself against Israel. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> He stationed troops in all the fortified cities of Judah and put garrisons in Judah and in the towns of Ephraim that his father Asa had captured. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> The LORD was with Jehoshaphat because in his early years he walked in the ways his father David had followed. He did not consult the Baals </verse>
    <verse value="4"> but sought the God of his father and followed his commands rather than the practices of Israel. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> The LORD established the kingdom under his control; and all Judah brought gifts to Jehoshaphat, so that he had great wealth and honor. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> His heart was devoted to the ways of the LORD; furthermore, he removed the high places and the Asherah poles from Judah. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> In the third year of his reign he sent his officials Ben-Hail, Obadiah, Zechariah, Nethanel and Micaiah to teach in the towns of Judah. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> With them were certain Levites--Shemaiah, Nethaniah, Zebadiah, Asahel, Shemiramoth, Jehonathan, Adonijah, Tobijah and Tob-Adonijah--and the priests Elishama and Jehoram. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> They taught throughout Judah, taking with them the Book of the Law of the LORD; they went around to all the towns of Judah and taught the people. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> The fear of the LORD fell on all the kingdoms of the lands surrounding Judah, so that they did not make war with Jehoshaphat. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> Some Philistines brought Jehoshaphat gifts and silver as tribute, and the Arabs brought him flocks: seven thousand seven hundred rams and seven thousand seven hundred goats. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> Jehoshaphat became more and more powerful; he built forts and store cities in Judah</verse>
    <verse value="13"> and had large supplies in the towns of Judah. He also kept experienced fighting men in Jerusalem.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Their enrollment by families was as follows: From Judah, commanders of units of 1,000: Adnah the commander, with 300,000 fighting men;</verse>
    <verse value="15"> next, Jehohanan the commander, with 280,000;</verse>
    <verse value="16"> next, Amasiah son of Zicri, who volunteered himself for the service of the LORD, with 200,000. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> From Benjamin: Eliada, a valiant soldier, with 200,000 men armed with bows and shields;</verse>
    <verse value="18"> next, Jehozabad, with 180,000 men armed for battle.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> These were the men who served the king, besides those he stationed in the fortified cities throughout Judah. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>