<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">After the wall had been rebuilt and I had set the doors in place, the gatekeepers and the singers and the Levites were appointed. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> I put in charge of Jerusalem my brother Hanani, along with Hananiah the commander of the citadel, because he was a man of integrity and feared God more than most men do. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> I said to them, "The gates of Jerusalem are not to be opened until the sun is hot. While the gatekeepers are still on duty, have them shut the doors and bar them. Also appoint residents of Jerusalem as guards, some at their posts and some near their own houses."</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Now the city was large and spacious, but there were few people in it, and the houses had not yet been rebuilt. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> So my God put it into my heart to assemble the nobles, the officials and the common people for registration by families. I found the genealogical record of those who had been the first to return. This is what I found written there:</verse>
    <verse value="6"> These are the people of the province who came up from the captivity of the exiles whom Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon had taken captive (they returned to Jerusalem and Judah, each to his own town, </verse>
    <verse value="7"> in company with Zerubbabel, Jeshua, Nehemiah, Azariah, Raamiah, Nahamani, Mordecai, Bilshan, Mispereth, Bigvai, Nehum and Baanah): The list of the men of Israel:</verse>
    <verse value="8"> the descendants of Parosh 2,172</verse>
    <verse value="9"> of Shephatiah 372</verse>
    <verse value="10"> of Arah 652</verse>
    <verse value="11"> of Pahath-Moab (through the line of Jeshua and Joab)%@%@%@ 2,818</verse>
    <verse value="12"> of Elam 1,254</verse>
    <verse value="13"> of Zattu 845</verse>
    <verse value="14"> of Zaccai 760</verse>
    <verse value="15"> of Binnui 648</verse>
    <verse value="16"> of Bebai 628</verse>
    <verse value="17"> of Azgad 2,322</verse>
    <verse value="18"> of Adonikam 667</verse>
    <verse value="19"> of Bigvai 2,067</verse>
    <verse value="20"> of Adin 655 </verse>
    <verse value="21"> of Ater (through Hezekiah) 98</verse>
    <verse value="22"> of Hashum 328</verse>
    <verse value="23"> of Bezai 324</verse>
    <verse value="24"> of Hariph 112</verse>
    <verse value="25"> of Gibeon 95</verse>
    <verse value="26"> the men of Bethlehem and Netophah 188 </verse>
    <verse value="27"> of Anathoth 128 </verse>
    <verse value="28"> of Beth Azmaveth 42</verse>
    <verse value="29"> of Kiriath Jearim, Kephirah and Beeroth 743 </verse>
    <verse value="30"> of Ramah and Geba 621</verse>
    <verse value="31"> of Micmash 122</verse>
    <verse value="32"> of Bethel and Ai 123 </verse>
    <verse value="33"> of the other Nebo 52</verse>
    <verse value="34"> of the other Elam 1,254</verse>
    <verse value="35"> of Harim 320</verse>
    <verse value="36"> of Jericho 345 </verse>
    <verse value="37"> of Lod, Hadid and Ono 721 </verse>
    <verse value="38"> of Senaah 3,930</verse>
    <verse value="39"> The priests: the descendants of Jedaiah (through the family of Jeshua)%@%@ 973</verse>
    <verse value="40"> of Immer 1,052</verse>
    <verse value="41"> of Pashhur 1,247</verse>
    <verse value="42"> of Harim 1,017</verse>
    <verse value="43"> The Levites: the descendants of Jeshua (through Kadmiel through the line of Hodaviah)%@%@ 74</verse>
    <verse value="44"> The singers: the descendants of Asaph 148</verse>
    <verse value="45"> The gatekeepers: the descendants of Shallum, Ater, Talmon, Akkub, Hatita and Shobai%@%@ 138</verse>
    <verse value="46"> The temple servants: the descendants of Ziha, Hasupha, Tabbaoth,</verse>
    <verse value="47"> Keros, Sia, Padon,</verse>
    <verse value="48"> Lebana, Hagaba, Shalmai,</verse>
    <verse value="49"> Hanan, Giddel, Gahar,</verse>
    <verse value="50"> Reaiah, Rezin, Nekoda,</verse>
    <verse value="51"> Gazzam, Uzza, Paseah,</verse>
    <verse value="52"> Besai, Meunim, Nephusim,</verse>
    <verse value="53"> Bakbuk, Hakupha, Harhur,</verse>
    <verse value="54"> Bazluth, Mehida, Harsha,</verse>
    <verse value="55"> Barkos, Sisera, Temah,</verse>
    <verse value="56"> Neziah and Hatipha</verse>
    <verse value="57"> The descendants of the servants of Solomon: the descendants of Sotai, Sophereth, Perida,</verse>
    <verse value="58"> Jaala, Darkon, Giddel,</verse>
    <verse value="59"> Shephatiah, Hattil, Pokereth-Hazzebaim and Amon</verse>
    <verse value="60"> The temple servants and the descendants of the servants of Solomon%@%@%@ 392</verse>
    <verse value="61"> The following came up from the towns of Tel Melah, Tel Harsha, Kerub, Addon and Immer, but they could not show that their families were descended from Israel:</verse>
    <verse value="62"> the descendants of Delaiah, Tobiah and Nekoda 642</verse>
    <verse value="63"> And from among the priests: the descendants of Hobaiah, Hakkoz and Barzillai (a man who had married a daughter of Barzillai the Gileadite and was called by that name).</verse>
    <verse value="64"> These searched for their family records, but they could not find them and so were excluded from the priesthood as unclean.</verse>
    <verse value="65"> The governor, therefore, ordered them not to eat any of the most sacred food until there should be a priest ministering with the Urim and Thummim.</verse>
    <verse value="66"> The whole company numbered 42,360,</verse>
    <verse value="67"> besides their 7,337 menservants and maidservants; and they also had 245 men and women singers.</verse>
    <verse value="68"> There were 736 horses, 245 mules, </verse>
    <verse value="69"> 435 camels and 6,720 donkeys.</verse>
    <verse value="70"> Some of the heads of the families contributed to the work. The governor gave to the treasury 1,000 drachmas of gold, 50 bowls and 530 garments for priests. </verse>
    <verse value="71"> Some of the heads of the families gave to the treasury for the work 20,000 drachmas of gold and 2,200 minas of silver. </verse>
    <verse value="72"> The total given by the rest of the people was 20,000 drachmas of gold, 2,000 minas of silver and 67 garments for priests. </verse>
    <verse value="73"> The priests, the Levites, the gatekeepers, the singers and the temple servants, along with certain of the people and the rest of the Israelites, settled in their own towns. When the seventh month came and the Israelites had settled in their towns,</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>