<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Then Job replied:</verse>
    <verse value="2"> "Doubtless you are the people, and wisdom will die with you! </verse>
    <verse value="3"> But I have a mind as well as you; I am not inferior to you. Who does not know all these things?</verse>
    <verse value="4"> "I have become a laughingstock to my friends, though I called upon God and he answered-- a mere laughingstock, though righteous and blameless! </verse>
    <verse value="5"> Men at ease have contempt for misfortune as the fate of those whose feet are slipping. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> The tents of marauders are undisturbed, and those who provoke God are secure-- those who carry their god in their hands.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> "But ask the animals, and they will teach you, or the birds of the air, and they will tell you; </verse>
    <verse value="8"> or speak to the earth, and it will teach you, or let the fish of the sea inform you.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Which of all these does not know that the hand of the LORD has done this? </verse>
    <verse value="10"> In his hand is the life of every creature and the breath of all mankind.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Does not the ear test words as the tongue tastes food? </verse>
    <verse value="12"> Is not wisdom found among the aged? Does not long life bring understanding?</verse>
    <verse value="13"> "To God belong wisdom and power; counsel and understanding are his. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> What he tears down cannot be rebuilt; the man he imprisons cannot be released. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> If he holds back the waters, there is drought; if he lets them loose, they devastate the land.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> To him belong strength and victory; both deceived and deceiver are his. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> He leads counselors away stripped and makes fools of judges. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> He takes off the shackles put on by kings and ties a loincloth around their waist. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> He leads priests away stripped and overthrows men long established. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> He silences the lips of trusted advisers and takes away the discernment of elders. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> He pours contempt on nobles and disarms the mighty. </verse>
    <verse value="22"> He reveals the deep things of darkness and brings deep shadows into the light. </verse>
    <verse value="23"> He makes nations great, and destroys them; he enlarges nations, and disperses them. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> He deprives the leaders of the earth of their reason; he sends them wandering through a trackless waste. </verse>
    <verse value="25"> They grope in darkness with no light; he makes them stagger like drunkards.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>