<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">"At this my heart pounds and leaps from its place. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> Listen! Listen to the roar of his voice, to the rumbling that comes from his mouth.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> He unleashes his lightning beneath the whole heaven and sends it to the ends of the earth. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> After that comes the sound of his roar; he thunders with his majestic voice. When his voice resounds, he holds nothing back. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> God's voice thunders in marvelous ways; he does great things beyond our understanding. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> He says to the snow, 'Fall on the earth,' and to the rain shower, 'Be a mighty downpour.' </verse>
    <verse value="7"> So that all men he has made may know his work, he stops every man from his labor. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> The animals take cover; they remain in their dens. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> The tempest comes out from its chamber, the cold from the driving winds. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> The breath of God produces ice, and the broad waters become frozen. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> He loads the clouds with moisture; he scatters his lightning through them. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> At his direction they swirl around over the face of the whole earth to do whatever he commands them. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> He brings the clouds to punish men, or to water his earth and show his love.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> "Listen to this, Job; stop and consider God's wonders. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> Do you know how God controls the clouds and makes his lightning flash? </verse>
    <verse value="16"> Do you know how the clouds hang poised, those wonders of him who is perfect in knowledge? </verse>
    <verse value="17"> You who swelter in your clothes when the land lies hushed under the south wind, </verse>
    <verse value="18"> can you join him in spreading out the skies, hard as a mirror of cast bronze?</verse>
    <verse value="19"> "Tell us what we should say to him; we cannot draw up our case because of our darkness. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> Should he be told that I want to speak? Would any man ask to be swallowed up?</verse>
    <verse value="21"> Now no one can look at the sun, bright as it is in the skies after the wind has swept them clean.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Out of the north he comes in golden splendor; God comes in awesome majesty. </verse>
    <verse value="23"> The Almighty is beyond our reach and exalted in power; in his justice and great righteousness, he does not oppress. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> Therefore, men revere him, for does he not have regard for all the wise in heart? " </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>