<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Then the LORD answered Job out of the storm. He said: </verse>
    <verse value="2"> "Who is this that darkens my counsel with words without knowledge? </verse>
    <verse value="3"> Brace yourself like a man; I will question you, and you shall answer me.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> "Where were you when I laid the earth's foundation? Tell me, if you understand. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> Who marked off its dimensions? Surely you know! Who stretched a measuring line across it? </verse>
    <verse value="6"> On what were its footings set, or who laid its cornerstone-- </verse>
    <verse value="7"> while the morning stars sang together and all the angels shouted for joy?</verse>
    <verse value="8"> "Who shut up the sea behind doors when it burst forth from the womb, </verse>
    <verse value="9"> when I made the clouds its garment and wrapped it in thick darkness, </verse>
    <verse value="10"> when I fixed limits for it and set its doors and bars in place, </verse>
    <verse value="11"> when I said, 'This far you may come and no farther; here is where your proud waves halt'?</verse>
    <verse value="12"> "Have you ever given orders to the morning, or shown the dawn its place, </verse>
    <verse value="13"> that it might take the earth by the edges and shake the wicked out of it? </verse>
    <verse value="14"> The earth takes shape like clay under a seal; its features stand out like those of a garment. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> The wicked are denied their light, and their upraised arm is broken.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> "Have you journeyed to the springs of the sea or walked in the recesses of the deep? </verse>
    <verse value="17"> Have the gates of death been shown to you? Have you seen the gates of the shadow of death?</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Have you comprehended the vast expanses of the earth? Tell me, if you know all this.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> "What is the way to the abode of light? And where does darkness reside? </verse>
    <verse value="20"> Can you take them to their places? Do you know the paths to their dwellings? </verse>
    <verse value="21"> Surely you know, for you were already born! You have lived so many years!</verse>
    <verse value="22"> "Have you entered the storehouses of the snow or seen the storehouses of the hail,</verse>
    <verse value="23"> which I reserve for times of trouble, for days of war and battle? </verse>
    <verse value="24"> What is the way to the place where the lightning is dispersed, or the place where the east winds are scattered over the earth? </verse>
    <verse value="25"> Who cuts a channel for the torrents of rain, and a path for the thunderstorm, </verse>
    <verse value="26"> to water a land where no man lives, a desert with no one in it, </verse>
    <verse value="27"> to satisfy a desolate wasteland and make it sprout with grass?</verse>
    <verse value="28"> Does the rain have a father? Who fathers the drops of dew? </verse>
    <verse value="29"> From whose womb comes the ice? Who gives birth to the frost from the heavens</verse>
    <verse value="30"> when the waters become hard as stone, when the surface of the deep is frozen?</verse>
    <verse value="31"> "Can you bind the beautiful Pleiades? Can you loose the cords of Orion? </verse>
    <verse value="32"> Can you bring forth the constellations in their seasons or lead out the Bear with its cubs? </verse>
    <verse value="33"> Do you know the laws of the heavens? Can you set up [God's] dominion over the earth?</verse>
    <verse value="34"> "Can you raise your voice to the clouds and cover yourself with a flood of water? </verse>
    <verse value="35"> Do you send the lightning bolts on their way? Do they report to you, 'Here we are'?</verse>
    <verse value="36"> Who endowed the heart with wisdom or gave understanding to the mind?</verse>
    <verse value="37"> Who has the wisdom to count the clouds? Who can tip over the water jars of the heavens </verse>
    <verse value="38"> when the dust becomes hard and the clods of earth stick together?</verse>
    <verse value="39"> "Do you hunt the prey for the lioness and satisfy the hunger of the lions </verse>
    <verse value="40"> when they crouch in their dens or lie in wait in a thicket? </verse>
    <verse value="41"> Who provides food for the raven when its young cry out to God and wander about for lack of food?</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>