<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">The LORD said to Job:</verse>
    <verse value="2"> "Will the one who contends with the Almighty correct him? Let him who accuses God answer him!" </verse>
    <verse value="3"> Then Job answered the LORD:</verse>
    <verse value="4"> "I am unworthy--how can I reply to you? I put my hand over my mouth. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> I spoke once, but I have no answer-- twice, but I will say no more." </verse>
    <verse value="6"> Then the LORD spoke to Job out of the storm: </verse>
    <verse value="7"> "Brace yourself like a man; I will question you, and you shall answer me.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> "Would you discredit my justice? Would you condemn me to justify yourself?</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Do you have an arm like God's, and can your voice thunder like his? </verse>
    <verse value="10"> Then adorn yourself with glory and splendor, and clothe yourself in honor and majesty. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> Unleash the fury of your wrath, look at every proud man and bring him low, </verse>
    <verse value="12"> look at every proud man and humble him, crush the wicked where they stand. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> Bury them all in the dust together; shroud their faces in the grave. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> Then I myself will admit to you that your own right hand can save you.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> "Look at the behemoth, which I made along with you and which feeds on grass like an ox. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> What strength he has in his loins, what power in the muscles of his belly! </verse>
    <verse value="17"> His tail sways like a cedar; the sinews of his thighs are close-knit. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> His bones are tubes of bronze, his limbs like rods of iron. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> He ranks first among the works of God, yet his Maker can approach him with his sword. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> The hills bring him their produce, and all the wild animals play nearby. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> Under the lotus plants he lies, hidden among the reeds in the marsh. </verse>
    <verse value="22"> The lotuses conceal him in their shadow; the poplars by the stream surround him. </verse>
    <verse value="23"> When the river rages, he is not alarmed; he is secure, though the Jordan should surge against his mouth. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> Can anyone capture him by the eyes, or trap him and pierce his nose?</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>