<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For the director of music. Of David the servant of the LORD. He sang to the LORD the words of this song when the LORD delivered him from the hand of all his enemies and from the hand of Saul. He said: I love you, O LORD, my strength.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> The LORD is my rock, my fortress and my deliverer; my God is my rock, in whom I take refuge. He is my shield and the horn of my salvation, my stronghold. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> I call to the LORD, who is worthy of praise, and I am saved from my enemies.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> The cords of death entangled me; the torrents of destruction overwhelmed me.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> The cords of the grave coiled around me; the snares of death confronted me.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> In my distress I called to the LORD; I cried to my God for help. From his temple he heard my voice; my cry came before him, into his ears.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> The earth trembled and quaked, and the foundations of the mountains shook; they trembled because he was angry. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> Smoke rose from his nostrils; consuming fire came from his mouth, burning coals blazed out of it. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> He parted the heavens and came down; dark clouds were under his feet. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> He mounted the cherubim and flew; he soared on the wings of the wind. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> He made darkness his covering, his canopy around him-- the dark rain clouds of the sky. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> Out of the brightness of his presence clouds advanced, with hailstones and bolts of lightning.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> The LORD thundered from heaven; the voice of the Most High resounded. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> He shot his arrows and scattered [the enemies], great bolts of lightning and routed them.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The valleys of the sea were exposed and the foundations of the earth laid bare at your rebuke, O LORD, at the blast of breath from your nostrils.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> He reached down from on high and took hold of me; he drew me out of deep waters. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> He rescued me from my powerful enemy, from my foes, who were too strong for me.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> They confronted me in the day of my disaster, but the LORD was my support. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> He brought me out into a spacious place; he rescued me because he delighted in me.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> The LORD has dealt with me according to my righteousness; according to the cleanness of my hands he has rewarded me. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> For I have kept the ways of the LORD; I have not done evil by turning from my God. </verse>
    <verse value="22"> All his laws are before me; I have not turned away from his decrees. </verse>
    <verse value="23"> I have been blameless before him and have kept myself from sin. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> The LORD has rewarded me according to my righteousness, according to the cleanness of my hands in his sight.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> To the faithful you show yourself faithful, to the blameless you show yourself blameless, </verse>
    <verse value="26"> to the pure you show yourself pure, but to the crooked you show yourself shrewd. </verse>
    <verse value="27"> You save the humble but bring low those whose eyes are haughty. </verse>
    <verse value="28"> You, O LORD, keep my lamp burning; my God turns my darkness into light. </verse>
    <verse value="29"> With your help I can advance against a troop; with my God I can scale a wall.</verse>
    <verse value="30"> As for God, his way is perfect; the word of the LORD is flawless. He is a shield for all who take refuge in him. </verse>
    <verse value="31"> For who is God besides the LORD? And who is the Rock except our God? </verse>
    <verse value="32"> It is God who arms me with strength and makes my way perfect. </verse>
    <verse value="33"> He makes my feet like the feet of a deer; he enables me to stand on the heights. </verse>
    <verse value="34"> He trains my hands for battle; my arms can bend a bow of bronze. </verse>
    <verse value="35"> You give me your shield of victory, and your right hand sustains me; you stoop down to make me great. </verse>
    <verse value="36"> You broaden the path beneath me, so that my ankles do not turn.</verse>
    <verse value="37"> I pursued my enemies and overtook them; I did not turn back till they were destroyed. </verse>
    <verse value="38"> I crushed them so that they could not rise; they fell beneath my feet. </verse>
    <verse value="39"> You armed me with strength for battle; you made my adversaries bow at my feet. </verse>
    <verse value="40"> You made my enemies turn their backs in flight, and I destroyed my foes. </verse>
    <verse value="41"> They cried for help, but there was no one to save them-- to the LORD, but he did not answer. </verse>
    <verse value="42"> I beat them as fine as dust borne on the wind; I poured them out like mud in the streets.</verse>
    <verse value="43"> You have delivered me from the attacks of the people; you have made me the head of nations; people I did not know are subject to me. </verse>
    <verse value="44"> As soon as they hear me, they obey me; foreigners cringe before me. </verse>
    <verse value="45"> They all lose heart; they come trembling from their strongholds.</verse>
    <verse value="46"> The LORD lives! Praise be to my Rock! Exalted be God my Savior!</verse>
    <verse value="47"> He is the God who avenges me, who subdues nations under me, </verse>
    <verse value="48"> who saves me from my enemies. You exalted me above my foes; from violent men you rescued me. </verse>
    <verse value="49"> Therefore I will praise you among the nations, O LORD; I will sing praises to your name. </verse>
    <verse value="50"> He gives his king great victories; he shows unfailing kindness to his anointed, to David and his descendants forever. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>