<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For the director of music. Of the Sons of Korah. A [maskil.] We have heard with our ears, O God; our fathers have told us what you did in their days, in days long ago. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> With your hand you drove out the nations and planted our fathers; you crushed the peoples and made our fathers flourish. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> It was not by their sword that they won the land, nor did their arm bring them victory; it was your right hand, your arm, and the light of your face, for you loved them.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> You are my King and my God, who decrees victories for Jacob. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> Through you we push back our enemies; through your name we trample our foes. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> I do not trust in my bow, my sword does not bring me victory; </verse>
    <verse value="7"> but you give us victory over our enemies, you put our adversaries to shame.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> In God we make our boast all day long, and we will praise your name forever. [Selah]</verse>
    <verse value="9"> But now you have rejected and humbled us; you no longer go out with our armies. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> You made us retreat before the enemy, and our adversaries have plundered us.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> You gave us up to be devoured like sheep and have scattered us among the nations. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> You sold your people for a pittance, gaining nothing from their sale.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> You have made us a reproach to our neighbors, the scorn and derision of those around us. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> You have made us a byword among the nations; the peoples shake their heads at us. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> My disgrace is before me all day long, and my face is covered with shame </verse>
    <verse value="16"> at the taunts of those who reproach and revile me, because of the enemy, who is bent on revenge.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> All this happened to us, though we had not forgotten you or been false to your covenant. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> Our hearts had not turned back; our feet had not strayed from your path. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> But you crushed us and made us a haunt for jackals and covered us over with deep darkness.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> If we had forgotten the name of our God or spread out our hands to a foreign god, </verse>
    <verse value="21"> would not God have discovered it, since he knows the secrets of the heart? </verse>
    <verse value="22"> Yet for your sake we face death all day long; we are considered as sheep to be slaughtered.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Awake, O Lord! Why do you sleep? Rouse yourself! Do not reject us forever.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> Why do you hide your face and forget our misery and oppression?</verse>
    <verse value="25"> We are brought down to the dust; our bodies cling to the ground. </verse>
    <verse value="26"> Rise up and help us; redeem us because of your unfailing love. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>