<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Of Solomon. Endow the king with your justice, O God, the royal son with your righteousness. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> He will judge your people in righteousness, your afflicted ones with justice. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> The mountains will bring prosperity to the people, the hills the fruit of righteousness.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> He will defend the afflicted among the people and save the children of the needy; he will crush the oppressor.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> He will endure as long as the sun, as long as the moon, through all generations. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> He will be like rain falling on a mown field, like showers watering the earth. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> In his days the righteous will flourish; prosperity will abound till the moon is no more.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> He will rule from sea to sea and from the River to the ends of the earth. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> The desert tribes will bow before him and his enemies will lick the dust.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The kings of Tarshish and of distant shores will bring tribute to him; the kings of Sheba and Seba will present him gifts. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> All kings will bow down to him and all nations will serve him.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> For he will deliver the needy who cry out, the afflicted who have no one to help.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> He will take pity on the weak and the needy and save the needy from death. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> He will rescue them from oppression and violence, for precious is their blood in his sight.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Long may he live! May gold from Sheba be given him. May people ever pray for him and bless him all day long. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> Let grain abound throughout the land; on the tops of the hills may it sway. Let its fruit flourish like Lebanon; let it thrive like the grass of the field. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> May his name endure forever; may it continue as long as the sun. All nations will be blessed through him, and they will call him blessed.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Praise be to the LORD God, the God of Israel, who alone does marvelous deeds. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> Praise be to his glorious name forever; may the whole earth be filled with his glory. Amen and Amen.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> This concludes the prayers of David son of Jesse. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>