<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For the director of music. For Jeduthun. Of Asaph. A psalm. I cried out to God for help; I cried out to God to hear me. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> When I was in distress, I sought the Lord; at night I stretched out untiring hands and my soul refused to be comforted.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> I remembered you, O God, and I groaned; I mused, and my spirit grew faint. [Selah] </verse>
    <verse value="4"> You kept my eyes from closing; I was too troubled to speak. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> I thought about the former days, the years of long ago; </verse>
    <verse value="6"> I remembered my songs in the night. My heart mused and my spirit inquired:</verse>
    <verse value="7"> "Will the Lord reject forever? Will he never show his favor again? </verse>
    <verse value="8"> Has his unfailing love vanished forever? Has his promise failed for all time? </verse>
    <verse value="9"> Has God forgotten to be merciful? Has he in anger withheld his compassion?" [Selah]</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Then I thought, "To this I will appeal: the years of the right hand of the Most High." </verse>
    <verse value="11"> I will remember the deeds of the LORD; yes, I will remember your miracles of long ago. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> I will meditate on all your works and consider all your mighty deeds.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Your ways, O God, are holy. What god is so great as our God? </verse>
    <verse value="14"> You are the God who performs miracles; you display your power among the peoples. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> With your mighty arm you redeemed your people, the descendants of Jacob and Joseph. [Selah]</verse>
    <verse value="16"> The waters saw you, O God, the waters saw you and writhed; the very depths were convulsed.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The clouds poured down water, the skies resounded with thunder; your arrows flashed back and forth. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> Your thunder was heard in the whirlwind, your lightning lit up the world; the earth trembled and quaked. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> Your path led through the sea, your way through the mighty waters, though your footprints were not seen.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> You led your people like a flock by the hand of Moses and Aaron. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>