<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For the director of music. To [the tune of] "The Lilies of the Covenant." Of Asaph. A psalm. Hear us, O Shepherd of Israel, you who lead Joseph like a flock; you who sit enthroned between the cherubim, shine forth </verse>
    <verse value="2"> before Ephraim, Benjamin and Manasseh. Awaken your might; come and save us.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Restore us, O God; make your face shine upon us, that we may be saved.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> O LORD God Almighty, how long will your anger smolder against the prayers of your people?</verse>
    <verse value="5"> You have fed them with the bread of tears; you have made them drink tears by the bowlful.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> You have made us a source of contention to our neighbors, and our enemies mock us.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Restore us, O God Almighty; make your face shine upon us, that we may be saved.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> You brought a vine out of Egypt; you drove out the nations and planted it. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> You cleared the ground for it, and it took root and filled the land.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The mountains were covered with its shade, the mighty cedars with its branches.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> It sent out its boughs to the Sea, its shoots as far as the River.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Why have you broken down its walls so that all who pass by pick its grapes? </verse>
    <verse value="13"> Boars from the forest ravage it and the creatures of the field feed on it.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Return to us, O God Almighty! Look down from heaven and see! Watch over this vine,</verse>
    <verse value="15"> the root your right hand has planted, the son you have raised up for yourself.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Your vine is cut down, it is burned with fire; at your rebuke your people perish.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Let your hand rest on the man at your right hand, the son of man you have raised up for yourself. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> Then we will not turn away from you; revive us, and we will call on your name.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Restore us, O LORD God Almighty; make your face shine upon us, that we may be saved.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>