<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">A song. A psalm of Asaph. O God, do not keep silent; be not quiet, O God, be not still. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> See how your enemies are astir, how your foes rear their heads.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> With cunning they conspire against your people; they plot against those you cherish.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> "Come," they say, "let us destroy them as a nation, that the name of Israel be remembered no more."</verse>
    <verse value="5"> With one mind they plot together; they form an alliance against you-- </verse>
    <verse value="6"> the tents of Edom and the Ishmaelites, of Moab and the Hagrites, </verse>
    <verse value="7"> Gebal, Ammon and Amalek, Philistia, with the people of Tyre. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> Even Assyria has joined them to lend strength to the descendants of Lot. [Selah]</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Do to them as you did to Midian, as you did to Sisera and Jabin at the river Kishon, </verse>
    <verse value="10"> who perished at Endor and became like refuse on the ground. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> Make their nobles like Oreb and Zeeb, all their princes like Zebah and Zalmunna, </verse>
    <verse value="12"> who said, "Let us take possession of the pasturelands of God."</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Make them like tumbleweed, O my God, like chaff before the wind. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> As fire consumes the forest or a flame sets the mountains ablaze, </verse>
    <verse value="15"> so pursue them with your tempest and terrify them with your storm. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> Cover their faces with shame so that men will seek your name, O LORD.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> May they ever be ashamed and dismayed; may they perish in disgrace.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Let them know that you, whose name is the LORD-- that you alone are the Most High over all the earth. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>