<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Of David. Praise the LORD, O my soul; all my inmost being, praise his holy name. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> Praise the LORD, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits-- </verse>
    <verse value="3"> who forgives all your sins and heals all your diseases, </verse>
    <verse value="4"> who redeems your life from the pit and crowns you with love and compassion, </verse>
    <verse value="5"> who satisfies your desires with good things so that your youth is renewed like the eagle's.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> The LORD works righteousness and justice for all the oppressed.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> He made known his ways to Moses, his deeds to the people of Israel: </verse>
    <verse value="8"> The LORD is compassionate and gracious, slow to anger, abounding in love. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> He will not always accuse, nor will he harbor his anger forever; </verse>
    <verse value="10"> he does not treat us as our sins deserve or repay us according to our iniquities. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> For as high as the heavens are above the earth, so great is his love for those who fear him;</verse>
    <verse value="12"> as far as the east is from the west, so far has he removed our transgressions from us. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> As a father has compassion on his children, so the LORD has compassion on those who fear him; </verse>
    <verse value="14"> for he knows how we are formed, he remembers that we are dust. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> As for man, his days are like grass, he flourishes like a flower of the field; </verse>
    <verse value="16"> the wind blows over it and it is gone, and its place remembers it no more. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> But from everlasting to everlasting the LORD's love is with those who fear him, and his righteousness with their children's children--</verse>
    <verse value="18"> with those who keep his covenant and remember to obey his precepts.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> The LORD has established his throne in heaven, and his kingdom rules over all.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Praise the LORD, you his angels, you mighty ones who do his bidding, who obey his word. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> Praise the LORD, all his heavenly hosts, you his servants who do his will. </verse>
    <verse value="22"> Praise the LORD, all his works everywhere in his dominion. Praise the LORD, O my soul.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>