<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For the director of music. Of David. A psalm. O God, whom I praise, do not remain silent, </verse>
    <verse value="2"> for wicked and deceitful men have opened their mouths against me; they have spoken against me with lying tongues. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> With words of hatred they surround me; they attack me without cause. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> In return for my friendship they accuse me, but I am a man of prayer. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> They repay me evil for good, and hatred for my friendship.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Appoint an evil man to oppose him; let an accuser stand at his right hand. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> When he is tried, let him be found guilty, and may his prayers condemn him. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> May his days be few; may another take his place of leadership. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> May his children be fatherless and his wife a widow. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> May his children be wandering beggars; may they be driven from their ruined homes. </verse>
    <verse value="11"> May a creditor seize all he has; may strangers plunder the fruits of his labor.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> May no one extend kindness to him or take pity on his fatherless children. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> May his descendants be cut off, their names blotted out from the next generation.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> May the iniquity of his fathers be remembered before the LORD; may the sin of his mother never be blotted out.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> May their sins always remain before the LORD, that he may cut off the memory of them from the earth.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> For he never thought of doing a kindness, but hounded to death the poor and the needy and the brokenhearted.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> He loved to pronounce a curse-- may it come on him; he found no pleasure in blessing-- may it be far from him.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> He wore cursing as his garment; it entered into his body like water, into his bones like oil. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> May it be like a cloak wrapped about him, like a belt tied forever around him. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> May this be the LORD's payment to my accusers, to those who speak evil of me.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> But you, O Sovereign LORD, deal well with me for your name's sake; out of the goodness of your love, deliver me.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> For I am poor and needy, and my heart is wounded within me.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> I fade away like an evening shadow; I am shaken off like a locust. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> My knees give way from fasting; my body is thin and gaunt. </verse>
    <verse value="25"> I am an object of scorn to my accusers; when they see me, they shake their heads.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> Help me, O LORD my God; save me in accordance with your love. </verse>
    <verse value="27"> Let them know that it is your hand, that you, O LORD, have done it. </verse>
    <verse value="28"> They may curse, but you will bless; when they attack they will be put to shame, but your servant will rejoice.</verse>
    <verse value="29"> My accusers will be clothed with disgrace and wrapped in shame as in a cloak.</verse>
    <verse value="30"> With my mouth I will greatly extol the LORD; in the great throng I will praise him. </verse>
    <verse value="31"> For he stands at the right hand of the needy one, to save his life from those who condemn him. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>