<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Give thanks to the LORD, for he is good; his love endures forever.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> Let Israel say: "His love endures forever." </verse>
    <verse value="3"> Let the house of Aaron say: "His love endures forever." </verse>
    <verse value="4"> Let those who fear the LORD say: "His love endures forever."</verse>
    <verse value="5"> In my anguish I cried to the LORD, and he answered by setting me free. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> The LORD is with me; I will not be afraid. What can man do to me? </verse>
    <verse value="7"> The LORD is with me; he is my helper. I will look in triumph on my enemies.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> It is better to take refuge in the LORD than to trust in man. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> It is better to take refuge in the LORD than to trust in princes.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> All the nations surrounded me, but in the name of the LORD I cut them off.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> They surrounded me on every side, but in the name of the LORD I cut them off. </verse>
    <verse value="12"> They swarmed around me like bees, but they died out as quickly as burning thorns; in the name of the LORD I cut them off.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> I was pushed back and about to fall, but the LORD helped me. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> The LORD is my strength and my song; he has become my salvation.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> Shouts of joy and victory resound in the tents of the righteous: "The LORD's right hand has done mighty things! </verse>
    <verse value="16"> The LORD's right hand is lifted high; the LORD's right hand has done mighty things!"</verse>
    <verse value="17"> I will not die but live, and will proclaim what the LORD has done. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> The LORD has chastened me severely, but he has not given me over to death.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Open for me the gates of righteousness; I will enter and give thanks to the LORD. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> This is the gate of the LORD through which the righteous may enter. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> I will give you thanks, for you answered me; you have become my salvation.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> The stone the builders rejected has become the capstone; </verse>
    <verse value="23"> the LORD has done this, and it is marvelous in our eyes. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> This is the day the LORD has made; let us rejoice and be glad in it.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> O LORD, save us; O LORD, grant us success. </verse>
    <verse value="26"> Blessed is he who comes in the name of the LORD. From the house of the LORD we bless you. </verse>
    <verse value="27"> The LORD is God, and he has made his light shine upon us. With boughs in hand, join in the festal procession up to the horns of the altar.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> You are my God, and I will give you thanks; you are my God, and I will exalt you.</verse>
    <verse value="29"> Give thanks to the LORD, for he is good; his love endures forever.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>