<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">For the director of music. Of David. A psalm. O LORD, you have searched me and you know me. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> You know when I sit and when I rise; you perceive my thoughts from afar. </verse>
    <verse value="3"> You discern my going out and my lying down; you are familiar with all my ways. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> Before a word is on my tongue you know it completely, O LORD.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> You hem me in--behind and before; you have laid your hand upon me. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> Such knowledge is too wonderful for me, too lofty for me to attain.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Where can I go from your Spirit? Where can I flee from your presence? </verse>
    <verse value="8"> If I go up to the heavens, you are there; if I make my bed in the depths, you are there.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> If I rise on the wings of the dawn, if I settle on the far side of the sea,</verse>
    <verse value="10"> even there your hand will guide me, your right hand will hold me fast.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> If I say, "Surely the darkness will hide me and the light become night around me,"</verse>
    <verse value="12"> even the darkness will not be dark to you; the night will shine like the day, for darkness is as light to you.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> For you created my inmost being; you knit me together in my mother's womb.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> I praise you because I am fearfully and wonderfully made; your works are wonderful, I know that full well. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> My frame was not hidden from you when I was made in the secret place. When I was woven together in the depths of the earth, </verse>
    <verse value="16"> your eyes saw my unformed body. All the days ordained for me were written in your book before one of them came to be.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> How precious to me are your thoughts, O God! How vast is the sum of them! </verse>
    <verse value="18"> Were I to count them, they would outnumber the grains of sand. When I awake, I am still with you.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> If only you would slay the wicked, O God! Away from me, you bloodthirsty men! </verse>
    <verse value="20"> They speak of you with evil intent; your adversaries misuse your name. </verse>
    <verse value="21"> Do I not hate those who hate you, O LORD, and abhor those who rise up against you? </verse>
    <verse value="22"> I have nothing but hatred for them; I count them my enemies.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> Search me, O God, and know my heart; test me and know my anxious thoughts. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> See if there is any offensive way in me, and lead me in the way everlasting. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>