<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1"> A psalm of praise. Of David. I will exalt you, my God the King; I will praise your name for ever and ever. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> Every day I will praise you and extol your name for ever and ever.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Great is the LORD and most worthy of praise; his greatness no one can fathom. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> One generation will commend your works to another; they will tell of your mighty acts. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> They will speak of the glorious splendor of your majesty, and I will meditate on your wonderful works. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> They will tell of the power of your awesome works, and I will proclaim your great deeds. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> They will celebrate your abundant goodness and joyfully sing of your righteousness.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> The LORD is gracious and compassionate, slow to anger and rich in love. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> The LORD is good to all; he has compassion on all he has made. </verse>
    <verse value="10"> All you have made will praise you, O LORD; your saints will extol you.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> They will tell of the glory of your kingdom and speak of your might,</verse>
    <verse value="12"> so that all men may know of your mighty acts and the glorious splendor of your kingdom.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Your kingdom is an everlasting kingdom, and your dominion endures through all generations. The LORD is faithful to all his promises and loving toward all he has made.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The LORD upholds all those who fall and lifts up all who are bowed down. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> The eyes of all look to you, and you give them their food at the proper time. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> You open your hand and satisfy the desires of every living thing.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The LORD is righteous in all his ways and loving toward all he has made. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> The LORD is near to all who call on him, to all who call on him in truth. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> He fulfills the desires of those who fear him; he hears their cry and saves them. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> The LORD watches over all who love him, but all the wicked he will destroy.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> My mouth will speak in praise of the LORD. Let every creature praise his holy name for ever and ever. </verse>
  </content>
</chapter>