<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">Does not wisdom call out? Does not understanding raise her voice? </verse>
    <verse value="2"> On the heights along the way, where the paths meet, she takes her stand;</verse>
    <verse value="3"> beside the gates leading into the city, at the entrances, she cries aloud:</verse>
    <verse value="4"> "To you, O men, I call out; I raise my voice to all mankind. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> You who are simple, gain prudence; you who are foolish, gain understanding.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Listen, for I have worthy things to say; I open my lips to speak what is right.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> My mouth speaks what is true, for my lips detest wickedness. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> All the words of my mouth are just; none of them is crooked or perverse.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> To the discerning all of them are right; they are faultless to those who have knowledge.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Choose my instruction instead of silver, knowledge rather than choice gold, </verse>
    <verse value="11"> for wisdom is more precious than rubies, and nothing you desire can compare with her.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> "I, wisdom, dwell together with prudence; I possess knowledge and discretion. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> To fear the LORD is to hate evil; I hate pride and arrogance, evil behavior and perverse speech. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> Counsel and sound judgment are mine; I have understanding and power. </verse>
    <verse value="15"> By me kings reign and rulers make laws that are just; </verse>
    <verse value="16"> by me princes govern, and all nobles who rule on earth. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> I love those who love me, and those who seek me find me. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> With me are riches and honor, enduring wealth and prosperity. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> My fruit is better than fine gold; what I yield surpasses choice silver. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> I walk in the way of righteousness, along the paths of justice, </verse>
    <verse value="21"> bestowing wealth on those who love me and making their treasuries full.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> "The LORD brought me forth as the first of his works,, before his deeds of old; </verse>
    <verse value="23"> I was appointed from eternity, from the beginning, before the world began. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> When there were no oceans, I was given birth, when there were no springs abounding with water; </verse>
    <verse value="25"> before the mountains were settled in place, before the hills, I was given birth, </verse>
    <verse value="26"> before he made the earth or its fields or any of the dust of the world. </verse>
    <verse value="27"> I was there when he set the heavens in place, when he marked out the horizon on the face of the deep, </verse>
    <verse value="28"> when he established the clouds above and fixed securely the fountains of the deep, </verse>
    <verse value="29"> when he gave the sea its boundary so the waters would not overstep his command, and when he marked out the foundations of the earth. </verse>
    <verse value="30"> Then I was the craftsman at his side. I was filled with delight day after day, rejoicing always in his presence, </verse>
    <verse value="31"> rejoicing in his whole world and delighting in mankind.</verse>
    <verse value="32"> "Now then, my sons, listen to me; blessed are those who keep my ways. </verse>
    <verse value="33"> Listen to my instruction and be wise; do not ignore it.</verse>
    <verse value="34"> Blessed is the man who listens to me, watching daily at my doors, waiting at my doorway. </verse>
    <verse value="35"> For whoever finds me finds life and receives favor from the LORD. </verse>
    <verse value="36"> But whoever fails to find me harms himself; all who hate me love death."</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>