<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">The wise woman builds her house, but with her own hands the foolish one tears hers down.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> He whose walk is upright fears the LORD, but he whose ways are devious despises him.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> A fool's talk brings a rod to his back, but the lips of the wise protect them.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Where there are no oxen, the manger is empty, but from the strength of an ox comes an abundant harvest.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> A truthful witness does not deceive, but a false witness pours out lies.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> The mocker seeks wisdom and finds none, but knowledge comes easily to the discerning.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> Stay away from a foolish man, for you will not find knowledge on his lips.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> The wisdom of the prudent is to give thought to their ways, but the folly of fools is deception.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Fools mock at making amends for sin, but goodwill is found among the upright.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Each heart knows its own bitterness, and no one else can share its joy.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The house of the wicked will be destroyed, but the tent of the upright will flourish.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> There is a way that seems right to a man, but in the end it leads to death.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Even in laughter the heart may ache, and joy may end in grief.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> The faithless will be fully repaid for their ways, and the good man rewarded for his.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> A simple man believes anything, but a prudent man gives thought to his steps.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> A wise man fears the LORD and shuns evil, but a fool is hotheaded and reckless.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> A quick-tempered man does foolish things, and a crafty man is hated.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> The simple inherit folly, but the prudent are crowned with knowledge.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Evil men will bow down in the presence of the good, and the wicked at the gates of the righteous.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> The poor are shunned even by their neighbors, but the rich have many friends.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> He who despises his neighbor sins, but blessed is he who is kind to the needy.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Do not those who plot evil go astray? But those who plan what is good find love and faithfulness.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> All hard work brings a profit, but mere talk leads only to poverty.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> The wealth of the wise is their crown, but the folly of fools yields folly.</verse>
    <verse value="25"> A truthful witness saves lives, but a false witness is deceitful.</verse>
    <verse value="26"> He who fears the LORD has a secure fortress, and for his children it will be a refuge.</verse>
    <verse value="27"> The fear of the LORD is a fountain of life, turning a man from the snares of death.</verse>
    <verse value="28"> A large population is a king's glory, but without subjects a prince is ruined.</verse>
    <verse value="29"> A patient man has great understanding, but a quick-tempered man displays folly.</verse>
    <verse value="30"> A heart at peace gives life to the body, but envy rots the bones.</verse>
    <verse value="31"> He who oppresses the poor shows contempt for their Maker, but whoever is kind to the needy honors God.</verse>
    <verse value="32"> When calamity comes, the wicked are brought down, but even in death the righteous have a refuge.</verse>
    <verse value="33"> Wisdom reposes in the heart of the discerning and even among fools she lets herself be known.</verse>
    <verse value="34"> Righteousness exalts a nation, but sin is a disgrace to any people.</verse>
    <verse value="35"> A king delights in a wise servant, but a shameful servant incurs his wrath.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>