<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">An unfriendly man pursues selfish ends; he defies all sound judgment.</verse>
    <verse value="2"> A fool finds no pleasure in understanding but delights in airing his own opinions.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> When wickedness comes, so does contempt, and with shame comes disgrace.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> The words of a man's mouth are deep waters, but the fountain of wisdom is a bubbling brook.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> It is not good to be partial to the wicked or to deprive the innocent of justice.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> A fool's lips bring him strife, and his mouth invites a beating.</verse>
    <verse value="7"> A fool's mouth is his undoing, and his lips are a snare to his soul.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> The words of a gossip are like choice morsels; they go down to a man's inmost parts.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> One who is slack in his work is brother to one who destroys.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> The name of the LORD is a strong tower; the righteous run to it and are safe.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> The wealth of the rich is their fortified city; they imagine it an unscalable wall.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Before his downfall a man's heart is proud, but humility comes before honor.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> He who answers before listening-- that is his folly and his shame.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> A man's spirit sustains him in sickness, but a crushed spirit who can bear?</verse>
    <verse value="15"> The heart of the discerning acquires knowledge; the ears of the wise seek it out.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> A gift opens the way for the giver and ushers him into the presence of the great.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> The first to present his case seems right, till another comes forward and questions him.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> Casting the lot settles disputes and keeps strong opponents apart.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> An offended brother is more unyielding than a fortified city, and disputes are like the barred gates of a citadel.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> From the fruit of his mouth a man's stomach is filled; with the harvest from his lips he is satisfied.</verse>
    <verse value="21"> The tongue has the power of life and death, and those who love it will eat its fruit.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> He who finds a wife finds what is good and receives favor from the LORD.</verse>
    <verse value="23"> A poor man pleads for mercy, but a rich man answers harshly.</verse>
    <verse value="24"> A man of many companions may come to ruin, but there is a friend who sticks closer than a brother.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>