<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">When you sit to dine with a ruler, note well what is before you, </verse>
    <verse value="2"> and put a knife to your throat if you are given to gluttony.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Do not crave his delicacies, for that food is deceptive.</verse>
    <verse value="4"> Do not wear yourself out to get rich; have the wisdom to show restraint.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> Cast but a glance at riches, and they are gone, for they will surely sprout wings and fly off to the sky like an eagle.</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Do not eat the food of a stingy man, do not crave his delicacies; </verse>
    <verse value="7"> for he is the kind of man who is always thinking about the cost. "Eat and drink," he says to you, but his heart is not with you. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> You will vomit up the little you have eaten and will have wasted your compliments.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> Do not speak to a fool, for he will scorn the wisdom of your words.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> Do not move an ancient boundary stone or encroach on the fields of the fatherless, </verse>
    <verse value="11"> for their Defender is strong; he will take up their case against you.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Apply your heart to instruction and your ears to words of knowledge.</verse>
    <verse value="13"> Do not withhold discipline from a child; if you punish him with the rod, he will not die.</verse>
    <verse value="14"> Punish him with the rod and save his soul from death.</verse>
    <verse value="15"> My son, if your heart is wise, then my heart will be glad;</verse>
    <verse value="16"> my inmost being will rejoice when your lips speak what is right.</verse>
    <verse value="17"> Do not let your heart envy sinners, but always be zealous for the fear of the LORD. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> There is surely a future hope for you, and your hope will not be cut off.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> Listen, my son, and be wise, and keep your heart on the right path. </verse>
    <verse value="20"> Do not join those who drink too much wine or gorge themselves on meat,</verse>
    <verse value="21"> for drunkards and gluttons become poor, and drowsiness clothes them in rags.</verse>
    <verse value="22"> Listen to your father, who gave you life, and do not despise your mother when she is old. </verse>
    <verse value="23"> Buy the truth and do not sell it; get wisdom, discipline and understanding. </verse>
    <verse value="24"> The father of a righteous man has great joy; he who has a wise son delights in him. </verse>
    <verse value="25"> May your father and mother be glad; may she who gave you birth rejoice!</verse>
    <verse value="26"> My son, give me your heart and let your eyes keep to my ways, </verse>
    <verse value="27"> for a prostitute is a deep pit and a wayward wife is a narrow well. </verse>
    <verse value="28"> Like a bandit she lies in wait, and multiplies the unfaithful among men.</verse>
    <verse value="29"> Who has woe? Who has sorrow? Who has strife? Who has complaints? Who has needless bruises? Who has bloodshot eyes?</verse>
    <verse value="30"> Those who linger over wine, who go to sample bowls of mixed wine. </verse>
    <verse value="31"> Do not gaze at wine when it is red, when it sparkles in the cup, when it goes down smoothly!</verse>
    <verse value="32"> In the end it bites like a snake and poisons like a viper.</verse>
    <verse value="33"> Your eyes will see strange sights and your mind imagine confusing things.</verse>
    <verse value="34"> You will be like one sleeping on the high seas, lying on top of the rigging.</verse>
    <verse value="35"> "They hit me," you will say, "but I'm not hurt! They beat me, but I don't feel it! When will I wake up so I can find another drink?"</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>