<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">As dead flies give perfume a bad smell, so a little folly outweighs wisdom and honor. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> The heart of the wise inclines to the right, but the heart of the fool to the left.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Even as he walks along the road, the fool lacks sense and shows everyone how stupid he is. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> If a ruler's anger rises against you, do not leave your post; calmness can lay great errors to rest.</verse>
    <verse value="5"> There is an evil I have seen under the sun, the sort of error that arises from a ruler:</verse>
    <verse value="6"> Fools are put in many high positions, while the rich occupy the low ones. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> I have seen slaves on horseback, while princes go on foot like slaves.</verse>
    <verse value="8"> Whoever digs a pit may fall into it; whoever breaks through a wall may be bitten by a snake. </verse>
    <verse value="9"> Whoever quarries stones may be injured by them; whoever splits logs may be endangered by them.</verse>
    <verse value="10"> If the ax is dull and its edge unsharpened, more strength is needed but skill will bring success.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> If a snake bites before it is charmed, there is no profit for the charmer.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Words from a wise man's mouth are gracious, but a fool is consumed by his own lips. </verse>
    <verse value="13"> At the beginning his words are folly; at the end they are wicked madness--</verse>
    <verse value="14"> and the fool multiplies words. No one knows what is coming-- who can tell him what will happen after him?</verse>
    <verse value="15"> A fool's work wearies him; he does not know the way to town.</verse>
    <verse value="16"> Woe to you, O land whose king was a servant and whose princes feast in the morning. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> Blessed are you, O land whose king is of noble birth and whose princes eat at a proper time-- for strength and not for drunkenness.</verse>
    <verse value="18"> If a man is lazy, the rafters sag; if his hands are idle, the house leaks.</verse>
    <verse value="19"> A feast is made for laughter, and wine makes life merry, but money is the answer for everything.</verse>
    <verse value="20"> Do not revile the king even in your thoughts, or curse the rich in your bedroom, because a bird of the air may carry your words, and a bird on the wing may report what you say.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>