<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<chapter type="NIV" language="ENU">
  <content>
    <verse value="1">See, a king will reign in righteousness and rulers will rule with justice. </verse>
    <verse value="2"> Each man will be like a shelter from the wind and a refuge from the storm, like streams of water in the desert and the shadow of a great rock in a thirsty land.</verse>
    <verse value="3"> Then the eyes of those who see will no longer be closed, and the ears of those who hear will listen. </verse>
    <verse value="4"> The mind of the rash will know and understand, and the stammering tongue will be fluent and clear. </verse>
    <verse value="5"> No longer will the fool be called noble nor the scoundrel be highly respected. </verse>
    <verse value="6"> For the fool speaks folly, his mind is busy with evil: He practices ungodliness and spreads error concerning the LORD; the hungry he leaves empty and from the thirsty he withholds water. </verse>
    <verse value="7"> The scoundrel's methods are wicked, he makes up evil schemes to destroy the poor with lies, even when the plea of the needy is just. </verse>
    <verse value="8"> But the noble man makes noble plans, and by noble deeds he stands.</verse>
    <verse value="9"> You women who are so complacent, rise up and listen to me; you daughters who feel secure, hear what I have to say! </verse>
    <verse value="10"> In little more than a year you who feel secure will tremble; the grape harvest will fail, and the harvest of fruit will not come.</verse>
    <verse value="11"> Tremble, you complacent women; shudder, you daughters who feel secure! Strip off your clothes, put sackcloth around your waists.</verse>
    <verse value="12"> Beat your breasts for the pleasant fields, for the fruitful vines </verse>
    <verse value="13"> and for the land of my people, a land overgrown with thorns and briers-- yes, mourn for all houses of merriment and for this city of revelry. </verse>
    <verse value="14"> The fortress will be abandoned, the noisy city deserted; citadel and watchtower will become a wasteland forever, the delight of donkeys, a pasture for flocks, </verse>
    <verse value="15"> till the Spirit is poured upon us from on high, and the desert becomes a fertile field, and the fertile field seems like a forest. </verse>
    <verse value="16"> Justice will dwell in the desert and righteousness live in the fertile field. </verse>
    <verse value="17"> The fruit of righteousness will be peace; the effect of righteousness will be quietness and confidence forever. </verse>
    <verse value="18"> My people will live in peaceful dwelling places, in secure homes, in undisturbed places of rest. </verse>
    <verse value="19"> Though hail flattens the forest and the city is leveled completely, </verse>
    <verse value="20"> how blessed you will be, sowing your seed by every stream, and letting your cattle and donkeys range free.</verse>
  </content>
</chapter>